Synced by pacifier and
corrected by samir133
not much going on for a Friday.
It's early yet.
Make it a double would you.
Sure.
And buy one for yourself.
I gotta make a call.
Thank's pal.
Therese?
Is that you?
What do you know!
I'm saying to myself,
I know that girl.
Jack.
It's great to see you, therese.
It's been, months.
Months.
Jack, this is Carol arid.
Pleased to meet you.
Likewise.
Hey, Ted gray's meeting me here
Phil and a bunch of us
are going down to Phil's party.
You're going aren't you?
Yes. I just planned to
get there a little...
You two go ahead.
You coming along?
No,
I should make a few calls before dinner,
anyway.
I should really run.
You sure?
Of course.
Then it would be great to catch a ride.
Yeah, sure.
You two have a wonderful night.
Nice meeting you, Jack.
Nice meeting you.
Alright, well let me go make
sure the loaf is on his way.
Back in a flash.
I like your scribbles.
Yeah, I've been busy!
I don't know how you do it.
What?
You look a million bucks
first thing in the morning.
I'll be down in a minute.
So, I got the schedules.
In the mail.
You listening to me?
I'm listening!
You got the schedules.
Two sailings to France in June,
one in July.
Wow.
What do think?
I think...
It's too cold I can't think straight.
Alright let's get you warmed up.
Compliments in the
season from the management.
Compliments of the
Season's greetings
from the management.
Esther anyway she's just
going crazy with no girls
in the family but Esther-
how is Esther?
She'll pull through.
Compliments of the
season from the management.
I gotta open the floor.
See you later
miss blivet.
You're needed upstairs
make it snappy.
Frankenberg good morning,
happy
holidays and welcome,
shoppers, to frankenberg's.
Be sure to take advantage of our
congratulations ike and mamie
inaugural early bird special
ike mamie in our beds and bedding
department on the second floor.
And on your way there, you won't
want to miss our brand new general
electric television and
stereophonic display on
the first floor, just
past the haberdashery.
Miss, miss,
where's the ladies room, honey?
If you go back to the
elevator, make a right, you can't miss it.
Thanks you
I wonder if you might
help me find this doll for my daughter.
Bright Betsy bright Betsy.
Oh she cries. And wets herself.
But I'm afraid
we're out of stock.
I've left it too long.
We have plenty
of other dolls. All kinds, hmm…
right. What was
your favorite doll when you were four?
Me? I never...
Not many, to be honest.
Sorry. No
smoking on the sales floor.
Oh, of all the -
forgive me. Shopping makes me nervous.
That's okay.
Working here makes me nervous.
You're very kind.
Here she is.
She looks like you.
Around the eyes.
You think so?
So what did you
want when you were this age?
A train set.
Really? Do you
know much about train sets?
I do actually. And
there's a new model, just in last week.
Hand-built and hand-painted
cars, it's a limited
edition of five thousand,
you may have seen it.
Over by the elevators.
I would show you more of
it, but... I'm sort of confined.
To this desk.
Do you ship?
Special delivery. Or
courier. You'll have it in two, three days.
We'll even
assemble it for you.
Well. That's...
That. Sold.
Shall I pay now?
Oh yes, of course.
I need your account
details. And your shipping address.
Of course.
I love Christmas.
Wrapping gifts, all that. And then
you somehow wind up overcooking
the turkey anyway.
Done.
Where'd you learn so much about train sets?
I... read.
Too much, probably.
It's refreshing.
Thank you
merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas.
I like your hat.
Move over. Nobody
else can see the screen.
Nobody else is watching.
I'm watching.
I've seen it six times.
Right now I'm charting the correlation
between what the characters
say and how they really feel.
My kid brother,
the movie jerk.
I'm strictly a beer man.
Everything else makes me want to vomit.
Wine makes me feel naughty
but in a good way.
I drink to forget I gotta get up
for work in the morning.
Semco see, that's your problem,
semco.
You really ought to
drink because you remember you have a job.
Employment is a curse.
Phil you have a job, Phil.
You call that a job?
I call it an illusion.
You get paid.
Is money an illusion?
My kid brother,
the jerk philosopher.
Where do you work?
Dannie works at the New York times.
No kidding.
It's a job.
But I want to write.
That's why I watch movies.
Everybody's a writer...
Therese say, therese-before
I get too drunk to remember...
You did it? It's fixed?
He said it was a cinch.
No sweat.
Thank you, Phil!
I was missing it!
So, you take pictures?
Well.
She's more excited by some chintzy
camera than she is about
sailing with me to Europe.
Women.
You said it, pal!
I don't believe it!
Does the house un-American
activities know you're back on the streets?
Hey honey, hey darling.
Terry, honey,
it's been ages. Call me, would you?
I will, I promise!
You still owe me for that poker game!
Richard, watch out, you're!
You come by the times,
for dinner sometime?
I work at night, so... I've
got a good pal who's a
junior photo editor.
He loves to pontificate.
I'll introduce you.
Really? I would like that.
Yeah? Okay.
Sixty-four, sixty-five, sixty-six…. Sixty?
Fifty-four.
That must be your daddy.
Come on. We'd better finish up.
Mommy can you come skating too
oh, I wish I could, sweet pea.
Why plea please?
Hiya, sunshine.
Daddy! I want mommy to come.
You do don't you?
You're early.
Mail came.
Cy Harrison's wife.
Jeanette
Jeanette asked about you.
Did she?
You can color the trunk honey.
I know she'd love to see you there.
Give her my best.
I've always liked Jeanette.
I'd like you to be there.
I'm sorry, harge.
I have plans.
Mommy wants to give
aunt Abby a present
you been seeing a lot of
aunt Abby lately, haven't you sunshine?
With mommy?
Yes
I'll try and re-arrange with Abby.
Thank you.
I told this
customer it would get to
her by Christmas Eve.
According to what we've been told.
Three days should be...
Should have been
delivered this afternoon.
Oh. Right. So... it arrived?
She signed for it?
It arrived.
Great. Thank you. Thanks.
Belivet? Miss belivet?
Over here please. Now?
Sorry, would you excuse me. I...
Just be one minute.
Of course.
Hello?
Is this employee 645-a,
Theresa belivet?
Yes.
We're patching you though
so it was you.
Oh hello. Mrs. arid?
Did you receive the train set alright?
I did. Yes.
And the gloves. Thank
you so much. You're a
star for sending them.
I just wanna to say thank you.
Really.
Of course.
What... what I wanna to say was
do you get lunch hour there?
Let me take you to lunch.
It's the least I can do.
Yes, of course.
But you don't have to...
I'm free tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
No, I don't know it.
Hold on.
Can I borrow a pencil and paper?
Thank you.
All right
I'm so sorry to keep you waiting.
I'll have the creamed spinach
over poached eggs.
And a dry Martini.
With an olive.
I'll have the same.
The meal or the drink?
All of it. Thank you.
Cigarette?
Yes please.
So what kind of a name is belivet?
T's Czech. It's changed.
Originally...
It's very original.
Well
and your first name?
Therese
therese, not ter-eeza
no.
Therese belivet.
It's lovely.
And yours?
Carol.
Two dry Martinis.
Thank you.
Cheers.
So
You… I'm sure you thought
it was a man who sent
back your gloves.
I did.
I thought it might
be a man in the ski department.
I'm sorry.
No,
I'm delighted. I doubt
very much if I'd have
gone to lunch with him.
Your perfume.
Yes?
It's nice.
Thank you.
Harge thank you.
Harge bought
me a bottle years ago,
before we were married.
I've been
wearing it ever since.
Harge is your husband?
Yes. Well. Technically we...
We're divorcing.
I'm sorry.
Don't be.
And do you live alone, therese belivet?
I do.
Well there's Richard.
He wants to live with me.
No, it's nothing like that.
It's... he'd like to marry me.
I see.
Would you like to marry him?
I barely even know what to order for lunch.
And your meals.
Thank you.
Enjoy.
I'm starved.
Bon appetite.
What do you do on Sundays?
Nothing in particular.
What do you do?
Nothing... lately.
I mean, if you'd like to visit
me some time, you're welcome to.
At least there's some
pretty country around where I live.
Would you like to come out this Sunday?
Yes.
What a
strange girl you are.
Why?
Flung out of space.
Just see harge's
mother's face when she sees me in this.
Maybe I should stop home and change.
Don't be a stupe.
Maybe I should just not show up?
Well than I'll be blamed
for it. So you'd better
just grin and bear it.
You want to tell me about her?
Therese?
She returned my gloves.
And?
And if you don't get us
out of this traffic soon,
I won't have to worry
about that damned party.
Where... is my compact.
God damn it.
You look fine.
Come in with me.
Just for a minute.
Don't even start.
- You're the one who canceled on us
- you nitwit!
I know. I'm sorry. I'm going!
Call me later.
You're always the
most beautiful woman in any room.
Tell your mother that.
Keep an eye out, will
you? Cy will scream if
he catches me with this.
What will he do?
Dock your allowance?
He doesn't like me to smoke.
So? You like it.
Carol, I... it's really not my business
but if you're going to
be alone on Christmas
cy and I would love to have you.
Thank you, Jeanette.
I don't know.
I might get away by myself.
At least for a few days.
Don't worry.
Nothing will break if you pick it up.
What are your pictures like?
I don't know.
They're probably not very good.
I mean... what are they?
What do you take pictures of?
Trees. Birds. Windows. Anything, really.
What do you write about?
People.
Always feel funny taking
pictures of people.
Like it's some sort of a ..
Invasion of privacy?
Yes.
All of us, you know,
we have affinities for people.
We like certain people.
You like certain people right?
Sometimes.
You don't like others.
And you don't know why
you're attracted to some
people and not others,
the only thing you know is... you
either are attracted or
you're not attracted.
It's like physics bouncing
off each other like pin balls.
Yeah but... not everything's
as simple as a bunch of
pin balls reacting or,
some things don't
even react. But everything's alive.
It's late. I should go.
You shouldn't
why? Did you mind?
No.
I have to go.
Come back tomorrow? Or Wednesday?
Maybe. I don't know.
Here.
Thanks.
And thanks for staying sober
and driving me home.
Harge goodnight, harge.
Carol
come to my parents for Christmas.
We had a good time tonight.
It was one night harge.
I don't like the idea of you being alone.
I'm not alone. There's rindy. And a...
Abbey.
There's always Abby.
Harge Abby and I were
over long before you and
I were over, harge.
I'll have rindy packed
and ready for you at four on Christmas Eve.
It shouldn't be like this.
I know.
Mama's special girl.
Goodnight, Florence.
Where's this place in jersey?
The country. I don't really know.
My uncle sal lives in union city
and he claims it's pretty
dangerous at night
it's not union city.
Okay.
There's my ride.
Hi.
Hello. Carol arid.
Richard semco.
Glad to meet you.
Likewise.
Therese speaks very highly of you.
That's well.
So you'll get her back here safe and sound?
I think I see snow
wouldn't that be wonderful?
I love the snow
makes you feel like Christmas,
don't you think?
Love you.
You still with me?
Yes
mommy's home!
Hello, my darling!
Guess what I brought you?
I bet you'll never guess...
Is it blue?
No, it's green.
Oh it's long isn't it.
Do you need scissors?
Maybe we should do the star first.
We can do that,
where's the star?
The gold or...
- You choose
- ok
that's my girl.
What do you think?
Good.
That is the most beautiful
tree in the whole wide world.
Were those pictures of me you were taking?
At the tree lot?
I'm sorry. I should have asked.
Don't apologize.
I've been trying to...
A friend of mine told me
I should be more interested. In humans.
And how's that going?
It's going well... actually.
I'm glad.
That's beautiful.
Is that what you want to be?
A photographer?
I think so. If I have any talent for it.
Isn't that something other people
let you know you have.
And all you can do is...
Keep working.
Use what feels right.
Throw away the rest.
I suppose so.
Will you show me your work?
Sure. I mean, I haven't sold anything.
Or even shown a picture
to anyone who could buy one.
I don't even have a decent camera.
But they're all at my place.
Under the sink, mostly.
Invite me round.
Harge harge.
What's wrong?
Nothing. Does there have
to be a problem for me
to visit my wife?
That's not fair, harge.
We agreed that rindy
would stay with me until Christmas Eve.
What do you suggest I do?
You think I prefer traipsing
off to west palm beach
for the holiday?
It was all mother's idea
but I'm not... ready...
She's not packed,
she's asleep upstairs in bed!
What about my Christmas with my daughter?
I'm sorry, Carol,
but it can't be helped.
The flight's in the morning
you think I've packed already?
Goddammit!
How do you know my wife?
Harge, please...
I... work at frankenberg's.
The department store.
I ordered a gift from her desk.
I forgot my gloves.
She returned them.
I thanked her...
That's bold.
Can I do anything?
Just... leave it be.
Okay, snow flake.
Gimme a big one.
You're going to have a wonderful Christmas,
I promise.
There's room for you in the car, mommy.
You can come with us!
Oh, darling…
I wish I could...
You know sometimes...
Mommies and daddies decide there isn't
enough room for them both
in the same place at the same time
anyway, mommy has to be here to make sure
Santa's elf doesn't give your gift
from mommy to another little girl.
You wouldn't want that, would you?
No.
I love you snowflake
you smell good.
You're drunk.
Harge, I'm very cold.
Let me get you some coffee.
I'm not drunk.
You can still come with us.
Go back a bag.
I can't do that.
Yes, you can.
What are you gonna do?
You're gonna stay here with Abby?
You're gonna stay
with the shop girl over there?
What are you gonna do?
Stop it. God damn it.
I put nothing past women like you. Carol.
You married a woman like me.
If you don't get in that car
with us right now?
Then what? Then it's over?
God damn you
you were never... cruel.
Harge.
I should call a cab.
And just when you think it
can't get any worse,
you run out of cigarettes.
Oh...
I... tell me where to go.
I'll buy some for you.
I don't mind really.
You don't have to run out in
- the middle of nowhere to buy cigarettes.
- I'm fine.
The next train's at 8.30.
I'll drive you to the station.
Hello?
Do you know what time it is, miss belivet?
- I'm sorry,
- it just rang...
Hello?
I was... horrible. Earlier.
Will you forgive me?
Yes...
I mean
then will you... would you...
Let me... come see you tomorrow evening?
Alright, yes...
I want to... know.
I mean, I want to ask you... things.
But I'm not sure you want that.
Ask me. Things. Please.
Merry Christmas, Katherine.
Thank you Mrs. arid.
There he is.
Now will you talk to me?
I didn't want you to come
all the way down here
just... give it to me, straight, Fred.
What am I not to worry
about until after the holiday?
Jerry rix served some
papers this morning,
to my complete surprise.
Why don't you sit.
Why is it people think you're
going to take bad news better
if you're sitting down?
Rindy, harge took out an injunction
which denies you any access to
rindy until the custody hearing.
What?
Harge rindy
and I'm afraid harge has changed
his mind about joint custody.
He wants sole custody of rindy.
We've already
reached an agreement about custody.
What is this all about?
They'll be filing
the formal papers on the twenty-ninth
in district family court one. For
the, uh, permanent petition, that is.
Can he do this?
Is it... right?
I don't know if it's
right, but it's certainly legal.
On what grounds.
Listen.
Let's deal with
this after Christmas.
You'll have a chance to-
on. What. Grounds.
They're petitioning the
judge to consider a morality clause.
A morality... what
the hell does that mean?
Abby gerhard okay. I won't
mince words with you. Abby gerhard.
Also they're
suggesting similar associations
with, well they're alleging
evidence of a pattern of behave
evidence of a pattern?
Abbyrindy Abby... Abby is
rindy's godmother. Abby is...
Rindy... if he can't
have me, I can't have rindy. That's…
I'm sorry.
But they seem serious.
When's
the custody hearing?
That's hard to say, with
the holidays and a backlog of cases.
Fred your best guess, Fred.
Not before the middle
of march. Could be middle of April.
Can I see her?
Not - let me put it this way
it would not be advisable under the
at school?
In an office with a-
the
issue is not where
Carol
surely a visit supervised
by a teacher or a -Carol, these
are serious allegations.
Forcing
contact before the hearing
you
simply invite further
scrutiny concerning your conduct.
My conduct!
Jesus Christ.
I'm her mother
for god's sake.
A morality clause.
I see
do you?
No
Rindy there's nothing
moral about taking rindy from me.
Yes,
that's it thank you.
Find what you wanted?
Something for
someone at the store.
Oh that's nice of you.
You should stop
by on Christmas sometime.
My mom's sort
of planning on it.
…... Christmas... that's
for families. I'd feel.. I don't know...
Terry you
are family, Terry.
I'm
thinking of putting
together a portfolio, you
know, of my pictures.
Start taking portraits, even.
Apply for jobs.
Dannie...
Maybe at a newspaper.
Maybe at the times.
Dannie knows someone...
Have you been
thinking more about Europe?
Terry Terry?
What?
How many times
have you been in love?
Never.
Until you.
Don't lie. You told me about
those two other girls.
Come on. They were
I had sex with them.
That's not the same thing.
Meaning... I'm different
because you haven't...
Gone all the way with me?
No
Hey, what's this all about?
I love you. That's what's different.
Have you ever been in love with a boy?
No.
But you've heard of it?
Of course. I mean, have I heard of
people like that? Sure.
I don't mean people like that. I mean
two people who just...
Fall in love. With each other.
Say, a boy and a boy.
Out of the blue.
I don't know anyone like that.
But I'll tell you this... there's
always some reason for it.
In the background.
So you don't think it
could happen to somebody,
just anybody?
No. I don't.
What are you saying?
Are you in love with a girl?
No
Don't you know
I want to spend my life with you?
Come to France with me.
Let's get married.
Richard, I'm not... ready. For that.
I can't make myself...
What? Tell me.
I'm sorry. I have to go.
I'm sorry.
I found rindy's hair brush
underneath my pillow this morning.
Full of her hair.
She does that, you know,
to let me know she's been a good girl
and brushed properly.
I usually clean it out but
today, for some reason...
How could he. How dare he...
A morality what?
Clause, he said.
Carol if I'm responsible in any way
don't you dare
don't you ever.
Anyway, I've got my eye
on this redhead who owns a steak house
outside of paramus.
Rita Hayworth I'm talking...
Serious Rita Hayworth redhead.
Really? You think you have
what it takes to handle a redhead?
You going somewhere?
- West.
- I thought
at least for a few weeks until the hearing.
What else am I going to do?
I know you don't like to drive alone. So.
She's young.
Tell me you know what you're doing.
I don't.
I never did
your landlady let me in.
Merry Christmas.
Open it.
Oh Carol.
It's not that good. I was rushed,
I mean...
I can do better.
It's perfect.
Is this you?
Um-huh.
Do you keep anything in
the icebox besides photo chemicals?
I'm feeling...
Sure.
Is there any point in, I don't know...
Fighting it?
The injunction?
No.
I feel useless.
Like I can't help you or offer anything
it has nothing to do with you.
I'm going away for a while.
When?... where?
Wherever my car will take me.
West.
Soon.
And I thought...
Perhaps you might like to come with me.
Would you?
Yes.
Yes, I would.
You don't know her.
You can forward any mail to Chicago,
general post
I've paid the rent through February.
I had a little extra
some money I saved
Terry for our trip. Our trip, Terry.
And now you're...
I don't believe this is happening!
I can't explain it. I just...
You've got one hell
of a crush on this women...
Like a schoolgirl.
I do not
I just like her is all.
I'm fond of anybody I can really talk to.
Nice
you know what I think?
I think two weeks form now,
you'll be wishing that
she'll get tired of you, and then
you'll gonna wish you were never...
You don't understand
I do,I understand completely.
You're in a trance!
I'm wide awake. I've never
felt more awake.
Why don't you leave me alone?
Are we over?
Is that what this is?
I didn't say that.
But why should I want to
be with you if all you do
is argue about this?
- To say
- to say for a minute you
practically want to say goodbye
because of some silly crush!
I didn't say that.
You said it?
You made me buy boat tickets,
I got a better job for you...
I asked you to marry me,
for christsakes.
I didn't make you do
anything. I never asked you for...
Anything.
Maybe that's the problem.
I swear to you, two weeks from
now you'll be begging me
to forget this ever!
Richard...
Richard!
Have a great trip, Terry!
For you. Merry Christmas.
Oh no. You shouldn't have.
Open it.
I played it for you.
At your house.
I remember.
Thank you.
Oh god, I look a fright
no you do not,
you look wonderful.
Just stay like that.
Do you miss Richard?
No. I haven't thought about him all day.
Or of home. Really.
Home.
I have to speak to her.
What are you doing here?
You're supposed to be in Florida.
I couldn't do it.
Because rindy wanted
to be with her mother on Christmas.
Not that it's any of your business.
Just go get her.
I know she's here.
You've got some
fucking nerve ordering me around.
And, no. She's not here.
That's impossible.
She's not home.
She's not with me.
She must be with you.
You've spent ten years making
damned sure her only point
of reference is you,
your job, your friends, your family,
your...
Where is she. Goddamn it.
Abby she's still my wife, Abby.
She's my responsibility.
You should have thought of that
before you slapped her
with that injunction.
I'm closing the door.
I love her.
I can't help you with that.
Carol?
Therese, is that you?
Yes!
Would you be a sweetie and fetch
my red knit sweater?
It's in the big
suitcase on the bed.
Okay.
Hey, slowpoke...
Found it.
Thanks. Everything all right?
- I'm just
- suddenly starving.
I won't be a minute.
You hungry?
Sure.
Do you feel... safe.
With me, I mean?
You're full of surprises.
I mean you would tell me...
If something scared you.
And I could help.
I'm not frightened, therese.
Our standard rooms come equipped
with stereophonic console radios,
or if you prefer, the presidential
suite is available.
At a very attractive rate.
Two standard rooms should be fine.
Why not take the presidential suite?
If the rate's attractive...
Can I help you with that?
Thank you.
It's so cold.
So cold, my glasses have fogged
right the way over.
Here you go.
Thanks again. Night.
Night.
Don't blink.
There
I need lipstick.
Again.
Take a look at yourself.
Beautiful.
Next?
Would mademoiselle be so
kind as to apply at the pulse points only?
Me, too.
That's divine.
Smell that.
To president McKinley.
Good morning. Glad to see you
didn't freeze over or nothing.
You too.
I'm afraid the coffee is not very good
long as it's hot.
What's in the case?
Oh. Notions. I'm a
I sell them. Or try to.
Lousy coffee.
I'm sorry
excuse me?
We were just chatting.
Name's Tucker... Tommy
therese belivet Carol arid.
Pleased to meet you.
Mr. Tucker sells notions.
I see.
I don't really know what notions are.
Exactly.
But they do instruct us to use that word.
Sales appeals to women.
Do you sell lipstick?
No. But I have a sewing kit.
You don't need a sewing kit.
I can tell.
We should make Chicago
by five or six, if we get an early start.
I'm headlining.
There's a short cut across the
interstates, knocks three hours
off the drive.
Two hours that'll be something.
Can we stop to buy some magazines?
I have field and stream,
national geographic...
Popular photography?
Course not.
I am doomed to remain without a sale.
Is this alright?
Thank you so much.
Finally. A real bed.
Heaven.
And the furniture!
Good evening.
Table for two, please, for dinner.
Are you staying here at the hotel?
Yes, it's room...
623, Mrs. arid.
That'll be just a moment, Mrs. arid.
Therese belivet
hargess arid. Hello.
Someone's popular.
All from Richard.
Aren't you going to pick up your mail?
Nobody knows I'm here.
Were you... making a call?
What?
Ladies room.
Happy new year.
Harge and I never spend
new year's Eve together.
There's always a business function,
always clients to entertain.
I've always spent new year's Eve alone.
In crowds.
I'm not alone this year.
Take me to bed.
I never looked like that.
You're trembling.
Don't. I want to see you.
My angel. Flung out of space.
What town is this again?
This? Waterloo. Isn't that awful?
You the folks in 42?
We're checking out.
Telegram come for you last night.
When did this arrive?
Early. Seven. Nine. I ain't a clock, lady.
Where's my suitcase?
I put it in the back.
I want my fucking suitcase.
Carol...
What's going on?
Carol!
Carol what are you going to do with that?
What happened?
Carol, you're scaring me.
Where's the tape, you son of a bitch.
How much is harge paying
you for this? I'll give you double, triple.
Whatever you want.
I wish I could oblige you, ma'am.
But the tape is already on,
its way to your husband.
That can't be right.
My reputation rests on my efficiency,
Mrs. arid.
How do I know you're not lying?
You don't. Ma'am
how could you.
I am a professional,
miss belivet. It's not personal.
Let's get out of here.
There's nothing we can do.
As soon as we got the telegram
earliest flight into LaGuardia
is tomorrow afternoon...
Oh Abby, I don't know how to fix this...
I haven't the strength...
What are you thinking?
You know how many times
a day I ask you that?
I'm sorry. What am I thinking?
I'm thinking that I'm utterly selfish.
And I
don't do this. You had no idea.
How could you have known?
I should have said no to you.
But I can never say no.
And it's selfish because I take...
Everything.
And I don't know...
Anything.
I don't know what I want.
How could I if I say yes to everything?
I took what you gave willingly.
It's not your fault, therese.
Alright.
Thank you, darling.
You know. Shattered. Sickened.
I hope so.
Anything else you need?
Talk tomorrow.
Try to get some sleep. And don't worry.
I will. And thank you.
Night
you don't have to sleep over there.
She's gone?
Early this morning.
Is she coming back?
No.
This is all my fault.
Nonsense.
We should get going.
Eat something.
Suit yourself.
Why do you hate me?
I've never done anything to you.
Do you think I've flown halfway
across the country to drive you back east
because I hate you,
and want to see you suffer?
It's for Carol. Not for me.
That's...
With you and Carol, what happened?
Carol it's completely different.
I've known Carol since
I was 10 years old.
It was five or six years ago. Summer
late one night.
My Ford broke down at my mother's house.
We tried to stay up, but...
Curled up together in my old twin bed.
And that was it... for a while.
And then it changed.
It changes.
Nobody's fault.
So
Here, she...
Dearest. There are no accidents
and he would have found us
one way or another.
Everything comes full circle.
Be grateful it was sooner
rather than later.
You'll think it harsh of me to say so,
but no explanation I
offer will satisfy you.
Please don't be angry when I tell you
that you seek resolutions
and explanations because you're young.
But you will understand this one day.
And when it, happens,
I want you to imagine me there
to greet you.
Our lives stretched out ahead of us,
a perpetual sunrise.
But until then,
there must be no contact between us.
I have much to do, and you,
my darling, even more.
Please believe that I would do anything
to see you happy
and so I do the only thing I can...
I release you.
Hello?
Carol?
I miss you...
I miss you.
Therese, these are seriously
good. I mean, they really capture...
Whoever this is.
They're just practice.
You really wanna put together a portfolio.
Say the word,
I'll introduce you to my pal at the times.
There's always a clerk job going.
You went away with her, right?
Yes.
What happened?
Ohh. Nothing. It's hard to...
Is it because I tried to kiss you that day?
Because if it is, don't even think
about that, I mean, don't be afraid of...
I'm not afraid.
Let's finish while we
still have light, okay?
I still think you have to put
together that portfolio.
Okay.
More mashed potatoes, Carol?
Yes, thanks. They look delicious.
Thank you..
Chester Marge rindy I thought...
Maybe...
Chester and Marge would be here...
With rindy..
Marge said to go ahead, not to wait.
I'm sure they'll be here soon.
Harge tells us you've been
getting along quite well
with your doctor, Carol.
And why shouldn't she be getting on well.
He is a very expensive doctor.
Actually he's not a doctor
but a psychotherapist.
Well he is very well regarded.
A Yale man, like your uncle.
Does that make him a doctor?
But I do like him.
Very much. He's been a great help.
Oh baby...
My baby girl…
mommy!
Look how much you've grown.
Give me a big squeeze.
That's a long trip,
you must be hungry sweetheart.
You want something to eat?
Stay. Stay.
Don't be daft.
I don't know if I can keep it happen,
Abby.
How many more
tomato aspic lunches...
Then I come home every night without her.
To what like this!
And therese?
What about her?
Have you heard anything?
Oh no. No.
It's been over a month
since she tried to call.
Nothing since then. I wish I...
Have you? Heard anything?
From therese? No.
She must have started her job at the times,
though.
I should have said: Therese. Wait.
Who the hell is turning around in my drive?
I should go.
You don't have to.
I do.
We expect given the
seriousness of the charges
and the incontestability of the evidence,
the court will grant solo custody
of the child to my client.
Not so fast, Jerry.
My client's psychotherapist
is perfectly satisfied
with her recovery from...
The events of the winter
and is more than capable of caring
for her child.
She's had no further contact
with the girl in question.
We have the sworn
depositions of two saddle brook
institute psychiatrists
clearly stating that, in their opinions,
a series of events, precipitated
by my client's husband,
drove her to suffer an emotional break.
Which resulted in this described behavior.
That's absurd!
Furthermore…
alright Fred this is how
you're going to play this.
Furthermore, given the manner in which
these tapes were obtained and recorded
we're confident in their inadmissibility...
Okay. First off, I'd
like to see these depositions.
And second...
Fred... please.
Don't... may I speak?
I won't deny the truth of what's contained
in those tapes.
This is off the record, honey.
Might as well be on the record.
Harge. I want you to be happy.
I didn't give you that.
I failed you.
We both could have given. More.
But we gave each other rindy,
and that's the most breathtaking,
the most generous of gifts.
Why are we spending so
much time trying to keep
her from each other.
What happened with therese,
I wanted.
And I will not deny it or say that I reg..
But I do regret, I grieve
the mess we're about to make
of our child's life.
Harge we are both responsible.
Let's set it right.
I think that harge should
have custody of rindy.
Could I suggest that let's
take a break, folks
Fred, no.
Fred. Let me have my speak.
Because if you don't...
I won't be able to cope
I'm no martyr.
I have no clue what's best for me.
But I do know. I feel it
in my bones what is best for my daughter.
I want visits with her, harge.
I don't care if they're supervised.
But they need to be regular.
There was a time when
I would've done most anything
I would've locked myself away
to keep rindy with me.
But what use am
I to her, to us,
living against my own grain
so that's the deal.
I won't... I cannot negotiate anymore.
Take it or leave it.
If you leave it, we go to court.
We go to court and it will get ugly.
We're not ugly people, harge.
Carol, Carol.
Belivet
hand delivered. Swank.
I wasn't sure you'd come.
It's nice of you to see me.
Don't say that.
Do you hate me, therese?
How could I hate you?
Abby tells me you're thriving.
You've no idea
how pleased I am for you.
You look very fine, you know.
As if you've suddenly blossomed.
Is that what comes
of getting away from me?
No.
What?
Nothing.
Harge and I are selling the house.
I've taken an apartment on Madison Avenue.
And a job, believe it or not.
I'm going to work for a
furniture house on fourth
Avenue as a buyer.
Have you seen rindy?
Once or twice.
She's living with harge for now.
It's the right thing.
Anyway, the apartment's a nice big one...
Big enough for two.
I was hoping you might
like to come and live with me,
but I guess you won't. Would you?
I don't think so.
I'm meeting some people
at the furniture house
at the oak room at nine.
If you want to have dinner...
If you change your mind...
I think you'd like them.
Well. That's that.
I love you.
Therese? Is that you?
What do you know!
I'm saying to myself, I know that girl.
Jack.
It's great to see you, therese.
It's been, well, months.
Months.
Jack, this is Carol arid.
Pleased to meet you.
Likewise.
Hey, Ted gray's meeting me here
and a bunch of us are going down
to Phil's party.
You're going aren't you?
Yes. I just planned to
get there a little...
You should go ahead.
You coming along?
No.
I should make a few calls before dinner,
anyway.
I should really run.
You sure?
Of course.
Well, it would be great to catch a ride.
Yeah, sure.
You two have a wonderful night.
Nice meeting you, Jack.
Nice meeting you.
Alright, well let me go
make sure the loaf is on his way.
Back in a flash.
Yes, right up here.
It's about time, belivet.
Say hello at least
it hasn't been that long!
- Hello
- Phil sorry, I was...
There she is!
Get up there!
What?
Nothing! There better be beer. Or wine.
You can have her, she's one
of these real greenwich village
phonies if you ask me.
I'm gonna remember that. Charles.
Where are you going Ted?
Stick around a minute.
You're Phil's friend, aren't you?
I... am. Yes. I'm dannie's.
Aren't you going to ask me how I knew that?
Aren't most people here Phil's friends?
I can see why Phil speaks so highly of you.
Can you?
Sorry I'll be out in a minute.
Do you have a reservation?
Sorry I'm looking for someone.
I'm sorry ma'am,
I can't seat you without...
www.moviesubtitles.org