Dilwale
Re-Sync & Edit
Tharindu_Lakmal_Jeewantha
Good morning, Raj.
- Good morning, Raj.
- Good morning. Veer near where?
He went test drive trains that dah Jerry dibaiki.
Okay. Good, good.
- Good morning, Raj.
- Good morning.
Raj  Good morning.
Raj?
Why ni?
There's no nothing.
Still runsing think events tu?
Dah dah Raj 15 years.
- Thieves! Dare you steal!
- Death. Remove me.
What do you all make ni?
Please stop it!
Why beat him?
Already-never mind!
Why are you all beat him?
He stole En  train. Almeda,
tu loose bolt.
Bang. Why create a work that is not useful
ni?
I do not kid any kind of work for ni.
But forced to, I have a problem.
What is the problem?
The issue of wine or gambling?
Shakti. For him explain first.
I confess I stole!
But I work for ni
because my younger brother.
- For your brother?
- Yes.
Release mak death, I bear all.
Until forced to steal.
I stole was because nak
family responsibilities.
If yes also, why steal work?
Look for work more elegant.
I am illiterate, not educated.
I enlarged...
... To learn to steal.
If you do not steal,
what else I should do?
If you do not believe, be to my house.
There is a house but can not afford to pay the rent.
House there menthol but bergelap.
There is no money to pay the electric son.
BBang Bb .. .. Do not cry.
Shakti, like your wallet here.
- Smth bang.
- This is it.
- Bang. This is it.
- Abang ni money grab.
- Not! Do not suck!
Not even grab all the money ni je.
If you need money again, tu front of my house, came je
when-when.
A lot of money you for near Mani ni.
But I ni Encik thief.
It's your brother.
If it brother and sister...
... What we do does not make sense.
Because what we make, it comes from the heart.
What do you make Veer ni?
If so anything near the train ni
before getting near Jerry ..
..abang Shakti with brother Raj
we will do it later.
Siddhu Relax!
We dah tired-tired buggy custom ni ..
..saya Would not let him
calar even though Lama.
You sit next to and enjoy it!
Wey! He walked toward us.
Maybe her son overlap.
- Do not rested him eh!
- Why?
You forget what brother Raj message?
What is she?
Other names for women,
is unfortunate.
Empathetic, he was a self-je.
- I phone your brother.
- Telephone Gila what brother?
- Nak way to telephone my son?
- Yes, I will go ahead.
Beautiful girl punyalah tu, tu aje
wide apart.
Silent! Je road continues.
- Foot bodek brother!
- What?!!
Veer, what it also ni?
- I kid pee.
- Urine?
Jom piss all.
Temankan me.
What? Remember to dance duet.
There is a sense of kencinglah son.
You look at, hear je.
I'll have to pee boy too.
- Out there?
- Not.
- Dah out?
- Not again.
- Exit dah?
- Exit at last.
- I had that did not come out!
- Veer! Veer!
Urinary  taxable focus.
No one was kid look.
Less acid Veer!
You nak where ?! Veer !!!
- Hi.
- Hey. Ishita.
- Veer. May I please?
Damaged  Actually my bike.
Oh.
I nak to the Municipal council.
I am from Bangalore ..
..nak Please licensee to open a restaurant.
Today conductivity borang end dates.
Officials also closed 10 minutes again.
Please conductivity I may?
- Not in vain I left my friend earlier.
- What is she?
I mean, let me open the door!
Please.
Oh God, crowded street!
What we nak make now?
Do not worry.
Oh, fate has not been closed.
Veer, dah you help me.
Thank you very much.
No problem.
Dah my responsibility.
Bye!
- Hello.
- Veer?
- Yes bang?
Jerry dah telephone article asked her train.
All okay, right?
Yes bang, train ni ..
Okay  kot.
Raj.
It Veer guide the "fast" ..
But you do not "furious" anyway.
Smth Raj. Relax.
Cool heart.
Out of my son into the crate cool?
You also ni ..
What is the story ni? Various
where so kind ni?
This is all because of urine.
Diabetes?
Bang! At first he asked me pee ..
I temanlah him.
When my son pee, he disappeared.
Where did he go?
Oh. I think he went
extensive search field.
Raj, urinating in the field was Glory.
So I you ni Anwar!
Not lousy son tale character you anyway.
Veer, which sorts may be gini?
Earlier I favor a weak girl.
- Girl weak?
- Yes.
He hastily nak conductivity borang ..
..sebab Dah end dates.
I'm sorry, so I please conductivity.
I do not know she was an impostor kot...
Lagipun, brother taught me ..
..tolong Help the noble deeds.
Not kisahlah the evil to good.
When the matter of women, all must help.
When the train Damaged, anything can not help.
- Kan? Right? Right?
- Do not bang. Dah dah.
Haa, what laughter-laughter?
I have not finished the story piss article.
- You Ceritalah near other people.
- Abang Shakti?
Taoru! Bring here the player screws.
This is it ..
Bang, should I turn first?
I nak girlfriend brought me dinner.
Go.
But do not wear pants ni.
Thank you bang.
Pintoo, look ni,
can not open it.
Bang, I may as well return?
Ni son go where anyway?
Please uruskan
Taoru dinner with his girlfriend.
All right. Go.
- Tomorrow arrive on time eh.
- Okay bang.
Excuse me?
- Eh! Veer?
- Oh! Ishu!
- Ishu?
- What do you do around here?
Kind of you know,
scooter ni for it.
Not chapters in contact with the foot.
Let me look, I'm a professional.
- Ishu, scooter ni no "issue" seriously!
- Yes to?
So?
- What did you give your home address.
Dah ready repaired, I conductivity.
- What?
Paper work, borang all dah conductivity?
Dah. All because help you.
- Err. You mechanic?
- Mechanical ???
I'm the boss around here.
- You know, this is all for you.
- For me?
For carrying your son earlier, ni
until the train accident.
Cause tu ..
I created ..abang collar workers.
I hit the work from daylight to night.
Oh, I really am sorry.
I guilt on your Veer.
You taste what I taste?
Yela. Because I am right ..
You let here. Sitting
first. Sitting here.
- Who are you really?
- What?
I do not know why my heart told
partnership with your problems.
What is she? Ceritalah Veer.
You know what my brother made visible state
off the train tu?
What is he doing?
He slapped me in front of all the workers.
Huh? It was very embarrassing.
You do not stop him?
He's my brother.
The pain felt until now.
Let me see.
Invisible "marks" (former tampar) too?
Remember exam papers to no "marks".
Invisible cause pain tu here.
Ishita, you know?
My childhood diligent study.
But brother
spend money for my lesson, close to the women.
You do not fight to?
Not face- to-face with him?
You bertegas contact with Veer.
Bertegas what? What? Women
je ni suddenly.
- Veer?
- I do not like people mengata my brother.
Kot  This is my brother.
- Women's crazy. He's crazy, brother.
- What?
- Yes?
- I do not even know him.
Oh, so he's your brother.
What kind of brother you ni?
Able to make him quit school,
Always at her small childhood.
- Not ashamed of themselves?
- Shame too.
- Remove ni, do not make anymore, understand?
- Okay.
Veer, here.
You buried long dah all right ..
..so Luahkan everything now.
- Cakaplah Veer! Bold, wide your name!
- Yes, so daring!
- Proficient !!
- Cakaplah !!
I .. (dear .. brother ..)
What he meant,
heart he feels bad.
He nak you back first.
If I apologize close to him, in front of you ..
He do not think Glory.
My sister right.
But you do not worry.
I promise to apologize.
- All right.
- Thank you.
But you must not be afraid okay.
There is a problem, then call me.
- There are my numbers right?
- You save, right?
Do not worry!
He will not forget the telephone.
I'm sorry. Sorry. Sorry brother.
Where women to younger brother
tu dah clever for merepek story.
Dah! Jom eat.
Not! I swear I will not eat
while the train is not ready.
Although any bribe brother,
I would not be touched.
Do not Veer.
Do kinds ni.
Takkan not eaten all day?
Do not punish yourself.
Veer!
Well you double chicken burger.
- Hi bang.
- Hey!!
- You got it?
- Not.
Do you know? Abang should change anything else train.
But you can not change the temperament.
- Goodnight brother.
- Good night.
Jom.
Abang dah you grab a burger.
Out  ye son to eat?
I see you Ishita,
it dah for me satisfied.
Well coffee.
You taxable night work, right?
You really take the weight of my article.
Veer! We're dah kind of brother and sister.
Ops! Okay.
Work  good.
If sleepy coffee ni.
Okay? Take care of yourself.
Ishu! My first dah miss you.
Oh, God.
Translation corrected by: CahayaRiang
(Just a Hindustan films lover)
Good Morning
Veer.
Look here, son.
Kena once again to steal?
- Yes.
- Radio contact with stolen?
Yes.
- I fell asleep again eh?
- Eh taklah.
You vigil one night,
to train radio contact with stole.
So now, who is engrossed
stolen goods trains ni?
- Abang Oscar !!
- Hi, my cool.
Come here.
Here's your radio,
of rail BMW.
Good. This is my son.
Work  you good.
Like a kind of playing dominoes.
You bunk with good strategy.
I like the way you are.
Talented wide man ni,
we should present for wine.
Brother Oscar, if true
brother appreciated my talent ..
Divide  I Lama bonus.
Because today the anniversary of my girlfriend.
- I take heart her son.
- Can! Because today was the anniversary of my sister.
Hello Jenny, I dah aturkan
birthday party you ni evening.
Oh wow! WinCE
I asked my brother first.
Okay! Bye!
- Hello.
- Hello brother.
Hello my brother. What is wrong?
Comrades  I created for my birthday party
..
..boleh I join them?
Go.
Enjoy your life.
It's your money.
Go berseronok.
- Hi.
- Hai Veer!
Scooty you dah ready repaired.
Wah  good. thanks.
- How taxable pay?
- Pay? For you, no need to pay.
- The good you are.
- Why Veer?
- Huh?
Wait for someone to?
My friend took my son came.
I was told to come here.
But invisible nose too.
WinCE again reached.
While waiting, we drink coffee together?
- What do together?
- Coffee!
Veer. Actually earlier, middle
I Think ye.
What is she?
I mean, your brother on your attitude.
My lifetime, never meet a cruel man,
important: self-sorts your brother.
Abang what kind of feeling no tu?
Ishita, I dah lie to you.
Liar?
My brother
not like what I tell you.
He is a pity to me.
Affection was
you can not imagine.
He heed me in all cases.
So why do you make a wide ni?
When I respected your face, my heart struggled
talk with your son.
If dah boasted,
my heart very own boy friend you.
You also single, sudden sympathy with me.
I also get carried away ..
Veer, you're crazy, you know not.
Hi comrades.
This is my friend, Siddhu.
And that her girlfriend, Jenny.
- Hi.
- Hey.
Today is the anniversary of Jenny.
- Oh! Happy Birthday!
- Thank you.
Ishita, you must be bored
sitting home alone, right?
Nak look tv no good design, also should be moist
internet right?
- What?
What he means, what you said
join us dinner?
Mmmm. I ..
Do not reject the request "birthday girl".
Let Ishita.
We enjoy.
All right. I am getting used to.
I'm not going to sell you medicine nearby.
This is where young people berhibur.
I'm not going to destroy their lives by selling objects
kinds ni.
We are the King!
King! Ideology?
If we say sell, you hit selling medicine
ni.
Please forgive me.
What do you make ni?
Remove tu uncle.
Do not get mixed.
Uncle! You have to sell.
Release uncle,
if not my phone policy.
Oh God.
(Not understand what he's capable)
What?
Telefon. Why measles telephone him?
Dah broke even.
There are problems to?
You men friends he?
He's not my boy friend
Yes or not it was our problem.
Later we finish Ishu.
Uncle Joe! What is the problem?
They ni slaves King.
They tell uncle selling medicine.
Bye?
Take this and berambus!
Hey hero! You do not know what plagues you
ni dah day book.
You dah at the King.
- King will not let you get away.
- Berambus!
- Good night.
Bye. Bye.
At blasted slave ni.
Hoi  stop! Stop
Contact doctorate!
He's okay now.
Tomorrow you must take him back.
- Veer. Retiring taste okay?
- Thank you, doctor.
Honestly tell brother,
who are they?
I do not know.
Siddhu you know?
I .. I ..
I did not know bang.
- So to pain?
- Not.
- No pain whatsoever.
- You're the strong slave.
This is it. Pain medication may be you.
You ni nak phone right?
Yes!
But what kind of brother know?
- Veer. You okay?
- Ishu?
We ordinary comrade je.
Formal encounter.
- Betul not Ishu?
- Hi brother.
- Ishita.
What-whatever, cuba tell,
his name Ishita to Ishu?
- Everywhere the brother likes.
- Oh, I see?
Good thing you came.
I remember my son home to you.
Period  day you broke the phone.
It's a gift for you.
New Telefon, I traded.
Where can I take a gift ni.
I really should not be.
Take. He bought with affection.
Typical for you.
New Telefon.
Lagipun no telephone,
happy kid since formally.
Abang think you shall receive.
Thank you.
Hey. Take care of yourself.
Please keep yourself well.
Welcome back.
Amboi. The new phone.
We dah nak find out where they are.
Why the lights went out ni?
Hey. Who are you all?
Hey Michael. Go look.
Hey.
You do not know with whom you are searching chapter.
If King can know later,
he would not let go of you.
So, tell him my name.
Tell him, 'Kaali'
(God of Death) coming.
How much "stuff" we are there again?
- All dah no. Taxable depleted fuel.
- Got fuel?
Who dares find article with the King?
Who ??
I am invisible, because his face
lids.
But he was told his name.
How many times do you need to tell me
?
- Kaali!
- Kaali ???
Who Kaali ni?
King, slave Garaj which we tibai day
tu ..
..dia No brother.
Maybe it was him.
There's no way he's the one.
He tu and respected.
So we hit
match and find intimation.
Look what I made close them later!
What is it?
Why come here?
Veer. Veer.
What it ni?
Abang, these people hit me.
Yes, betullah right.
You beat them, they beat you back.
Fair.
Already-never mind.
You all go from here.
- But brother, they ..
- Veer!
You know brother not like pergaduhan.
Siddhu, take Veer away from here.
Dah jom come with me.
Pintoo. Taoru.
You all work continued.
I really am sorry,
I am ashamed of what dah so.
It is fair.
You are indeed a fair.
Taklah, big-hearted host.
I'm just a small shop owner.
As with a custom-trains as well.
Various host customized train pretty ni,
El Dorado, 1969. Definitely a very dear lord.
That is true.
And most importantly ..
The train was a gift from the father master.
Oh! Yes you really great!
- You train to this astrology?
- Ha ha. Astrology?
I know Lama-Lama alone.
Not kisahlah.
But how do you know my father article.
- You are indeed a great man.
- Not. Tuan actually great man.
Look at yourself, sir, recover hat.
Father must be very proud
host to host.
Not to?
- He dah died.
- I am sorry.
Mr. okay?
- Master's okay, right?
- I'm okay.
- May I say something?
- Yes, please, please.
I who killed my father.
He is not a great teacher but the head of the mafia
school.
If I take over and replace him,
I mulakan bisnes medicine.
So my father said was
contrary to our principles.
Against principle?
In bisnes no matter of principle !!
So I killed him.
Patrick. Joshua. Starting today, we make custom
train here.
So Raj, is the king of the train King.
- Aslo the verse I?
- Yes.
The location of the gun away.
The location of the gun away !!!
- You're afraid of the gun?
- It should be afraid any host.
Starting today, do not be afraid.
Because I am there for you.
If there is a problem, you call me
King.
If he Kaali, I am not King,
but the Queen!
Jom!
Look at them tu.
Bring pistols and wondering we fear not.
If I turn out good.
The whole world also looks evil.
- 15 Years Ago; Bulgaria -
We dah try Sedaya host effort.
But not succeeding barrier Kaali
of taking the former gold tu.
Raghav, are there people very great Randhir
..
..or
Those of us who are too weak and humid?
I used and Randhir equally
steal in the harbor.
But now he's my son plays tricks?
All the riches and honor
that he is now ..
..semuanya Because Kaali.
Shakti. You dah bush
guest list Meeting tomorrow?
- I dah bush.
- Nice.
You need swathe ni
and careful okay.
You all go ahead.
And the two tu, dressing and selling.
Beware ..
- Hi. Sorry.
- Yes, it is me?
I ..
Yes, that haritu.
I am sorry. For me you are injured.
There is none. No problem.
Two days healed.
Let me carrying you
with my train.
It's okay.
I take the tram near there.
Never mind. Let me
friends you there.
- May right?
- OK.
- I really am sorry.
- It's okay.
Who is chasing you haritu?
The weather today is very good.
You live in Bulgaria?
Actually my hobby fishing.
What?
You ni right, another
asked, the other answered.
Okay. Okay.
OK.
So who are they?
Samseng.
- Samseng?
- Hmmm.
Actually they gang enemies.
Meaning?
You've heard the name
Randhir Bakshi?
Big Mafia India dah moved here?
Yes.
And my son.
Why ni?
You're afraid to?
Not! Why my son scared?
I do not messed up your father, your father
will not kill my son.
I mean ..
- I'm not afraid.
- So why retreat to the back?
Tram right side.
Mari.
What's your name?
- M..Meera!
- Sedap.
Meera ..
(Dev Malik - Sinking behind siren)
And you?
- Kaali!
- Kekeke!
- Why?
- Nothing.
No, you're the new "kekeke" was.
Why?
You look kind of modern, but ..
Name .. Kaali ..
Oh. Tu name was not awkward.
Kaali good name.
Do not take heart okay.
Your father when angry, he must be capably ..
I vow in the name of Kaali (God of Death),
I will kill you.
Kan?
Not to?
Okay not!
- It was a joke. Indeed buffoonery.
- You no sense of comedy, right?
Meera.
You were born in Bulgaria to?
Tak.
Actually, my father from India.
He was very sukakan art and artifacts.
That's why we go to the gallery here.
And I also created an exhibition of street
for my paintings.
Yes, yes. Appeared earlier.
- Ohhh.
- Ouch. I .. I'm sorry very-very.
I think you look guilty in a state of sorts ni
.
- Guilt to?
- Very.
So pay my hospital bills.
What is she ??
Medicine, bandage, wood stick ..
- You know how expensive tu all?
- Eheh.
So if you for money near me ..
- Maybe the guilt you will be reduced.
- Okay.
Eh! Would not a small problem, son to the gun?
Not pistol.
Telefon.
Good luck!
- To me your numbers.
- Number me ??
Yela. I take your numbers, just off I call, you can numeric
me, fun ..
Oh, kind tu ya?
Yela. I mean, you should
to the hospital and ..
..nanti Can bil right?
So kenalah for telephone numbers, right?
Or .. Not ??
0887439!
088 743!
3 what ??
- 9!
- 9! Okay. I love 9.
- Come here sister brother.
- Abang!
- Dad!
- Veer How are you?
I'm okay je!
Just look ni. What gifts bring to your father?
Meaning
months I was back home?
What?
There was no pity me.
And brother.
Brother was dah not remind me, right?
- Why involve my brother?
- Veer.
Instant  father.
Let my conversation with him.
Father was right.
Kid brother did not know what the conversation.
You are correct.
We can only meet once a month.
But that ..
..hidup Without you,
day a month a wide sense.
You really well,
brother did not warn you.
Reason ..
Various  where our son near the
remember that we never forget.
And, you are correct again.
We do not bring your son back.
The reason also ..
We're building a new home.
House there is a large chamber
for Veer that cute.
The house where my brother, you and dad,
stay together.
- True to brother?
- Hmmm.
I love my brother.
Goodbye.
What Think father?
Middle Dad think ..
..kerana Perbalahan and this hostility,
We can not bring Veer
stay with us.
Because this will endanger the life of him.
And she was a child.
But, if you no Kaali,
- Dad does not know where the boy's face all kinds ni.
- Not the father.
It discharges father's heart.
Sometimes father flavor ..
Father does not do justice to you.
Veer conductivity father studied here,
But you, father heret you join father.
Father give the responsibility of a father to you.
Father always endanger the lives of you.
You know ..
You're not flesh and blood father ..
..ayah Hope you will not
misunderstanding with the intention ya boy's father?
Not father.
Never.
I no sesiapa dah.
Father who take and defend me.
May I also luahkan
what in my heart?
Father himself did not know ..
..yang My dear father,
more than Veer.
Promise with father Kaali,
which Veer never know ..
..kamu Not brother and sister were both younger.
He would not know until when-if ..
And the father was hit appointments
Starting today and until when-when
Do not call again about blood between us.
Be careful.
Welcome back dad.
Hi .. Meera.
Actually Kaali,
I called you here because ..
- There are some men always screwed me.
- Nice. Nice.
Kaali? Kaali !!
You heard right?
Yes. I heard it all.
There are some men engrossed bother me.
I do not think Glory.
In the area ni, I just
painter Indian nation.
They always give racist comments.
- Betul to?
- Yes.
Proficient alone, let me toward them.
Hindi Hey girls!
You to who painted it?
Perhaps painting my portrait?
In return, I give you a kiss.
Ayuh, do not be shy.
What is your problem?
Go away from here.
What dah so?
Son go where?
Where goings Poyo attitude you had?
Nothing son conversation? Huh?
And you? You kiss my son, right?
Kiss!
No?
Who's the man now?
I am the man.
Kid kind look where Indians make?
Here  Let me point to you.
Touch me. Touch me now.
Letaklah your hand, I will appoint
..
- What ??
- Dah go.
- Eh. Know went because of fear.
- Yeah.
- Jom.
- Okay.
Hebatkan way I taught them.
- Yes! Wow!
- Mahina. Pack all of ya.
- Thanks also to you.
- No, I do not make anything.
Meera, article hospital bills are paid
told you last night ..
Do not worry tu article.
- Today is your auspicious.
- Betul to? Why?
Did you help me right dah, dah
so I consider pay.
Wow. You are a man of great heart.
That's what should I make right.
Look  earlier,
if I did not make mixed ..
Yes, absolutely tu.
Primarily period "be a man" tu.
- It mengkagumkan.
- We hit them feared Lama.
If the old Lama earlier, I dah ..
Eh! Perhaps!
Please guard your emotions.
You do not understand Kaali. The world now,
we hit so brave.
If fear What kind of kid life?
Living in fear is like a ni ..
Oh God. Eeee.
Meera. Do not move!
Why?
If you move, he will bite.
Do not be afraid, do not be afraid!
Inhale. Bellows breath.
Inhale equally.
Naughty dog.
Good Meera ..
The dog will come back to?
Who?
I think the dog was afraid
with you and continue to run.
Meera. My son asked.
Was having lunch with my son?
Today I hit go gallery father.
It does not matter!
If tomorrow, dinner?
Tomorrow ..
Anniversary mother and father.
Oh. Unfortunately!
I mean, Congratulations.
- Breakfast in the morning the day after tomorrow?
- Lusa anyway ..
Do not proficient.
I just need five minutes you alone.
- Five minutes?
- Ouu. Only 5 minutes.
Ok. Set.
September Lama.
- Hi!
- Hey!
I remember you did not come.
Thank you.
Thank you very much because it comes.
- So?
- So. We have temujanji right?
- You know you have 5 minutes je right?
- Yes, I know.
- And your time starts now.
- Okay. Okay. Your scheme.
Come here fast!
- This ride?
- Yes, because our son goes away.
Quick  ride. Do banyal matter.
- Thank you, Robert. Lama fast!
- Okay boss!
- To the restaurant.
- Restaurant?
Yes yes. Hungry right?
We mulakan to eat first.
- You know 5 minutes je?
- Yes, I know, I hear.
Cuba  let me know, you dah
story how special your father ..
So, there sesiapa
more special in your life?
I think you also dah know?
Indeed I dah know.
If you are special, you should not come
temujanji us.
And .. We dah up.
Jom down.
- Thank you very much Robert.
- Equally boss.
Meera. This is my favorite restaurant.
- This is the first time I bring friends here.
- Betul to?
Please sit down.
- Uh, are you? Dah exchange work?
- He permissiveness.
Tell me, you son eat what?
Arab food? China? France?
Italy or England?
- China!
- China.
Thank you.
Meera. All paintings tu,
you are painting to?
- Yes. You like?
- Yes. Never see you as beautiful as it is.
Actually, pretty until
son could not look away.
It seems that you are not capable
article painting.
- Kaali?
- Hmmm?
- Kaali !!!
- Huh?
Oh yes, yes. Give me bil.
You dah pay hospital bills, so I paid
.
It's okay, I must pay.
Wear check.
Checks should not be.
Cash sake only. This is it.
Do not waste time.
Come quickly!
We are 5 minutes je.
Hurry up!
- Savory food, dessert What kind?
- Dessert?
I kid aiskrim.
- I kid ice cream!
- Aiskrim? Okaylah.
Quick!
- Dah-long period. Fast.
- Okay boss. Okay.
- Go aiskrim my shop.
- Shop aiskrim you?
- My dad had.
The fate of the hours of the day no ni.
- If you do not slow us up.
- Dah up to the boss.
Dah up? Nice. Hurry up.
Pick aiskrim come to my shop.
- Swap working again?
- He was a talented ni.
Nak perisa what?
Vanilla? Butterscotch? Strawberry?
- Belgian chocolate chips.
- Who??
Belgian chocolate chips.
B .. B .. B .. Belgian? Chocolate chip?
Not in vain way away,
can also perisa your indulgence.
Belgian chocolate.
Mmmm. Savory. I like.
Kaali  Actually, when you look,
I never thought you create the danger of work.
I know. I winsome man.
There is the fear?
First you must not be weak ..
..and It off,
not fear anything.
But .. I do not know the...
So, there is nothing more surprises?
Dah course. He is not over yet again.
It was you. thanks.
Flowers, to shoo my girl.
Thank you. So pretty.
Equally .
- There's more to?
- Not.
You just give me five minutes. So ..
Temujanji ..
- ..habis.
- Oh. Loss.
So .. I think .. You like me ..
Dah course I love you.
All my bills paid, it was cash.
I really like you seem.
Sure enough.
So, see you tomorrow?
Tomorrow I have an important job.
May Lusa?
But .. The next day I was born.
Sorry, I do not know.
If you do not come,
I do not welcome the birth of my son.
Not kinds tu Meera ..
Tomorrow I hit carrying goods to Romania.
My father  dah "kawtim" with border policy,
and all dah regulated.
We dah appointments with buyers,
so can not not go.
If sorts tu, I can come right?
- Greet the day I was born on the border. Great idea, right?
- No!!
Idea that is not good.
Former gold mine  son conductivity,
our enemies, Malik, was mahukannya.
He's just waiting for the opportunity
grab the golden boy of mine.
And you do not know Malik.
He is very dangerous.
Miscellaneous  may be.
You can not come, I did not know
What kind of dangers that may exist.
You taknak take me. Greet the day of my birth was not.
If you do not exist, I would welcome the day of my birth.
All right. Wherever wide, je
ready to work tomorrow afternoon, I came back.
To be on your side.
Promise?
Promise !!
- Promise?
- Yes.
I promise.
- Kaali? Tomorrow we would meet again.
- Ahah.
- There ekori us.
- Proceed.
Hi.
Why ni?
You look kind of surprised.
Like a kind of inverted dah world.
I dah right word ..
We will definitely meet the ni.
And, what do you say?
Do not participate .. Never .. Danger ..
Actually, the danger that you mention it ..
The danger of it is ..
I !!!
You do not understand?
Cuba remember really Kaali.
What is the full name of my
I tell you?
Meera. Dev. Malik.
Malik!
My dad.
..yang He is now,
everything because Kaali.
You know what's most interesting today?
Today is the day of my birth,
but I will be present for this gold to my father.
For me the kind of big heart.
So I designed all of this.
What ..
..kamu Remember I accidentally collide with trains
you?
I myself ran to the front of the train you.
So that my people should kill you.
But they did not prevail.
So, I was forced to approach you
to get the gold clause tu intimation.
I'm willing to be a decoy.
I make my people as my enemies.
And forced to go you stupid temujanji tu.
Oh, God!
Whatever ..
Various  where lakonan me?
Standard Intl right?
Not to?
I release you this time.
Lagipun day today so I'm right.
- Now Malik's father will not let go!
- No, dad!
Father do not make anything.
I betrayed.
I will do what I need to make.
- But ..
- Please father.
Let me see you once Meera.
- Hello.
- Stop the train Meera.
Meera. Stop the train.
Meera  Stop the train!
Do not be afraid!
I'm not going to release you.
I sincerely cintakan you from the heart ..
..and You, you evil minds poisoned.
Starting today,
do not point you face the front of me.
I will kill you.
I'm sorry.
I made a lot of wrong to you.
But you ..
..cuma Sincere love me.
What do you believe ..
That's love.
Just who membezakannya ..
You are aware right from the beginning again,
But my new, conscious now.
Maybe you do not trust me ..
But I need to know you ..
I cintakan you.
Kaali. Kaali, please listen first.
While you do not trust me,
I will not go from here.
Help Kaali.
Please trust me.
Cik nak dinner?
Okay. Perhaps the middle of diet ..
But now heavy rain,
I bring my son ..
Coffee Coffee .. ..
Not son?
What are you trying to prove my son?
What I cintakan you.
And why do I need to trust you?
When I was cintakan you ..
You trust me ..
And now I dah first cintakan you ..
You can not trust my son?
What is the problem?
I do not kid cheated again.
If I Hankey,
you should shoot me dead.
Pistol, rifle, shot dead,
Kill, take lives ..
That's just to you know?
I do not know.
But you certainly know ..
Teach me ..
Please help ..
I think we need to tell us about the relationship family
ni.
I do not mahu later ..
They know of other people.
It's not beautiful right.
Yes, it is also capable you are.
I will try my father Pujuk.
But what kind of father you?
Fear him think, this time my dad and son design
that you hokey.
I will try make him understand.
And lagipun, hate him to you ..
..tak Maybe longer than
her affection on me.
Yes. I certainly.
But right ..
If the correct word my dad and I
designed for circumvention you this time?
So I'll shoot you.
- Kena steal again?
- Yes !!
- The light rail is stolen?
- Yes.
- I fell asleep again?
You are so consistently the Veer.
Evening ni ni nak-carrying train back to his master.
But the headlights do not exist.
I do not know what kid so.
Do not worry brother.
It was my fault.
Let me finish, leave it to me.
Anwar, what you do?
Raj. This thief.
Look what he stole.
- Mani, first you steal behind?
- Not. Not.
- This kek.
- That's what I try tell.
- Mani, now you steal kek anyway?
- Tak Raj, so my day today.
Kek  I bought it.
Look. This resitnya.
I nak welcome with Raj,
is why I bought this kek.
But can you accuse me of stealing?
Sorry Mani. Sorry.
Anwar, ye ni was accused not think first.
Actually Mani, today there are
theft again in this Garaj.
That applies Lama cause mistakes. Forgive me.
- Now, let's cut.
- Cut whom ??
Cut ye kek ..
- Create my fear je.
- Anwar brought candles
Anwar is rapidly kind of emotion, forgive him yes.
Hey sedara ..
Why face kind of problem?
Mani, light dah subject to import stolen.
Where is my son looking new?
- The light rail imported huh?
- Yes.
Do not worry.
There was a man shall please.
Oscar.
Wah Mani. Your mate seems possible dah ..
Best thief I've told before,
he may bring light you are looking for.
Because last night he had stolen.
Create quickly Lama.
Look ni, speaker and radio
dah nak no purchase.
What is this anyway, steering BMW.
It's all it was he who got, Mani.
So if he is coming?
I mean, you're a thief.
Wait in 5 minutes longer.
- May be on the way.
- Okay!
We can not wait to meet her son.
He who lesapkan goods from our Garaj.
Let him come here.
I would gari his own hands.
- Why son gari?
- Because my son made her guests.
There was the same man
I Think now?
Brother Oscar.
Dah until the thief was my number one.
Place it here.
I know you did bring a profit.
Take this money and be glad
with your girlfriend.
But before that let me try ..
Where did you steal all the valuables ni?
- With coffee.
- Coffee?
Coffee  ??
Brother Oscar, I have a friend ..
She was entrusted to me.
So I gave him coffee mixed with sleeping pills.
Siddhu !!
Huh ?? Vv vv .. .. Veer?
Various  where you should be here?
- Veer hear first what my son said.
- Thieves blasted !!
- Veer, we may talk over a cup of coffee.
- Coffee?
Coffee mak you!
Suffice tu  Veer.
I dah assume you kind my brother.
Other people steal I may receive.
But can you make a wide tu ??
Jom go Mani.
Why Veer?
When people get a belasah
no word stopped ..
So why did you stop?
Dah told you a hundred times to stop!
Mani, the only cubaan
I make "extempo".
What is she?
Release caned
dah nak went wide tu je?
I call "extempo" Mani.
Large Bala wide to where?
Silent Mani!
Veer.
You seem dah you what
"brother" is dah you make.
Kind of which he made.
You said you consider
I kind of brother, right?
But you do not ask me why I do this?
Look at my situation.
Shabby clothes. Pants, old shoes.
They never exchanged.
I never spend money
for yourself.
All that I can,
I use for my girlfriend, Jenny.
Not happy kid lure him ..
You just see the fate of your life.
You enlarged in male hostels.
Never let alone women seem son sex.
Our lives are surrounded  brother, uncle-uncle.
The life of our youth is wasted
surrounded by men.
Yes you said Siddhu.
Remember not.
Painstakingly Punyalah my son ngorat Makcik Monica.
Makcik?
Yes.
People salaries.
Oh yes to.
I'm serious.
But I could not luahkan feeling,
he dah ran off with someone else ..
Life is dah pull us too deep ..
..sampai We do not see you way out.
Now ni, I still have not dared to tell Ishita
.
What I cintakan him.
Veer. Why are you crying?
You cried.
"Abang"
you who is still alive again, right?
I will help you.
- You'll help me, right?
- Yes.
You will help me, right?
You will not tell my brother who stole right?
Evil slave.
Sorry. But you look at it later
idea what I was going for.
You will surely prevail.
You are my help,
everyone else I will please.
We are also in contact please Mani
looking for a female friend for her.
Are you capable?
Until now, my father did not think my article,
but you take the weight.
You are not human but angelic.
I was always right there.
Veer. You wait and see what my son made.
You look at it later.
What ni?
What is your son doing?
Veer  Where? Hitherto unseen?
Veer? Cuba look there.
He's waiting for you there.
Wait for me?
- Hi.
- Hey.
Ishita, this time I did not dare.
But ni Christmas night, my son tell something.
About what?
About my heart ..
Cakaplah.
Crowded
which comes with a special friend at Christmas party ni.
And they have to scramble kid so my friend.
But I only mahu go with ..
..gadis In this mirror.
I do a lot of lying on your
But the people said, on Christmas day
we got the right conversation.
And actually ..
..saya Really (I Love You)
And every day life,
I spend with your son.
Although later you get old like this.
(Abang restuilah I)
Veer?
- I kid capable of something.
- Cakaplah.
I think we need to tell each family
about our relationship.
Why haste Ishu?
I mean, we've made love.
Veer. I do not kid they knew of others.
I do not think beautiful.
We need to tell them about.
- Yes.
- What ya ya?
I will be back and tell my family,
And you tell your brother,
or my son...
Ishu ..
We cintakan each other right, why nak
stealth.
Tell my brother excited objects je.
Dah few minutes passed Veer,
nothing son conversation?
From a conversation something was busy boy, boy
ably something. What is she?
- I kid partnership discharge my heart on my brother.
- Okay.
- I just need Lama je period.
- Okay. Okay. Take your time.
I kid through the first night.
By whom?
Su Su  .. .. Subash !!
I tell the kid brother Subash article.
Tomorrow bring her son to come "bumper".
Punyalah long, that je nak tell you.
Do not worry, brother later take "bumper" from Subash.
I kid lies "Sindhoor" on the forehead brother.
- Veer!
- No!
What you object capable ni?
- I kid kiss lips brother.
- Heppp!
You dah crazy to?
Do not know what he merepekkan.
Let me tell.
I dah nak bit him hard to tell!
Actually brother ..
We cintakan each other.
- Betul to?
- Yes !!
And I do not kid brother heard the news
ni from others.
- I think not beautiful then.
- Raj?
Veer always mistaken for "call" (decision).
But this one, maybe not.
- Yes, it seems it is not a "fake call".
- Eh! You ni Anwar.
Abang really sorry.
Actually, brother, son indeed meet your family.
- If tomorrow free, to know. Brother came later.
- Okay.
Encik. Puan will go down in 2 minutes longer.
Encik boy drinking water? Coffee to tea?
Not mengapalah. It also allowed.
Please forgive me. I think you ..
Now I know you brother Veer dah ..
I would not be justified Veer Ishita meet again.
You are wrong Meera.
I tell you, son, True case ..
But at that time you dah go away.
You betrayed my trust dah Kaali.
Today because Ishita,
I would forget about it and let you get away.
But if you come again,
I will kill you.
- Nak ..
- Yes.
You dah uncle
with honesty assure you ..
But what kind of father are you?
Uncle so he knew ..
He will not have the blessing of your relationship.
I will try Pujuk him.
All right! Dah dad willing to meet them both.
Thank you, father.
Other objects is not the story of my father,
but the father could not look you sad.
Mr. Malik!
What master do?
Mr. nak enter the master's son to the enemy?
You do not understand Raghav.
For a Meera, I will make just about anything.
But I can not see the defeat itself.
It seems that now we are in contact with Finish this hostility.
Always we hear and see,
friendship ..
..berubah Into family relationships.
But Malik, who is probably the first time we hear
,
Hostility so long,
exchange into a family.
There is only one way
Finish son Randhir hostility.
"Finish" your enemy.
Meera where?
You know Kaali?
Meera very cintakan you.
But perhaps he will not appear
you and your father died.
Meera. Kaali and father
dah toy with us.
They attacked us first.
Meera just try understand the present situation.
By what applies to Randhir Bakshi,
they all will not sit still.
If not yourself, please fikirkan
Ishita article.
If he knew about this case,
what will be on him later.
I dah assume you kind my brother.
Listen to my advice.
Take Ishita and go away from here.
And mulakan new life.
We will was always on your side
like a shadow.
Meera dah go away from here.
No one knows
where he is going.
But I need to see him ..
It's important for him to know what exactly happened
.
Kaali. I am not a wise
But one case I studied
off this bloodshed,
This life only once.
Well you forget everything.
And fikirlah about yourself Veer.
We are always together right.
We are both beginning a new life.
Believe it or not,
But the prevailing story 15 years ago,
Now repeated.
Far  wherever we try to run,
met also our back.
True Raj, punyalah many other countries besides India and Bulgaria
..
Who knows, here too they live.
For a long time I tried to hide everything than Veer.
Veer nak  I do not know the truth until
when-when.
Whatever we try to stop contact with Veer.
Lagipun Meera ..
Takkan blessing of their relationship.
But this is about my life kak.
What is the problem?
The problem is too big.
Sister no longer talk about ni nak.
Forget him.
But why?
What is so between brother and sister Ishita?
Until he does not agree?
Kan brother dah conversation, do not ask any questions.
- Is why.
- Abang !!!
Veer!
Abang dah ably right, is why.
- This is something very serious.
- But what does his thing tu?
Just look at eh Sid.
Abang and Meera should know each other.
If you do not, why they do not agree?
- Who knows the story of your brother last?
- Abanglah!
Answer dah well.
But tu wrong direction.
Story ago you brother ..
My brother would know.
Peter, bring them the most special food.
Brother did not know!
Go, there are crowded customers ni.
Bang. Kid eating kid to look at the TV?
Instant. 5 minutes longer my order.
Abang should know.
But just hide.
While no story, I do not kid go.
- You ni the Veer.
- Abang Shakti, Ceritalah.
Abang Anwar, Ceritalah.
Abang Anwar, an oath on my behalf.
Help inform.
Various  where my son said no...
Their story?
- They both are thieves!
- Anwar ??
- Huh ??
That is, they stole the hearts of each other.
Meaning brother Raj with Meera lover?
Abang Anwar, Ceritalah from the beginning.
- Real name your brother, not the Raj.
- Anwar !!!
He cuba nak conversation, your brother
real name ..
Ramlal.
Ramlal?
- Ramlal really like pounder hand.
- You mean he ..
- In order to wash your hands.
- Why?
- Because he handyman dobi.
- Abang artisan dobi ???
So sister Ishita real name?
Pogo.
Pogo  ??
Ramlal and Pogo. Various
where they meet?
One day Pogo walk alone,
No bad guys go with him.
Then Ramlal at them.
Abang not possible at the...
Abang you the artisan dobi.
He libas libas kinds of fabric.
- Remove tu?
- Pogo cup of tea a day-to-day.
- Then...?
- Then during the night he demolished all.
- Why demolished anyway?
Pam water! Pam water!
For use pam Ramlal tu
water to wash her clothes.
If their love is strong
why they hate each other?
"Now I'm waiting"
Gold is my God.
Pogo very sukakan
goods container and diamonds.
That their love story kind ..
Khana (Eat) Khazana (treasure) ??
(Draft cuisine)
Dah food anyway?
What merepek ni?
For Ramlal like to eat,
and Pogo sukakan treasures.
- And after that?
- ..and Then
The days they wail
until one day Ramlal ..
- So sida!
- Abang so sida? What kind of be ..
Tak. Mean she...
finally finished sida.
Abang so sida once again?
- Veer, patutlah brother you do not kahwin.
- You shut up!
Finally Ramlal leave Pogo,
because not able to fulfill the will of him.
And then both ..
Manifestation of the abyss (Daraar) ..
Split (Judaai) ..
Hostilities (Dushmani) ..
Stail (Tashaan) ..
Oh God (Oh My God) ..
What so between them until "Oh my God"?
It's just an expression alone.
If dah visible enemy,
must necessarily call "Oh God" !!!
Hey Peter !!
Please lift this man out ..
And grab the TV remote from him
before I cut her finger !!
Abang Shakti, as I recall ..
..masa I was a kid ..
..bila Brother and father come visit me in the dorm,
..pakaian They are beautiful and stylish.
Train  big. Our rich period tu ..
Kan your brother artisan dobi!
Him to outfit her customers.
And your father the mechanic.
She borrowed her train customers.
That's what you remember the rich.
You mechanic, you must understand.
Go repaired vehicles there.
Go! Go!
Abang. But our father waitress ..
You are the same, get out!
Out!
It's a very touching story of emotions.
Anwar ..
Who am told you mulakan story?
Dah slaves tu urgent.
Earlier tu  okaylah, but who do not understand ..
Why not kahwin-kahwin brother?
Come here.
- I'm just wondering je.
- Because no kid brother so dad !!!
Look ..
Until now brother
laundry everyone.
Ramlal?
Hey Ramlal.
What is in contact with both of you?
It may not release? Why ni?
Abang Anwar dah Shakti and stories on our
all the stories brother.
Everything?
Abang.
This is the hand that working hard is not it?
Who?
- Why brother seems to be afraid?
- No .. No .. Not afraid ..
Meritorious dah big brother's hand.
Brother had been a handyman dobi!
Artisan dobi?
Abang artisan dobi ??
We know all the stories
dah article Ramlal and Pogo.
Ramlal?
Who?
Pogo.
Give me.
Starting today, let us make.
Abang may go.
Okay enough!
Bye Ramlal.
Raj, we do not tell
The real matter at Veer.
But I do not tell too
you make me Ramlal.
We kot mafia.
Yes. But they urged,
ready to swear ..
- We kid for which kind.
- Proficient je do not know.
Where may not know, we live together
years.
Lagipun Raj, we were there people's lives.
So you're both plays tricks my people's lives?
Take a look at my personality, which is equal to a portion
Ramlal?
Apologize Raj.
Why are you so angry?
Because I know the temperament of Veer.
He will not be silent.
Release hear your story,
he would not stop to think to know, True story.
And who Pogo ???
Pogo? Sister real name?
I do not believe the story ni.
And my brother leave your brother because of money?
It may very well.
I heard from an old friend's brother.
From her brother ni.
All ni  true. Various
where with us?
What would you remove yourself
both days.
Where knew Ramlal and liquid
Pogo hearts and change minds.
They are not allowed to liquid-liquid aiskrim.
Nice work, you kahwin run.
Tak. Dah brother sacrificed so much for me.
I could not lukakan him.
I was not allowed to create a wide brother tu.
Wink! Ishu?
Why until now brother and sister we kahwin
no longer?
Why?
Because they still save more memories ..
"One night stand" should not be forgotten tu.
Veer. You ably middle chapter of my brother.
Okay, you try to think about.
They had sex once.
If we make them fall in love again?
We are united behind them.
What do you think?
- Meaning finished our problem.
- Exactly.
Various  where nak unite them?
Only God knows.
Patrick. I heard there is a new restaurant opened.
Yes, sir kedainya named Meera.
You go talk to him now.
Dude, Where's my train?
Here.
Where do I train?
- Patrick, train tu no medicine!
- What?
- Veer?
- Yes.
- I have no idea pithy to close the Ramlal and Pogo.
- What?
Various  ni, we will pursue Pogo samseng conductivity.
When you enter round heroin with bad people,
future hero had come to save.
The wicked hit wrap,
hero heroin was united.
What united objects?
For nak unite behind the old love,
Your idea for any age old idea.
Veer! Arak which brooded long tu
most intoxicating.
You just say yes only.
And later you lo ..
You'll praise my idea and said ..
"Great Idea!"
- Who kid so samseng?
- We'll look for.
That train King.
Mani. Why do you scout train King?
I know this train King.
- So this is buggy stolen?
- And train King also tu.
If King can know, drop me.
Please exchange the color of this train,
so I should sell.
Mani, you also know,
if the goods are stolen, I will not help.
But because trains ni sir my enemy,
So I'll help you.
But we got the first
hide from Abang Raj.
Hide this train and
do not tell my brother.
- Boy lying on Brother Raj?
- My son to know the article you stuff?
I will not forget your help.
Tak. Not.
Raj dah much please me, you too.
Starting from today,
if the boy for help anything ..
You should let me know.
I could make anything for you.
- Mani. Our son for help.
- Call je !!
- You please contact us acting so samseng.
- Samseng?
You need to be acting in the love story of a brother Raj.
For the hero and heroin together before,
Before the bad guys kidnap heroin
hit first.
It may please the Mani?
For the sake of Raj, the life I was able to pawn.
Name. The place. Animals. Goods.
Just say it!
Call it !!
Mani. Remember, it all depends on you.
Ye are our expectations.
Veer! Look! Dah come.
Hopefully prevail.
Good luck.
Son to die?
Ke Lama edge.
- My son just asked you a question.
- What is she?
- No baby to your house?
- No.
I appears there is an opportunity here.
The baby will be born.
Great Idea.
Selalunya brother Raj this time will last.
Now you will be able, "Uhuuhuuhuu."
"What exactly are you, son?"
I will be able, "Hahahaha."
Release ye tu conversation, "Do not lay a hand on me."
You also capable, "Please."
Then I capably, "Jeritlah."
But here,
no one should save you.
Good lakonan Mani.
Great Idea.
Then you come near me,
And powerful handheld my hands.
New  you're conscious of time tu,
Here no sesiapa
which may come please....
No sesiapa. No.
Yes !!
- YOU.
- I?
Nak remove what the tu?
Hey! Hey! Hey! This stratagem.
Hey, I never at women.
Although women,
I will not forgive you.
What ni, women at...
Why did you hit me?
Jom unplug!
Please !!
Where did you son go tu?
Pogo dah mulakan WWF channel.
Oh mak.
Oh mother, I dah ruined people's lives.
Dah beaten to shreds.
All slaves because both ni
run my left.
Please, you two,
you call this great design.
Who had the idea ni?
- She !!!
- Look. Dah save my brother love.
All objects exist had.
You dah crazy to Veer?
- Abang...
- Veer !!
You all remember,
to create a kind of ni...
That relationship ended dah.
You will not prevail. There was no avail.
Veer  And this is all not beautiful.
Do not make stupid ni case again.
Stop everything.
Various  where brothers should capably kinds tu?
Ab .. Brother?
Actually, I do not believe
brother sister leave because of money.
And when he left ..
Why until now he did not kahwin with others?
Ye tu  Memorable question.
Ask again.
Why did not he find a life partner?
Proficient again, again ..
And
brother was no relationships with anyone the right?
Yes brother. Why.
Answer.
Yes brother, until now no see brother
replacement again.
Takkan you do not get caught everywhere
with the girl?
Mani ..
Brother Raj?
What is the heart's brother,
only brother who knows.
But my obvious state of my brother ..
Even with what dah so,
But the far corner of the heart...
He may not be able to forget his first love.
Hantarkan this train Veer.
Abang dah untouched.
Veer! In my brain came a new idea.
Mani...
- Ishita, sister, son went Meeting.
- Later you please close the restaurant yes.
- Bye ..
Enjin
the train he would stop on the way to Panjim later.
And my brother is going to last
tu region every day.
Ishita, this opportunity will not be separated again.
Veer.
Work  you're so great.
I mean, the best.
You exchange the entire train ni dah.
King was not Cam.
Amazing man!
Veer, why ni?
Why are you kind of not a good mood?
We make all kinds dah nak
united Ramlal and Pogo but to no avail.
I do not know why my son now.
Veer. I no idea...
Your Idea?
Takpe. Not. Not.
At least listen first.
What if we raised
flame of their love?
The fire of love? How?
Near the puppet now, there is one movie ni
.
We bought a ticket for a seat
tip.
If the watch together,
fire their love will bloom again.
Film  what?
[[Movie 3rd Rate]]
Come here.
Front exquisite je!
Idea should not be used.
Veer. Good riddance tu film.
I dah watch.
Bang! There beg in Bonet.
Who has this bag?
Perhaps Mani know.
Beg is not mine
If not you, who has?
Manalah I know.
Whose?
Oh God. Bye.
Bye?
It must goods King.
What we make with objects ni nak now?
Even if medicine ni all marketed ..
I do not know who will be the prey.
So what we nak make now?
We burn.
Bye rosakkan ni dah many young people.
Hey King, you dah stuff on fire. Nudity
I look.
It seems Mani dah drunk.
Let him. She was sexy tu.
Mani, guard yourself Lama.
Why son had passed away?
Remove all.
She drunk excessive dah.
Take him flip.
Eh! King there is near here.
King Lala.
What do you burn?
For ye know what fuel?
- We burn the goods train.
- What?
Once a month, scrap near Garaj,
we burn and make a camp fire.
Good for the younger generation.
What do you make here?
I Damaged Train.
We should fix.
Jom Mani. Jom.
Turn the engine  him.
- Pffttt?
- What is she?
Why are you laughing?
He reheat themselves with him we burn stuff.
Mani! Shut up!
If he heard what kind?
Veer. He went there.
Hurry spend.
Kinggu.
You look "smart" once.
Thank you.
But if there is a train penchant your father tu,
must again smart.
Bye bye to the train tu?
Not bye, right?
- King! Do serviceability him. He was drunk.
- Mani !!
Kinggu!
There is nothing in the wagon?
It did not meet?
Hey! Do not brash.
That King !! King!!
Hep! King ni my angel.
Kinggu!
Dah can meet Kaali?
It did not meet.
Train'm ready!
Why are you screwed him.
Bye!
Veeru.
He dah go!
Ramlal and Pogo dah bye to?
They did not meet again right.
Get out!
We are the King!
I said get out!
Joshua.
It Kaali.
Why ni Veer?
Dah come diligent church.
Various  where suddenly become pious ni?
Yes bang.
In our lives there are two important matters.
Train and handle.
- Cantikkan church ni?
- Yes.
- Abang, I go grab a candle WinCE.
- Okay.
- Brother waiting here, I go grab a candle.
- Okay, off you go.
Why are you ekori me?
I came here with Veer.
Where is he?
Raj. You are also here.
Why fool ni come here?
Joshua tell me, you're Meera.
Let me introduce myself.
I am King.
Good thing you were here.
I kid you meet.
Last night, my people into your restaurant, suddenly ..
..Kaali Come.
You know who Kaali?
If you know, to know me.
I promise my people will not bother you again.
Just  I will kill him alone.
You know Kaali?
I do not know.
If I can dah Kaali later ..
You know not?
I pray Kaali will not meet with you.
We do not know ..
What also will be later ..
I mean, at him, not you.
- I hit go first.
- Okay.
Veer. You did great work.
Like a kind of exchange
home telephone so the smart phone ..
Iron  bad so Iron Man ..
Bats (Bat) so Batman ..
And spider (Spider) so Spiderman ..
Down  wide black Blackberry, on "Buffy Larry".
So-so I bought airplanes.
- Bit-plane rather what price?
- Come tu. For those prepared to work.
It trains King !!
- If she knows it ..
- I do not know what your destiny.
True tu.
Exactly.
Take Courant you ..
Go on a shopping and panties.
Pants in?
Oscar, you look very happy today.
What is the case?
Today if you ask me anything ..
I will give it to you willingly.
Why?
For this day my sister told
him having sex with someone.
Man's slave masters had a hotel.
- What?
- Yes.
Tomorrow me to her house, talk
chapter of their relationship.
And if it be ..
I train ni nak
give as a gift of their marriage.
Where the right words?
Prize or gift?
Where one should ever Oscar.
Prize was granting too.
Sure enough. Samalah our minds.
Accept is love.
- Siddhu! It was Jenny.
- Jenny.
- Hi all.
- How are you Jenny?
Jenny, why did you come here?
- Most do not even telefonlah first.
- Cuba puzzle.
- What is she?
- I dah tell my brother all of our chapters.
- And he agreed that we kahwin.
- What?
- In fact, he son come meet you.
- What do you mean? Jenny...
- So why wait here anymore.
- Abang where you waiting for?
- Brother-in-law...
- Eh Siddhu !!
Encik Oh brother brother in law ..
Where are you?
Brother Oscar.
Aha. What do you make here?
Brother was why here?
I come see you boy friend of my brother man.
I also kid brother bye my lady friend.
Where is he? Bring here.
's Him. This person.
- You?
It seems you dah know each other.
Kan?
They did know each other very well
.
The outside and inside.
If he had brought from the outside, he's ni
will be brought into.
Great  right.
The outside and inside? Veer
What do you mean?
Sister. I'll tell my brother.
She ni thief number one on the market.
Thief? Siddhu, you thief?
Aaaaa .. Your brother was a thief too.
Ready  there are stalls selling stolen goods anymore.
Items I stole, it was he who bought
.
Forget your lady friend's brother.
Your brother in sight tu.
- Shakti, wait patiently.
- Dah dah enough.
Here you. Here here!
Brother there to teach you steal?
There kebulur to me for him?
So why did you steal?
This girl causes all...
Abang. Today it ..
Ask  everywhere youth like me.
Various  where expensive nak sex.
If you go look at the puppets, dah
800 rupees fly.
And if my son combo buy popcorn and samosas ..
Fly 900 rupees.
And if baby I'm a coffee,
price is 1000 rupees.
And if overnight telephone,
"hello, dear, miss you, love you" ..
"Mmuuahh mmuuahh mmuuahh"
Sedar not aware 2000 rupees exhausted.
And and and ..
anniversary of contact for the prize.
Valentine's Day! Pun gifts.
And when he said,
"Baby, Friday we'll see you first."
So every ulangminggu, gift again.
I mean .. Need to ???
- Large boarding.
- Abang what know.
Period brother is very disparate.
The streets in the flower garden,
brother succeeding mooring dah tu girl's heart.
But girls today,
boarding high implementation.
Ask my brother.
I Love ni became evidence.
Each week hit go
sides purchasing center, cafe, puppet.
It is not easy.
It is very expensive.
Siddhu. Smth.
You're going hard.
Wait. Let my conversation with him.
Siddhu. We do not know you much trouble.
It is very expensive.
Shakti, pity he tersepit between love and money.
Abang Puruskar!
- My name is Oscar.
- That's what I call you right ..
- Siddhu ni good slave.
- Both near where?
Various  where my dear Veer,
so is my dear Siddhu.
Brother Oscar, this is my brother.
Good care of their family ni,
no record of a crime.
And he was very cintakan your sister.
Lagipun cafes, Garaj, all property belonging to them as well ni
later.
Silalah agree.
But where my son kind of agree?
- Do not ask what kind.
- Out tu?
Meeting you both dah determined God.
We both?
Lagipun him a thief. You are also a thief.
- Do not be shy, should be proud of him.
- Yes, but...
- Abang !! Setujulah.
- Setujulah.
Please.
Okay!
I agree with the marriage ni.
Front he was dah kinds of Jackie Shroff.
But I have one condition.
- There was not a kid wondering what condition?
- What?
Marriage they will be held in the church.
Are you capable?
All dah agree with Jenny and Siddhu
marriage?
This is good news.
Everyone dah bless them,
but we both when again?
Do not worry Veer.
They will definitely blessing.
Proficient with Siddhu we held parti okay.
Jom conference-yack and raikan.
- Okay.
- Bye.
Sister cakapkan dah ..
Not another relationship with him.
He .. Erm .. Brother ..
Sister that there is a problem with them.
Not me.
And what exactly is the problem tu?
It was not kid sister tell.
I do not understand why brother
too insistent way.
Remove dead mother and father,
Sister turutkan every kemahuan you.
Every desire you.
Brother never asked why.
Sister let you make your own decisions.
Never once asked why.
So today ..
If for the first time ..
Sister blocking your decision ..
There should not be to you come alone?
Well kak.
I'm going to join a conversation sister.
And I would not ask anything.
I promise.
But if not Veer ..
I would thank sesiapa again in life ni.
Ishita.
Pick Veer come tomorrow.
Sister something a conversation with her son.
That is, brother...
Messages with him, come alone.
Thank you Cik Pogo.
Cik Puan.
Sorry.
If you hear agree,
brother very happy.
But you have to agree with my request.
Beres. Whatever you ask.
If formaliti participate, contact sister asked first.
But suppose bereslah.
Release kahwin, you hit live here.
If you mahu continue a relationship with Ishita ..
You taxable disconnect with your brother.
What capably brother ni?
You kidding me into?
Ishu. This one "issue" great.
Cik Meera told me to leave my brother.
I really cintakan you.
But he's not just a brother.
Mother, father, friend,
he is everything to me.
Whole life, he's just think about my happiness.
And he mahu me ..
Sorry shoo ladies.
You did open bisnes restaurant ..
But this is not a system of "home-delivery"
and "take away".
Sorry Ishita.
But nothing is more important than a brother.
You did not.
Veer.
Abang  Where are you glorifying
to be able to leave Ishita?
He was not your biological brother.
Your father quotes him on the street.
Ishita...
You do not believe?
Go ask him.
Enough!
Veer  Where do you go?
Evenly average  brother find you.
Let's eat.
The food...
Why ni?
I wonder kid brother something.
Ask, what does?
There is something to which
brother hide from me?
What are you capable,
brother did not hide anything from you.
There's nothing to hide brother.
Abang not my biological brother, right?
Who told you?
Sister Ishita.
Why silent brother?
Sworn in my behalf.
Notify me  The real case.
Yes, my brother is not your biological brother.
Infact, brother love you more than siblings.
And yes ..
Abang ni rahsiakan case of you.
But why ..
Abang mahu not lose you.
Sister Ishita layout requirements before kahwin son.
In order for me to leave my brother.
What do you say?
I leave him.
I left Ishita. Leave...
Brother, I'll meet someone else.
But I would first check ..
That he no brother.
Make sure you check out.
Perhaps there is a problem with the brother sister
all the pretty girls.
You continue to say do not agree?
Very dear brother to you on?
Why stand there, let
here.
Release me.
What you real son?
Huh ??
What are you son achieve?
Brother and sister against each other?
Hospital to?
Just by thinking alone
you pain?
Think  So what I think.
If you kill my father.
- There's what you think I think?
- I did not kill your father.
You're lying.
It's true. Correct.
See my eyes...
I swear on my brother,
I did not kill your father.
Just look into my eyes Meera.
This is the truth.
We cheated Meera ..
We cheated ..
And if you still do not believe ..
This is it. Finish the story we are now.
Shoot me Meera.
Shoot!
With close range like this,
I would not survive.
Shoot.
Mr. Malik that you circumvention Meera.
All competent Kaali is true.
Raghav, you two make me ..
Why do not you tell me?
Takkan my son opponent landing Mr. Malik.
And I would not have the heart to tell a child
nak ..
What her father did dah.
You do not know what you dah make.
You do not know...
You are very regrettable your brother, right?
Yes.
And Ishita too?
So you kahwinlah with him ..
And lived here.
Together with your brother.
- What?
- I mean...
I'm not going to be single until old age?
I was allowed kahwin too?
I...
Veer?
I mean, you son drink tea?
Do not drink tea je.
I propose we all ..
The morning breakfast before turning.
Ishita. Jom kitchen to make tea.
Jom jom!
Abang. Why stand alone?
Pogo Cik first came here.
Abang bring him look Garaj, home, sofa...
- Gorgeous home.
- Yes.
Thank you.
It Garaj us.
We create custom train, they form,
stailing...
Fiber, and all kinds of work.
You had always liked the train, right?
It Anwar and Shakti.
You remember them do not you?
Now they go to cafes.
Until now still permissiveness.
Raghav and tell everything to me,
You're still the same kind of first.
There's only janggutlah Lama.
Actually, you are not changed.
- Maybe I dah sikitlah fat.
- Yes yes, Lama...
I do not intend kinds tu.
You look okay.
- Same as what is worth.
- Yes to?
There are other sikitlah.
Sorry.
15 years dah passed Kaali.
15 years, 4 months,
10 days.
Courant Garaj the next there is a...
For kejuruteraan Courant, AutoCAD...
... And others again.
I'm sorry.
I'm really sorry.
What I seem,
I assume that's the truth.
I do not give you an opportunity to explain.
I do not trust you.
I tell my son everything Meera.
But you dah relieving themselves.
And I...
I came here.
Let's forget all this.
We no longer need toleh back.
But everything I am mistaken, right?
I...
Not one of you.
Not my fault too.
This is all wrong circumstances.
- Meera ..
- I kid ably something with you...
Good morning, Raj!
Day marriage dah close, many boy
make.
Come with me and we mulakan...
- I need your help.
- Nak where?
I nak create guest list.
Because if I were senaraikan ..
Majlis filled with thieves,
headlong become.
That is why ..
Raj? Who is this?
- Your wife?
- No, no.
There is none. You was not married right.
- Girlfriend?
- Not. Not. Not.
There is not none. Your lady friend was not there.
- Tot tot tot tot tot.
- What his tot tot?
Drum sound marriage.
This Release your turn anyway.
Do not. What are you capable ni?
Why ni?
Jom.
Let us talk there.
Oh yes. My Oscar.
- May entertained -
CahayaRiang
Thank you Cik Pogo.
For you, I will marry.
I do not do anything else.
Because love,
Therefore you can kahwin.
So why not kahwin-kahwin brother?
There is no reason whatsoever.
I did not know.
But may I tell you something?
Period  I came here with Siddhu make reservations.
I have heard the great news.
If for two simultaneous marriage majlis ..
They gave half the price.
Jewelry, food, equipment,
all at half price.
Very interesting.
But be not to know me ..
My face  ni there seems kind ..
Stingy to ??
There is none. Not mean sorts tu.
For someone who is the elder brother ..
More beautiful when you live with.
Just look.
Two-two seem happy.
Yes, they are happy.
And a few more days of marriage Ishita and Veer.
- You will certainly miss Ishita.
- Very.
You should come meet Ishita always that kid.
And if you son...
I can come pick you up.
And, you may have dinner with us.
I dah great cook now.
- Yes to?
- Yes, it is true.
Taxi. Railway. Solemn accompaniment.
All of nothing.
Wow.
Every day shuttle, carrying forth,
shuttle, carrying forth...
Nak Ishita conference days,
seems I hit the road looking for another.
Actually, I have one street...
What is she?
Tomorrow you give me five minutes of contact with your past.
Will I Think and tell you.
This is my train !!
Open Bonet quickly.
Joshua.
Man who called
where this train is a train him?
Sir.
Mr. ably earlier.
Go !! Find the tu and bring it here.
Welcome.
Here families Oscar.
Son brought me to where?
Advise really, what is it?
When I asked the train who,
he replied he had.
Yes, why?
If the dog will die ..
Mr she would say,
"Death to you."
Not original direct!
That dialogue Karan Arjun!
Maybe you do not know who I am?
- Who are you?
- King !!
Out  make my son a credit card?
This train...
Do not touch the kid occasional train.
It's not for sale.
Oscar did not deal with people who are not recognized.
Lagipun face you seem kind of bad guy.
I'm sorry.
It's not my fault.
Mani who steal and sell it to me.
If a dog dies ..
Then the eyes of a child
neighbor will initially looked at the young widow.
What is the master say?
Children neighbor. Young widow.
Message what...
Where is everyone?
Hello? 1 2 3 4?
Widow? Child?
I am here Mani.
Cumanya you my left view right view.
Mani?
It is worth millions kror bye.
Veer who took it.
Where she lies I do not know.
You ask him if the boy knew jawapannya.
Hello !!!
Bring Veer here.
What all ni King?
Why call me here?
Because if a dog dies...
Joshua. I dah run out of ideas.
You got another idea?
In me there is about a cat.
Brother Mani? Brother Oscar?
Why is a right view of a more left?
You get angry with each other to?
Not angry! But punished.
Do not play games, kid
if not chastened.
Simply  King. You dah transgressors.
Beyond the limits?
Kerana bataslah, first college period, Rekha ..
It enabled me hold her hand.
King. Everyone with you.
King. Do not emotion.
What you dah make with my medicine Veer?
- Whatever, you can not reverse your medicine.
- You mean?
The fire that warms your hands that day ..
That medicine you are burned.
I dah day that's asked.
There is nothing in the wagon?
Hello ?? 1 2 3 4?
You all dah crazy to?
That medicine which is worth millions kror.
Veer. Veer.
Kaali !!!
We dah know the real story kak.
Abang dah tell me everything.
Brother do not worry.
True brother. And one brother.
Sister left brother right?
For money, of artisan dobi
mafia brother so named Kaali.
Sister afraid brother gave a bad influence on Veer, because it's...
Cik Pogo resting yes.
Nak not juice? I go traded.
WinCE again I come back.
Jom Ishu!
Why not tell them the case, True?
Because I did not tell my son.
What Meera boondoggle?
Hostility your father and my father.
They kill each other.
Why?
In fact, we are all subject to mulakan new life.
And nobody will sesiapa toleh backwards again.
But why say I am right and you are wrong?
Actually...
Dilwale
Re-Sync & Edit
Tharindu_Lakmal_Jeewantha
www.moviesubtitles.org