Life's not fair, is it?
You see I -- well,
I... shall never be King.
And you...
shall never see the light of another day. ... Adieu...
Didn't your mother ever tell you not to play with your food?
What do you want?
I'm here to announce that King Mufasa is on his way.
So you'd better have a good excuse
for missing the ceremony this morning.
Oh now look, Zazu. You've made me lose my lunch.
Hah! You'll lose more than that when
the King gets through with you.
He's as mad as a hippo with a hernia.
Ohhh... I quiver with FEAR.
Now Scar, don't look at me that way...
HELP!!!!
Scar!
Mm-hmm...?
Drop him.
Impeccable timing, your majesty.
Eyyccch.
Why! If it isn't my big brother descending
from on high to mingle with the commoners.
Sarabi and I didn't see you at the presentation of Simba.
That was today? Oh, I feel simply awful.
...Must have slipped my mind.
Yes, well, as slippery as your mind is,
as the king's brother,
you should have been first in line!
Well, I was first in line, ... until the little hairball was born.
"That ""hairball"" is my son -and your future king."
Ohh, I shall practice my curtsy.
Don't turn your back on me, Scar.
On, no, Mufasa. Perhaps you shouldn't turn your back on me.
Is that a challenge?
Temper, temper. I wouldn't dream of challenging you.
Pity! Why not?
Well, as far as brains go, I got the lion's share.
But, when it comes to brute strength ...
I'm afraid I'm at the shallow end of the gene pool.
There's one in every family sire...
Two in mine actually. And they always manage to ruin special occasions.
What am I going to do with him?
He'd make a very handsome throw rug.
Zazu!
And just think! Whenever he gets dirty,
you could take him out and beat him.
Hmmm... Ah heh heh heh heh heh...
Simba
Hmmm... Ah heh heh heh heh heh.
Dad! Daad!  Come on, Dad, we gotta go, wake up!
Oomph!
Sorry!
Dad? Daad. Dad, ...
Your son.... is awake....
Dad, Dad, Dad, Dad, Dad, Dad, Dad...
Before sunrise, he's your son.
Dad? Daad! Come on, Dad! Daa- Whoa!
You promised!
Okay, okay. I'm up. I'm up.
Yeah!
Look Simba. Everything the light touches is our kingdom.
Wow.
A king's time as ruler rises and falls like the sun.
One day Simba, the sun will set on my time here
and will rise with you as the new king.
And this'll all be mine?
Everything.
Everything the light touches...What about that shadowy place?
"That's beyond our borders; you must never go there, Simba."
But I thought a king can do whatever he wants.
Oh, there's more to being king than-- getting your way all the time.
There's more?
Simba.
Everything you see exists together, in a delicate balance.
As king, you need to understand that balance,
and respect all the creatures
from the crawling ant to the leaping antelope.
But, Dad, don't we eat the antelope?
Yes, Simba, but let me explain.
When we die,our bodies become the grass.
And the antelope eat the grass.
And so, we are all connected in the great Circle of Life.
Good morning, sire!
Good morning, Zazu.
Checking in... with the morning report.
Fire away.
Well! The buzz from the bees is that
the leopards are in a bit of a spot ...
Oh, really?
And the baboons are going ape over this.
What are you doing, son?
- What are you doing, son?
- Of course, the giraffes are acting like they're above it all....
- Pouncing.
- Let an old pro show you how it's done.
- The tick birds are pecking on the elephants.
I told the elephants to forget it, but they can't ...
Zazu, would you turn around?
Yes, sire.The Cheetahs are hard up, but as I always say ...
Stay low to the ground.
Cheetahs never prosper...
Okay, stay low to the ground, right yeah ...
What's going on?
A pouncing lesson.
Oh very good. Pouncing.
Pouncing!?!
Oh no, sire, you can't be serious ...
Oh, ... this is so humiliating.
Try not to make a sound.
What are you telling him Mufasa? Mufasa? ...Simba?
Ha ha ha ha ha. That's very good. Ha ha ha...
Zazu.
Yes?
Sir. News from the underground.
Now, this time--
Sire! Hyenas!! In the Pride Lands!
Zazu, take Simba home.
Oh Dad, can't I come?
No, son.
I never get to go anywhere.
"Oh young master, one day you will be king;"
then you can chase those slobbering, mangy,
stupid poachers from dawn until dusk.
Hey Uncle Scar, guess what!
I despise guessing games.
I'm going to be king of Pride Rock.
Oh goodee.
My Dad just showed me the whole kingdom,
and I'm going to rule it all. Heh heh.
Yes. Well... forgive me for not leaping for joy....
Bad back, you know.
Hey, Uncle Scar? When I'm king, what will that make you?
A monkey's uncle.
Heh heh. You're so weird.
You have no idea. ...
So, your father showed you the whole kingdom, did he?
Everything.
He didn't show you what's beyond
that rise at the northern border...?
Well, no... he said I can't go there.
And he's absolutely right!
It's far too dangerous. Only the bravest lions go there.
Well, I'm brave! What's out th--
"No, I'm sorry Simba; I just can't tell you."
Why not?
"Simba, Simba; I'm only looking out for
the well-being of my favorite nephew."
"Yeah, right; I'm your only nephew."
All the more reason for me to be protective...
An elephant graveyard is no place for a young prince ... Oops!
An elephant what? Whoa!
Oh dear, I've said too much....
Well, I suppose you'd have found out sooner or later,
you being so clever and all....
Oh, just do me one favor--
Promise me you'll never visit that dreadful place.
No problem.
There's a good lad. You run along now and have fun.
And remember... it's our little secret.
Hey, Nala.
Hi, Simba.
Come on. I just heard about this great place.
Simba! I'm kind of in the middle of a bath.
And it's time for yours.
Mom! ... Mom. You're messing up my mane.
"Okay, okay; I'm clean. Can we go now?"
So where are we going? It better not be anyplace dumb.
No. It's really cool.
"So where is this ""really cool"" place?"
Oh.... uh ... around the water hole.
The water hole?! What's so great about the water hole?
I'll show you when we get there.
Oh....  Uh.... Mom, can I go with Simba?
Hmm... What do you think, Sarabi?
Well...
Pleeeease?
It's all right with me....
All right!
...As long as Zazu goes with you.
No! Not Zazu.
Step lively. The sooner we get to the water hole, the sooner we can leave.
So where're we really going?
An elephant graveyard.
Wow!
Shhh! Zazu.
Right. So how are we gonna ditch the dodo?
Oh I know how we can--
Oh, just look at you two.
Little seeds of romance blossoming in the savannah.
Your parents will be thrilled...
what with your being betrothed and all.
Be-what?
Betrothed. Intended. Affianced.
Meaning...?
One day you two are going to be married!
Yuck!
Ewww!
I can't marry her. She's my friend.
Yeah. It'd be too weird.
Well, sorry to bust your bubble, but you two turtle doves have no choice. It's a tradition...
...going back generations.
Well when I'm king, that'll be the first thing to go.
Not so long as I'm around.
Well in that case, you're fired.
Hmmm.... Nice try, but only the king can do that.
Well, He's the future king.
Yeah.So you have to do what I tell you.
Not yet I don't. And with an attitude like that,
I'm afraid you're shaping up to be a pretty pathetic king indeed.
Hmph. Not the way I see it.
I'm gonna be a mighty king. So enemies beware!
Well, I've never seen a king of beasts...  With quite so little hair
I'm gonna be the mane event
Like no king was before
I'm brushing up on looking down
I'm working on my ROAR!!
Thus far, a rather uninspiring thing
Oh, I just can't wait to be king!
You've rather a long way to go, young master, if you think....
No one saying do this
No one saying be there
No one saying stop that
No one saying see here
Free to run around all day
Free to do it all my way!
I think it's time that you and I. Arranged a heart to heart
Kings don't need advice
From little hornbills for a start
If this is where the monarchy is headed
Count me out!
Out of service, out of Africa I wouldn't hang about ... aaagh!
This child is getting wildly out of wing
Oh I just can't wait to be king!
Everybody look left
Everybody look right
Everywhere you look I'm
Standing in the spotlight
Let every creature go for broke and sing
Let's hear it in the herd and on the wing
It's gonna be King Simba's finest fling
Oh I just can't wait to be king!
Oh I just can't waaaaaait ... to be kiiiiiiiiiing!
I beg your pardon, madam, but ... GET OFF!... Simba? Nala?
All right, it worked!
We lost 'im.
I ... am a genius.
Hey, Genius, it was my idea.
Yeah, but I pulled it off.
With me!
Oh yeah?... Rrarr!!
Ha. Pinned ya.
Hey, lemme up.
Pinned ya again.
This is it.... We made it.
Whoa!
It's really creepy.
Yeah... isn't it great?
We could get in big trouble.
I know, huh.
I wonder if its brains are still in there.
There's only one way to know. Come on. Let's go check it out.
The only checking out you will do will be to check out of here.
Aw, man.
We're way beyond the boundary of the Pride Lands.
Huh. Look, banana beak is scared. Heh.
That's Mister Banana Beak to you, fuzzy.
And right now we are all in very real danger.
Danger? Hah! I walk on the wild side.
I laugh in the face of danger. Ha ha ha ha!
Well, well, well, Banzai. What have we got here?
Hmm. I don't know Shenzi. Uh... What do you think, Ed?
Yeah, just what I was thinking. A trio of trespassers!!
And quite by accident, let me assure you.
A simple navigational error. Eh heh heh...
Whoa, whoa, wait wait wait.... I know you.
You're Mufasa's little stooge.
I, madam, am the king's majordomo.
And that would make you...?
The future king.
Do you know what we do to kings who step out of their kingdom?
Puh. You can't do anything to me.
Uhh.... Technically, they can. We are on their land.
But Zazu, you told me they're nothing
but slobbering mangy stupid poachers.
Ix-nay on the oopid-stay...
"Who you callin' ""oopid-stay?!?"""
My, my, my. Look at the sun. It's time to go!
What's the hurry?  We'd love you to stick around for dinner.
Yeaaaah! We could have whatever's ... lion around!
Get it? Lion around!
Oh wait, wait, wait. I got one, I got one.
Make mine a cub sandwich. Whatcha think?
What? Ed? What is it?
Hey, did we order this dinner to go?
No. Why?
'Cause there it goes!!
Did we lose 'em?
I think so.... Where's Zazu?
The little Majordomo bird hippity-hopped
all the way to the birdie-boiler.
Oh no.... Not the birdie boiler! Aaaaaaaa...!
Hey! Why don't you pick on somebody your own size?
Like ... you?
Oops!
Boo!
Simba!
Aaaaiee!
Here kitty, kitty, kitty.
Oo-hoo... That was it? Hah. Do it again.... come on.
Huh?!
Oh, Please, please. Uncle. Uncle.
Ow. Ow. Ow.
Silence!
Oh, we're gonna shut up right now.
Calm down. We're really sorry.
If you ever come near my son again...
Oh this is ... this is your son?!?
Oh your son??
Did you know that?
No.... Me? I-I-I didn't know it. No. Did you?
No! Of course not.
No! Ed?
Toodles!
Dad, I ..
You deliberately disobeyed me.
Dad, I'm.... I'm sorry.
Let's go home.
I thought you were very brave.
Zazu?
Yes, sire?
Take Nala home. I've got to teach my son a lesson.
Come, Nala. Simba... Good luck.
Simba!
Simba, I'm very disappointed in you.
I know.
You could have been killed. You deliberately disobeyed me.
And what's worse,- you put Nala in danger!
I was just trying to be brave like you.
I'm only brave when I have to be.
Simba ... being brave doesn't mean you go looking for trouble.
But you're not scared of anything.
I was today.
You were?
Yes ... I thought I might lose you.
Oh. I guess even kings get scared, huh?
Mm-hmm.
But you know what?
What?
I think those hyenas were even scareder.
Cause nobody messes with your dad.  Come here, you.
Oh no, no ... Aaagh! Errrggh! ...
Oh, come here... Hah! Gotcha!
Dad?
Hmm?
We're pals, right?
Right.
And we'll always be together, right?
Simba, ... Let me tell you something that my father told me ... Look at the stars.
The great kings of the past look down on us from those stars.
Really?
Yes ... So whenever you feel alone,
just remember that those kings will always be there to guide you
... And so will I.
Man that lousy Mufasa! I won't be able to sit for a week.
It's not funny, Ed.
Hey, shut up!
Will you knock it off!
Well, he started it.
Look at you guys. No wonder we're dangling at the bottom of the food chain.
Man, I hate dangling.
Shyeah?  You know, if it weren't for those lions, we'd be runnin' the joint.
Yeah. Man, I hate lions.
So pushy.   And hairy.    And stinky.
And man are they ...
Uuug-LEE!
Oh, surely we lions are not all that bad.
Ohh. Oh Scar, it's just you.
We were afraid it was somebody important.
Yeah, you know, like Mufasa.
Yeah.
I see.
Now that's power.
Tell me about it. I just hear that name and I shudder.
Mufasa.
Ooooh. ... Do it again.
Ooooh.
Mufasa. Mufasa! Mufasa!
Oooh! It tingles me.
I'm surrounded by idiots.
Not you Scar, I mean, you're one of us. I mean, you're our pal.
Charmed.
Ohh, I like that. He's not king, but he's still so proper.
Yeah. Hey, hey hey. Did ya bring us anything to eat,
Scar, old buddy, old pal? Huh? Did-ya-did-ya-did-ya?
I don't think you really deserve this.
I practically gift wrapped those cubs for you.
And you couldn't even dispose of them.
Well, ya know
it wasn't exactly like they was alone, Scar.
Yeah. What are we supposed to do?... Kill Mufasa?
Precisely.
I know that your powers of retention
Are as wet as a warthog's backside
But thick as you are, pay attention
My words are a matter of pride
It's clear from your vacant expressions
The lights are not all on upstairs
But we're talking kings and successions
Even you can't be caught unawares
So prepare for the chance of a lifetime
Be prepared for sensational news
A shining new era
Is tiptoeing nearer
And where do we feature?
Just listen to teacher
I know it sounds sordid
But you'll be rewarded
When at last I am given my dues!
And injustice deliciously squared
Be prepared!
Yeah, be prepared.  Yeah-heh.  We'll be prepared, heh ... For what?
For the death of the king.
Why? Is he sick?
No fool, we're going to kill him. And Simba too.
Great idea! Who needs a king?
No king! No king! la--la-la--la-laa-laa!
IDIOTS! There will be a king!
Hey, but you said, uh...
I WILL BE KING! Stick with me, and you'll never go hungry again!
Yaay! All right! Long live the king!
Long live the king! Long live the king!
It's great that we'll soon be connected.
With a king who'll be all-time adored.
Of course, quid pro quo, you're expected
To take certain duties on board
The future is littered with prizes
And though I'm the main addressee
The point that I must emphasize is
You won't get a sniff without me!
So prepare for the coup of the century
Be prepared for the murkiest scam
Meticulous planning
Tenacity spanning
Decades of denial
Is simply why I'll  be king undisputed
Respected, saluted
And seen for the wonder I am
Yes, my teeth and ambitions are bared
Be prepared!
Yes, our teeth and ambitions are bared
Now you wait here. Your father has a marvelous surprise for you.
Ooooh.  What is it?
If I told you, it wouldn't be a surprise, now would it?
If you tell me, I'll still act surprised.
Ho ho ho
You are such a naughty boy!
Come on, Uncle Scar.
This is just for you and your daddy
You know, a sort of father-son ... thing....
Well! I'd better go get him.
I'll go with you.
No! Heh heh heh. No. Just ... stay on this rock.
You wouldn't want to end up in another mess
like you did with the hyenas...
You know about that?
Simba, everybody knows about that.
Really?
Oh, yes. Lucky Daddy was there to save you, eh?
Oh, and just between us, you might
want to work on that little roar of yours, hmm?
Oh, okay ...
Hey, Uncle Scar? ...Will I like the surprise?
Simba, it's to DIE for.
Shut up.
I can't help it. I'm so hungry ...
I gotta have a wildebeest!
Stay put.
Well can't I just pick off one of the little sick ones?
No! We wait for the signal from Scar.
There he is
Let's go.
Little roar. Puh!
Rarrr!
Rrrraowr-nh.
RAOWR!!
"Oh look, sire; The herd is on the move.
Odd...."
Mufasa. Quick. Stampede. In the gorge. Simba's down there!
Simba?
Zazu!
Help me!
Your father is on the way!  Hold on!
Hurry!
There! There! On that tree!
Hold on, Simba!!
Ahhhh!!!
Oh, Scar, this is awful!  What'll we do what'll we do?!
Hah ... I'll go back for help, that's what
I'll do, I'll go back for he-- oomph!
Scar! ... Broth--  Brother ... Help me!
Long  live  the  king!
Aaaaaaahh!
NOOOOOOOO!
Daaad!!
Dad?
Dad? ...Dad, come on. You gotta get up.
Dad.We gotta go home.
HEEEEELP!
Somebody! Anybody... help.
Simba. ... What have you done?
There were wilde beest and he tried to save me
It was an accident, I didn't mean for it to happen.
Of course, of course, you didn't.
No one ever means for these things to happen.... But the king is dead.
And if it weren't for you, he'd still be alive.
Oh!  What will your mother think?
What am I gonna do?
Run away, Simba.... Run....  Run away, and never return.
Kill him.
Whoa!!
Yeooow!
Hey-- There he goes! There he goes!
So go get 'im.
There ain't no way I'm going in there. What you want me
to come out looking like you? Cactus Butt?
But we gotta finish the job.
Well, he's as good as dead out there anyway.
And if he comes back, we'll kill him.
Yeah! you hear that?  If you ever come back, we'll kill ya!
"Mufasa's death was a terrible tragedy; but to lose Simba ..."
who had barely begun to live....
For me, it is a deep personal loss.
And so it is with a heavy heart that I assume the throne.
Yet, out of the ashes of this tragedy,
we shall rise to greet the dawning of a new era
in which lion and hyena come together,
in a great and glorious future.
Heeyyyaaaahh!! Get out!  Get out!  Get outta here!!!!  Whoo!
I love it! Bowling for buzzards!
Gets 'em every time.
Uh-oh. Hey Timon. You better come look.
I think it's still alive.
Yeewgh!...
All righty, what have we got here?
Jeez, it's a lion! Run Pumbaa! Move it!
Hey, Timon. It's just a little lion. Look at him.
He's so cute, and all alone! Can we keep him?
Pumbaa, are you nuts?!  We're talking about a lion.
Lions eat guys like us.
But he's so little.
He's gonna get bigger.
Maybe he'll be on our side.
A--Huh! That's the stupidest thing I ever heard. Maybe he'll b--
Hey, I got it! What if he's on our side?
You know, having a lion around might not be such a bad idea.
So we keeping 'im?
Pthpt. Of course. Who's the brains in this outfit?
Uhhh....
My point exactly. Jeez, I'm fried.
Let's get out of here and find some shade.
You okay, kid?
I guess so.
You nearly died.
I saved you.
Well, uh, Pumbaa helped...a little.
Thanks for your help.
Hey, where you going?
Nowhere.
Gee. He looks blue.
I'd say brownish-gold.
No, no, no, no. I mean he's depressed.
Kid, what's eatin' ya?
Nothing-- he's at the top of the food chain!
The food cha-haain! Ah heh-- Ahem.
So, where you from?
Who cares? I can't go back.
"Ahh. You're an outcast! That's great; so are we!"
What'cha do, kid?
Something terrible. But I don't wanna talk about it.
Good. We don't wanna hear about it.
Come on Timon. Anything we can do?
Not unless you can change the past.
"You know, kid, in times like this my buddy Timon here says
""You got to put your behind in your past."""
No. No. No.
I mean...
"Amateur. Lie down before you hurt yourself.
It's ""You got to put your past behind you."""
Look, kid. Bad things happen, and you can't do anything about it, right?
Right.
Wrong!  When the world turns its back on you,
you turn your back on the world!
Well, that's not what I was taught.
Then maybe you need a new lesson.
Repeat after me. Hakuna Matata.
What?
Ha-ku-na Ma-ta-ta. It means no worries.
Hakuna Matata!
What a wonderful phrase
Ain't no passing craze
It means no worries for the rest of your days
It's our problem-free philosophy
Hakuna Matata!
Hakuna Matata?
Yeah, it's our motto.
What's a motto?
Nothing! What's a motto with you? Ah haah haah hah hah...
You know, kid-- these two words will solve all your problems.
That's right! Take Pumbaa for example.
Why, when he was a young wart-hog
When I was a young wart hooog!
Very nice.
Thanks!
He found his aroma lacked a certain appeal
He could clear the Savannah after every meal
I'm a sensitive soul though I seem thick-skinned
And it hurt that my friends never stood downwind
And oh, the shame
He was ashamed
Thoughta changin' my name
Oh, what's in a name
And I got downhearted
How did you feel
Ev'rytime that I...
Hey, Pumbaa! Not in front of the kids!
Oh.  Sorry.
Hakuna Matata!
What a wonderful phrase
Ain't no passing craze
It means no worries
For the rest of your days
Yeah, sing it, kid!
It's our problem-free philosophy.
Hakuna Matata!
Welcome to our humble home.
You live here?
We live wherever we want.
Yep. Home is where your rump rests. Heh!
It's beautiful.
I'm starved!
I'm so hungry I could eat a whole zebra.
Eeeahhah. We're fresh out of zebra.
- Any antelope?
- Na ah.
- Hippo?
- No
Listen kid, if want to live with us, you have to eat like us
Hey, this looks like a good spot to rustle up some grub
- What's that?
A grub, what's it look like?
Ooh, Gross!
It tastes like chicken
Slimy yet satisfying!
These are rare delicacies. Hmm. Piquant with a very pleasant
crunch.
You'll learn to love them!
I'm telling you kid, this is the great life.
No rules, no responsibility.
ooh, the little cream filled kind... and best of all, no worries! Well kid!
Oh, well...
Hakuna Matata!
Slimy, yet satisfying.
That's it!
Hakuna Matata
It means no worries
For the rest of your days
It's our problem-free philosophy
Hakuna Matata!
Nobody knows
The trouble I see...
My sorrow...
Oh Zazu, do lighten up.
Sing something with a little bounce in it.
It's a small world after all
No! No. Anything but that!
I've got a lovely bunch of coconuts
There they are a-standing in a row.
Big ones, small ones, some as big as your head
Oh I would never have had to do this for Mufasa.
What? What did you say?
Oh, nothing!
You know the law: Never, ever mention that name in my presence.
I ... am ... the king!
Yes, sire. You are the king. I, I,  Well,
Well I only mentioned it to illustrate the differences
in your royal managerial approaches.
Hey, Boss!
Oh, What is it this time?
We got a bone to pick with you.
I'll handle this. Scar, there's no food, no water.
Yeah, it's dinner time, and we ain't got no stinkin' entrees.
It's the lionesses' job to do the hunting
Yeah, but they won't go hunt.
Oh, eat Zazu.
Oh, you wouldn't want me. I'd be so tough and gamey and- eewwgh!
Oh, Zazu, don't be ridiculous!
All you need is a little garnish.
I thought things were bad under Mufasa...
What did you say?
I said Muf--
"I said, uh ... ""Qué pasa?"""
Good. Now get out.
Mm, yeah, but-- we're still hungry.
Out!
Whoah. Nice one, Simba.
Thanks. Man, I'm stuffed.
Me too. I ate like a pig!
Pumbaa-- you are a pig.
Oh. Right.
Timon?
Yeah?
Ever wonder what those sparkly dots are up there?
"Pumbaa. I don't wonder; I know."
Oh! ...What are they?
They're fireflies. Fireflies that uh, got stuck up
on that big, bluish-black, thing.
Oh. Gee. I always thought that they were
balls of gas burning billions of miles away.
Pumbaa, wit' you, everything's gas.
Simba, what do you think?
Well, I don't know
Aw come on. Give, give, give ..
Well, come on, Simba, we told you ours... pleeeease?
Well, somebody once told me that the great kings
of the past are up there watching over us.
Really?
You mean a bunch of royal dead guys are watching us?Pbbb.
Who told you something like that? What mook made that up?
Yeah. Pretty dumb, huh?
Ah, you're killing me, Simba.
Was it something I said?
Simba? He's- he's alive? He he- He's alive!!
It is time!
Ohi'mbube
In the jungle
The mighty jungle
The lion sleeps tonight.
In the jungle
The mighty jungle
The lion sleeps to--
I can't hear ya, buddy, back me up!
A-weee-ee-ee-ee aa-Pum-ba-bum-ba-waaay...
A-Pumbaa? Pumbaa?
Timon?
HYEEEEAAAHHH!!!!!
Pumbaa?
Pumbaa? What's going on?
SHE'S GONNA EAT ME!!
Huh?
Whoah!! ... Jeez! Why do I always have to save your AAAAAA!!
"Don't worry, buddy; I'm here for you. Everything's gonna be okay."
Get her! Bite her head! Go for the jugular. The jugular!
See, I told you he'd come in handy.
Nala?
Is it really you?
Who are you?
It's me. Simba.
Simba?  Whoah!!!
Well how did you.. where did you come from ... it's great to see you..
Aaaah! how did you... who... wow... this is cool... it's great to see you.
Hey, what's goin' on here?
What are you doing here?
"What do you mean,
""What am I doing here?"" What are you doing here?"
HEY!! WHAT'S GOIN' ON HERE?!?
"Timon, this is Nala; she's my best friend!"
Friend?!?
Yeah. Hey, Pumbaa! Come over here.
Nala, this is Pumbaa. Pumbaa, Nala.
Pleased to make your acquaintance.
The pleasure's all mine.
How do you do.. Whoa! Whoa. Time out... Let me get this straight.
You know her. She knows you. But she wants to eat him.
And, everybody's okay with this?
DID I MISS SOMETHING?!
Relax, Timon.
Wait 'til everybody finds out you've been here all this time.
And your mother what will she think?
She doesn't have to know. Nobody has to know.
Well, of course they do. Everyone thinks you're dead.
They do?
Yeah. Scar told us about the stampede.
He did? What else did he tell you?
What else matters? You're alive.  And that means... you're the king!
King? Pbbb. Lady, have you got your lions crossed.
King? Your Majesty! I gravel at your feet.
Stop it.
"It's not ""gravel,"" it's ""grovel."" And don't; he's not the king. Are ya?"
No.
Simba!
No, I'm not the king. Maybe I was gonna be.
But, that was a long time ago.
Let me get this straight. You're the king?
And you never told us?
Look, I'm still the same guy.
But with power!
Could you guys ... excuse us for a few minutes?
Hey, whatever she has to say, she can say in front of us. Right, Simba?
Hmm.... Maybe you'd better go .
It starts. You think you know a guy.....
Timon and Pumbaa. You learn to love 'em.
What?  What is it?
It's like you're back from the dead.
You don't know how much this will mean to everyone.
What it means to me.
" Hey; it's OK."
I've really missed you.
I've missed you too.
I tell ya, Pumbaa.  This stinks.
Oh.  Sorry.
Not you. Them! Him. Her. Alone...
What's wrong with that?
I can see what's happening
What?
And they don't have a clue
Who?
They'll fall in love and here's the bottom line
Our trio's down to two.Oh...
Ze sweet caress of twilight
There's magic everywhere
And with all this romantic atmosphere
Disaster's in the air
Can you feel the love tonight?
The peace the evening brings
The world, for once, in perfect harmony
With all its living things
So many things to tell her
But how to make her see
The truth about my past? Impossible!
She'd turn away from me
He's holding back, he's hiding
But what, I can't decide
Why won't he be the king I know he is
The king I see inside?
Can you feel the love tonight?
The peace the evening brings
The world, for once, in perfect harmony
With all its living things
Can you feel the love tonight?
You needn't look too far
Stealing through the night's uncertainties
Love is where they are.
And if he falls in love tonight
It can be assumed
His carefree days with us are history
In short, our pal is doomed
Isn't this a great place?
It is beautiful.... But I don't understand something.
You've been alive all this time.
Why didn't you come back to Pride Rock?
Well, I just ... needed to get out on my own.
Live my own life. And I did. And it's great!
We've really needed you at home.
No one needs me.
Yes we do! You're the king.
Nala, we've been through this. I'm not the king.  Scar is.
Simba, he let the hyenas take over the Pride Lands.
What?
Everything's destroyed. There's no food, no water.
Simba, if you don't do something soon, everyone will starve.
I can't go back.
Why?
You wouldn't understand.
What wouldn't I understand?
No, no, no. It doesn't matter. Hakuna Matata.
What?
Hakuna Matata. It's something I learned out here.
Look, sometimes bad things happen
Simba!
...and there's nothing you can do about it! So why worry?
Because it's your responsibility.
Well, what about you? you left.
I left to find help! And I found you.
Don't you understand? You're our only hope.
Sorry.
What's happened to you? You're not the Simba I remember.
"You're right; I'm not. Now are you satisfied?"
No, just disappointed.
You know, you're starting to sound like my father.
Good. At least one of us does.
Listen!  You think you can just show up and tell me how to live my life?
You don't even know what I've been through.
I would if you'd just tell me!
Forget it! Fine!
She's wrong. I can't go back. What would it prove, anyway?
It won't change anything. You can't change the past.
You said you'd always be there for me!... But you're not.
And it's because of me. It's my fault.... It's my ... fault.
Come on, will you cut it out?
Can't cut it out. It'll grow right back!
Creepy little monkey. Will you stop following me? Who are you?
The question is: whooo... are you?
I thought I knew.... Now I'm not so sure.
Well, I know who you are. Shh. Come here. It's a secret.
Ernh! Enough already!  ...What's that supposed to mean anyway?
It means you are a baboon-- and I'm not.
I think, you're a little confused.
"Wrong! I'm not the one who's confused;
you don't even know who you are!"
Oh, and I suppose you know.
"Sure do; You're Mufasa's boy!"
Bye!
Hey, wait!
You knew my father?
Correction-- I know your father.
I hate to tell you this, but he died. A long time ago.
Nope. Wrong again! Hah hah hah! He's alive and I'll show him to you.
"You follow old Rafiki; he knows the way. Come on!"
Don't dawdle....  Hurry up!
Hey, whoa. Wait, wait.
Come on.  Come on!
Would you slow down?
STOP!  Shhh. Look down there.
That's not my father. That's just my reflection.
Noo. Look ... harder.
You see ... he lives in you.
Simba . . .
Father?
Simba, you have forgotten me.
No. How could I?
You have forgotten who you are, and so have forgotten me.
Look inside yourself, Simba.
You are more than what you have become.
You must take your place in the Circle of Life.
How can I go back? I'm not who I used to be.
Remember who you are. You are my son, and the one true king.
Remember who you are.
No! Please! Don't leave me.
Remember...
Father!
Don't leave me.
Remember...
What was that? The weather-- Pbbbah!  Very peculiar. Don't you think?
Yeah. Looks like the winds are changing.
Ahhh, change is good.
Yeah, but it's not easy. I know what I have to do.
But, going back means I'll have to face my past.
I've been running from it for so long....Oww! Jeez-- what was that for?
"It doesn't matter; it's in the past!"
Yeah, but it still hurts.
Oh yes, the past can hurt. But the way I see it,
you can either run from it... or ... learn from it.
Hah!  You see?  So what are you going to do?
First... I'm going to take your stick.
No, no, no, no! Not the stick!
Hey!  Where are you going?
I'm going back!
Good! Go on! Get out of here!
Hey. Hey, wake up.
It's OK. Whoa, whoa. It's OK. It's me.
Don't ever do that again! Carnivores, oy!
Have you guys seen Simba?
I thought he was with you.
He was, but now I can't find him. Where is he?
Ho ho ho ho!  You won't find him here.
Ha ha. The king has returned.
I can't believe it. He's gone back!
Gone back? What do you mean? Hey!
What's going on here?  Who's the monkey?!
Simba's gone to challenge Scar.
Who?
Scar.
Who's got a scar?
No, no, no. It's his uncle.
The monkey's his uncle?
No! Simba's gone back to challenge his uncle
to take his place as king.
Ohhh.
Simba, wait up! It's awful, isn't it?
I didn't want to believe you.
What made you come back?
I finally got some sense knocked into me.
And I've got the bump to prove it.
Besides, this is my kingdom.  If I don't fight for it, who will?
I will.
It's going to be dangerous.
Danger? I laugh in the face of danger. Hah ha ha haa!
I see nothing funny about this.
Timon? Pumbaa? What are you doing here?
At your service, my liege.
Uh.. We're going to fight your uncle ... for this?
"Yes, Timon; this is my home."
Phh. Talk about your fixer-upper. Well, Simba,
if it's important to you we're with you to the end.
Live bait.
Good idea. Hey.
Come on, Timon-- you guys have to crate a diversion.
What do you want me to do? Dress in drag and do the hula?
If you're hungry for a hunk of fat and juicy meat
Eat my buddy Pumbaa here because he is a treat
Come on down and dine
On this tasty swine
All you have to do is get in line
Aaaare ya achin'
Yup, yup, yup
Fooor some bacon?
Heee's a big pig
Yup, yup, yup
You could be a big pig too.
Yup, yup
Nala, you find my mother and rally the lionesses.
I'll look for Scar.
SARABIII!
Yes, Scar?
Where is your hunting party?
They're not doing their job.
Scar, there is no food. The herds have moved on.
No. You're just not looking hard enough.
It's over. There is nothing left.
We have only one choice. We must leave Pride Rock.
We're not going anywhere.
Then you have sentenced us to death!
Then so be it.
You can't do that.
I'm the king. I can do... whatever I want.
If you were half the king Mufasa was you would neve--
I'm ten times the king Mufasa was!
Mufasa? No-- you're dead.
Mufasa?
"No; it's me."
Simba? You're alive? How can that be?
"It doesn't matter; I'm home."
Simba? Simba! I'm a little surprised to see you... alive.
Give me one good reason why I shouldn't rip you apart.
Oh, Simba, you must understand. The pressures of ruling a kingdom...
Are no longer yours. Step down, Scar.
Oh, oh, ye-- Well, I would, heh, naturally,
heh-- however, there is one little problem.
You see them? They think I'm king.
Well, we don't. Simba is the rightful king.
The choice is yours, Scar. Either step down or fight.
Oh, must it all end in violence?
I'd hate to be responsible for the death of a family member.
Wouldn't you agree, Simba?
That's not gonna work, Scar.  I've put it behind me.
Eh, but what about your faithful subjects?
Have they put it behind them?
Simba, what is he talking about?
Ahh, so you haven't told them your little secret.
Well, Simba, now's your chance to tell them.
Tell them who is responsible for Mufasa's death!
I am.
It's not true. Tell me it's not true.
It's true.
You see, he admits it! Murderer!
No! It was an accident!
If it weren't for you, Mufasa would still be alive.
It's your fault he's dead.... Do you deny it?
No.
Then ... you're ... guilty!
No. I'm not a murderer.
Oh Simba, you're in trouble again.
But this time, Daddy isn't here to save you.
And now everyone knows why!
Simba!
Now this looks familiar. Hmm.  Where have I seen this before.
Let me think. Hmmm... hmmm. Oh yes, I remember.
This is just the way your father looked before he died.
And here's my little secret.  I killed Mufasa.
NoooooOOO.... MURDERER!
No, Simba please.
Tell them the truth.
Truth? But, truth is in the eye of the beholdllgkkk!
All right. All right. I did it.
So they can hear you.
I ... killed ... Mufasa!
Heyyy-yaaaaah!!
'Scuse me. Pardon me. Comin' through. Hot stuff.  Whoo!
Let me out! Let me out!
Let me in let me in! Pleeease don't eat me.
Problem?
Hey, who's the pig?
Are you talking to me?
- Uh oh. They called him a pig.
Are you talking to me?! - Shouldn't 'a done that.
ARE YOU TALKING TO ME?!?
Now they're in for it.
THEY CALL ME.. MISTER PIIIG! AAAAAAAAAAA--
Take that! And that!
Take that! And that! You yellow belly...
Murderer.
Simba, Simba. Please. Please have mercy. I beg you.
You don't deserve to live.
But, Simba, I am ... ah ... family.
It's the hyenas who are the real enemy.
It was their fault-- it was their idea!
Why should I believe you? Everything you ever told me was a lie.
What are you going to do? You wouldn't kill your old Uncle...?
No, Scar.  I'm not like you.
Oh, Simba, thank you. You are truly noble.
I'll make it up to you, I promise.
How can I, ah, prove myself to you?
Tell me, I mean, anything.
Run. Run away, Scar. And never return.
Yes. Of course....  As you wish, your Majesty!
Ahh, my friends.
Frie-he-hends? I thought he said we were the enemy!
Yeah, that's what I heard.
Ed?
No. L-L-L-Le-Le-Le-Le-Let me explain.
No. You don't understand.
No! I didn't mean for... No, No!
Look, I'm sorry I called you...  No! NOO!
It is time.
Remember . . .
'Til we find our place
On the path unwinding
In the Circle
The Circle of Life
www.moviesubtitles.org