Neighbours heard them
screaming at each other,
like, for two hours.
Then they heard the gun
go off, both barrels.
Crime of passion.
Yeah.
Just look at all
the passion on that wall.
Yeah, well, it's a done deal,
all but the paperwork.
The kid see it?
What?
The kid.
What kind of fucking
question is that?
We are all going to be real glad
when we get rid of you,
Somerset.
It's always these questions.
Who gives a fuck?
He's dead. His wife killed him.
Anything else, it has
nothing to do with us.
Detective Somerset?
I'm Detective Mills.
Lieutenant, I apologise
for interrupting,
but I just get in town
they dump me here.
Look, um... Mills?
I thought we might
find a bar some place.
I'd like to get
to the precinct.
Not much time for
this transition thing.
I meant to ask you something
when we spoke
on the phone before.
Yep.
Why here?
I don't follow.
Well, all this effort
to get transferred.
It's the first question
that popped into my head.
I guess the same reasons as you,
the same reasons you had
before you decided
to quit, yeah?
You just met me.
Maybe I'm not understanding
the question.
It's very simple.
You actually fought
to get reassigned here.
I've just never seen it
done that way before.
I thought I could do some good.
Look. It would be great for me
if we didn't start out
kicking each other in the balls.
But you're calling
the shots, Lieutenant.
Yeah. I want you to look,
and I want you to listen, OK?
I wasn't guarding the Taco Bell.
I've worked homicide five years.
Not here.
I understand that.
Over the next
seven days, Detective,
you'll do me the favour
of remembering that.
You've got me closer to God
Hello.
Yep. OK.
Say it again.
I thought we moved here
to get away from tractor pulls.
Serpico's got to go.
Yeah. Well,
you might want to get rid of
this little crusty.
This eye, Serpico.
Did you get it?
Got it.
Coffee? No?
Nothing's been touched.
Everything's like I found it.
What time
was death established?
Like I said,
I didn't touch anything,
but he's got his face
in a plate of spaghetti
for about 45 minutes now.
No one bothers with vital signs?
Did I stutter?
This guy ain't breathing
unless he started
breathing spaghetti sauce.
So that's how it's done here.
This guy's been
sitting in a pile
of his own piss and shit.
If he wasn't dead,
he would have stood up by now.
Thank you, officer.
Thank you.
I wonder...
What exactly was the point
of the conversation
you were about to get into?
Don't know.
How many times has Barney Fife
found dead bodies
that weren't dead?
Drop it.
Somebody phone Guinness.
I think we've
got a record here.
Better homes and gardens.
Who said this was murder?
No one.
The guy's heart has got to be
the size of a canned ham.
If this isn't a coronary...
Ha ha! Well, I don't know.
Whoops!
How about that?
We had this case once...
Guy dead on the ground,
knife in his back.
Got to be murder, right?
Fuck.
Anyway, big insurance
policy involved, yeah?
The guy took
the tip of the blade,
stuck it in
his own shoulder blades.
He must have screwed up a
few times. There was multiples.
Could you please be quiet?
Wait a minute.
What?
Got a bucket here.
What's in it?
Oh, God!
Fucking vomit.
Any blood in it?
I didn't see any.
Help yourself.
Are you thinking it's poison?
Oh, wonderful.
Very moody.
Are you thinking
it's poison, Somerset?
You girls have got
forensics waiting outside.
I don't know
if we'll all fit, though.
There's room.
Light's the problem.
Detective Mills, would you
go help the officers
question the neighbours?
What?
Send in forensics
on your way out, please.
He's dead.
Thank you, Doctor.
You've seen my files, right?
You've seen
the things I've done.
No.
Well, I did my time
walking the beat.
I did that shit for a long time.
And?
My badge says Detective,
the same as yours.
Look. I made a decision.
I had to consider
the integrity of the scene.
Couldn't worry
whether you thought
you were getting enough time
on the playing field.
Hey, man...
Just don't jerk me off.
That's all I ask.
He's been dead a long time,
and I can tell you
it was not a poison.
Oh, man.
How does someone
let themselves go like that?
Lt took four orderlies
just to get him on the table.
But how'd the fat fuck
ever fit out his front door?
Please. It's obvious
he was a shut-in.
Now look at this.
See how big this stomach is?
And the strange thing is...
Stretches.
Here. Look at the size
of the cardiac orifice
where the food...
I see, but that means
nothing to me.
He's got lines of distension
across the duodenum,
and the interior wall
is ripped open.
This man ate till he burst?
He didn't really burst,
not all the way,
but he was haemorrhaging
internally.
There was a haematoma
in the rectus.
So he did die by eating.
Yes and no.
What about
these bruises up here?
I haven't figured that out yet.
Gun pressed against his head?
Pressed hard enough, sure.
Fuck, yeah.
The marks from the front side
flush with the muzzle.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we have ourselves a homicide.
Killer put a bucket beneath him,
kept on serving.
Coroner said this could have
gone on for more than 12 hours.
Victim's throat was swollen,
probably from the effort,
and there was definitely a point
when he passed out.
The killer kicked him,
and he burst.
Oof! Sadistic fucker, huh?
When you want somebody dead,
you don't risk the time
it takes to do this,
unless the act itself
has meaning.
Come on.
Somebody had a problem
with the fat boy
and decided to torture him.
In the grocery bags,
we found two receipts.
That means the killer
stopped in the middle
and made a second trip
to the supermarket.
So?
Hey, man... It's his thing.
I've been out
in the rain all day.
This is beginning.
We've got one dead guy,
not three.
No motive.
Don't even start
your big brain cooking on this,
all right? Please.
I'd like to be reassigned.
What? Whoa.
What in the hell
are you talking about?
This can't be my last duty.
It's just going
to go on and on.
You're retiring.
Six more days
and you're all the way gone.
Won't be the first time
you've left unfinished business.
Those cases were taken as close
to conclusion as possible,
and if I may speak freely...
This should not be
his first assignment.
I knew it.
This is not
my first assignment, you dick.
It's too soon.
I'm here. You can say
that shit to my face.
It's too soon.
Captain, if we can
just talk in private.
This isn't working.
It's a personal thing.
Shut up, Mills.
Look. I don't have
anyone else to put on this.
This is Metro.
You don't just get to swap.
Give it to me.
Fuck him.
See you later.
Give it to me.
I'm putting you
on something else.
Go on, Mills. Just go on.
I'm sorry, old buddy,
but it looks like you're stuck
cleaning up the fat man.
All right. Here we go.
Quiet down.
All right. Calm down.
Calm down.
Quiet down!
Calm down. Quiet down.
Now, here's how
it's going to be.
I'll answer questions
for 10 minutes.
If those questions do not come
in a calm, sane,
and orderly fashion,
I'm on my way out of here.
Detective.
Can I have
a moment of your time?
I will not discuss the details
of this ongoing investigation.
There he is.
That's the guy.
It looks like
we won't be eating dinner.
Who is this kid,
anyway? Hotshot.
What have you guys got for me?
Nothing yet, boss.
Why don't you guys, uh...
Go get a coffee, OK?
We have
this breaking story for you.
We're going
to go live downtown
where Defence Attorney
Eli Gould
was found murdered
this morning.
District Attorney
Martin Talbot
is taking questions
from reporters.
There's a conflict of interest
between your office...
That is ridiculous to the point
of being offensive.
There is no conflict
whatsoever.
Is it true that you're far
from apprehending a suspect?
I've just come from a meeting
of law enforcement officials,
and they've assured me
they have
their very best men on this.
This will be
the very definition
of swift justice.
Pardon me, George.
Somerset.
Come in.
Have you heard the news?
Nope. Haven't heard.
Eli Gould was found
murdered this morning.
Someone broke into his law firm
and bled him to death,
wrote the word "Greed"
on the floor.
Greed?
Yeah. In blood.
Mills is heading up
the investigation.
Uh, excuse me.
Excuse me.
Could you not do that, please?
Oh, OK.
Well, good for him.
What in the hell are you
going to do with yourself
out there, Somerset?
Oh, I'll work,
maybe on a farm,
fix my house.
Don't you feel that feeling?
You're not going to be
a cop any more.
That's the whole idea.
I don't think you're leaving.
Hell, you can't leave all this.
A guy's out walking his dog,
gets attacked.
His watch is taken, his wallet.
While he's lying there
on the sidewalk helpless,
his attacker
stabs him in both eyes.
This happened just last night
about four blocks from here.
Yeah, I read about it.
I don't understand
this place any longer.
It's the way it's always been.
Maybe you're right.
You were made for this work,
and I don't think
you can deny that.
Maybe I'm wrong.
The coroner sent
this down for you.
Found them
in the fat boy's stomach
mixed in with the food.
Looks like plastic.
Set them on the desk, please.
They were, uh...
They were fed to him.
Oh, Lord.
This was found on the wall
behind the refrigerator
at the obesity murder scene.
"Long is the way and hard
that out of hell
leads up to light."
Lt's from Milton.
Paradise Lost.
All right.
I'm confused.
It means that
this is beginning.
This was found behind
the same refrigerator,
written in grease.
There are seven deadly
sins, Captain -
gluttony...
greed...
sloth, wrath,
pride, lust...
and envy.
Seven.
This is not even my desk.
You can expect
five more of these.
Now wait a minute.
I can't get
involved in this.
Somerset!
He wanted it.
I'm all over it.
Where you headed?
Far away from here.
Thanks, George.
How you doing?
OK.
I've got two things to look up.
OK. Sit where you'd like.
How's everybody?
Hi there, Smiley.
Come on, George.
Your cards are getting cold.
Duty calls.
Gentlemen, gentlemen.
I'll never understand.
All these books...
A world of knowledge
at your fingertips.
What do you do?
You play poker all night.
Hey, we got culture!
Yeah. We got culture
coming out our ass.
All right!
How's this for culture?
Yo, Smiley.
You really going to miss us.
I just might.
Fucking Dante.
Goddamned poetry-rhyming faggot
piece of shit!
Fucker!
Yeah.
Yeah?
Good work, officer.
Thank you, Lord.
Oh. Sorry.
Be out of your way in a second.
You want your chair?
No. You go right ahead.
Yeah?
Phone.
It's a package deal.
It comes with the office.
Mills.
Are you OK?
Ls something wrong?
You dingleberry.
I told you not to call me
at work.
Yeah. Why?
Why?
OK.
It's my wife.
Sorry?
She'd like to speak to you.
Uh, this is Detective Somerset.
Well... it's nice
to talk to you, too.
I appreciate the offer, but...
Well, in that case,
I'd be delighted.
Yes, thank you very much.
Bye.
Hon, what...
Well?
Sorry?
I've been invited
to a late supper
at your apartment.
I accepted.
My... how's that?
Tonight.
Hello, men.
Hi, loser.
Hi, idiot.
This is Trace. Tracy, Somerset.
Hello.
Happy to meet you.
I've heard a lot about you.
Except, of course,
your first name.
It's William.
Hmm. It's a good name, William.
William, I'd like you
to meet David.
David, this is William.
I'll be right back.
How are the kids?
Good. They're in their room.
Come on in.
Oh, good dogs!
How are the good dogs?
How are you?
Smells good.
What?
The...
Oh, yeah. I mean thank you.
Um, please, have a seat.
Would you like
something to drink?
Uh, no. No, thanks. I'll wait.
Just throw that anywhere.
Excuse all this mess.
We're still unpacking.
I understand you two
were high-school sweethearts.
Pretty hokey, huh?
I knew on our first date
that this was the guy
I was going to marry.
Really?
He was the funniest guy
I'd ever met.
Really?
Well, it's kind of rare
nowadays, you know...
I mean, that level
of commitment.
Oh, don't worry.
I won't wear it
to the dinner table.
I, uh...
No matter how often I see guns,
I just... I can't
get used to them.
Same here.
Why aren't you
married, William?
Oh, Trace.
What the hell.
I was close once.
Just didn't happen.
It surprises me.
It really does.
Well...
Anyone who spends
a significant
amount of time with me
finds me disagreeable.
Just ask your husband.
Very true. Very, very true.
So how long have you lived here?
Too long.
How do you like it here?
You know,
takes time to settle in.
It'll be good.
You get numb after a while.
There are things to any city...
The subway.
It'll go away in a minute.
It's nothing.
That real-estate guy.
Fucking piece of...
Sorry, hon.
Shows us the place a few times.
I think it's good.
Trace likes it.
Then I start wondering
why he only brings us here
five minutes at a time.
We found out the first night.
The soothing, relaxing,
vibrating home, huh?
I'm sorry.
Yeah, all right, laugh it up.
I don't know what
you're laughing at.
All right already.
The guy had to get in
before the office was closed
and security tightened.
Gould would have
been working late.
I'm certain. He was
the biggest lawyer in town.
Infamous, really.
The body was found
Tuesday morning.
The office was closed Monday.
The guy could have
gotten in on Friday
and had his way
all day Saturday, Sunday,
maybe even Monday.
Look at this.
Gould was bound,
his right arm free.
He was handed
a butcher's knife.
Check out the scale.
A pound of flesh?
Yeah.
"One pound of flesh,
"No more, no less.
"No cartilage, no bone,
but only flesh."
Merchant of Venice.
Didn't see it.
"His task done,
then he would go free."
That chair was soaked
with sweat.
Of course.
The killer would have
wanted Gould
to take his time,
to sit and decide
which cut to make first.
Imagine it. There's
a gun in your face.
Which part of your body
is expendable?
How about the love handle?
Cut along the side
of his own stomach.
All right, let's take
a fresh look at these.
Even though
the corpse is there,
I looked through it.
The trick is to find
one item, one detail,
and focus on it
until it's an exhausted
possibility.
I'm going to get
another beer. Beer?
Wine, please.
He's preaching.
He's punishing.
The sins were used
in medieval sermons.
There were seven
cardinal virtues
and seven deadly sins
used as teaching tools.
Like in The Parson's Tale,
and what's-his... oh, Dante.
You read them.
Yeah. Well, parts.
Hey, remember in Purgatory,
Dante and his buddy,
they're climbing up the hill,
checking out all
the sinners, yeah?
Yeah. The seven terraces
of purgation.
Right, but there,
pride comes first,
not gluttony.
Well, for now,
let's consider that the books
were the inspiration.
The sermons were about
atonement for sin.
These murders are like
forced attrition.
Forced what?
Attrition. It's when
you regret your sins
but not because you love God.
Oh, like because
someone's sticking
a fucking gun in your face.
No fingerprints.
Nope.
Totally unrelated victims.
Yup.
And no witnesses of any kind.
Which I don't get because
the fucker had to get back out.
Well, in any major city,
minding your own
business is a science.
First thing they teach women
in rape prevention
is never cry for help.
Always yell "Fire."
Nobody answers to "Help."
Holler "Fire,"
They come running.
That's fucked up.
Must have left
another puzzle piece.
You know what? Thank you
for talking this out,
but I got to sleep,
walk the dogs.
This is to satisfy my curiosity.
I'm still leaving
at the end of the week.
Aw, shit. Wait, wait.
Gould's wife was out of town,
except this means
she saw something.
What if it's a threat?
I put her in a safe house.
She wasn't happy about it.
What if it isn't
something she has seen
but something
she's supposed to see
but hasn't been given a chance?
Yeah, OK. What?
I don't know.
But that's the one thing.
Sign us in.
We've got to see Mrs Gould.
We want you to have
a phone line, but...
Mrs Gould?
Mrs Gould, I am sorry.
I truly am.
I don't understand.
I need you to look at each photo
very carefully.
Look and see if there's anything
strange or out of place,
anything at all.
I don't see anything.
You sure?
I can't do this right now!
OK.
It's got to be now.
There may be something
we haven't seen.
Wait.
What?
Here.
This painting, it's upside down.
Your men didn't move this?
No, no, no.
Those shots were taken
before forensics.
Nothing.
There's got to be something.
Moved the screws to rehang it.
Yep.
What the fuck is that?
Switchblade.
Goddamn it!
Must be something.
He didn't paint
the fucking thing.
Now he's fucking with us.
That's what he's doing.
See this? This is us.
Yeah.
Just wait a minute.
Now Somerset's climbing
on the furniture.
Just wait a minute.
You're kidding me.
Call the print lab.
Oh, man.
Honestly, have you ever seen
anything like this?
No.
I can tell you guys
just by looking
at the swirl pattern,
they're not the victim's
fingerprints.
I don't know, man.
I'd say he's whacked enough.
Doesn't fit.
He doesn't want us
to help him stop.
Who knows?
Freaks out there
doing evil deeds
they don't want to do.
"Voices made me do it.
Jodie Foster told me to do it."
I've seen this take three days
to make a match,
so maybe you want to cross
your fingers somewhere else.
You meant what you said
to Mrs Gould, didn't you,
about catching this guy?
I wish I still thought
the way you do.
Why don't you tell me
what the hell it is
you think we're doing?
Picking up the pieces.
We're collecting
all the evidence,
taking all the pictures
and samples,
writing everything down,
noting the time things happen.
That's all?
That's all.
Putting everything
into neat little piles
and filing it away
on the off chance
it will ever be needed
in the courtroom.
Picking up diamonds
on a deserted island,
saving them in case
we get rescued.
Bullshit.
Even the most promising clues
usually only lead to others.
So many corpses
roll away unrevenged.
Don't try to tell me
you didn't get
that rush tonight.
I assure you.
We're getting somewhere.
Wake up, glimmer twins.
You've got a winner.
This guy goes by the name
of Victor.
His real name is Theodore Allen.
His prints were found
by homicide.
He's got a long history
of mental illness.
His parents gave him a strict
southern baptist upbringing,
but somewhere they fell short.
Victor dabbled in drugs,
armed robbery, assault,
spent time in prison here
for attempted rape of a minor,
but his lawyer saw to it
that didn't last long.
His lawyer was Eli Gould,
the greed murder victim.
We're going
to finish this today.
Victor's been
out of circulation,
but there's still
a residence in his name.
You're not buying this, are you?
Doesn't seem like our guy.
You tell me.
Our killer seems
to have more purpose.
You ever take a bullet?
Never in my 34 years,
knock wood.
I've only taken
my gun out three times
with the intention of using it.
Never pulled the trigger.
Not once.
You?
Yeah, but... no,
I never took a bullet,
but I pulled my gun once,
shot it once.
Really?
Lt was my first one of these.
I was shaky going in.
I was a rookie.
We bust open the door
looking for this junkie,
and the fucker opened fire.
One cop got hit in the arm.
Christ, what was his name?
Spun him like a top.
You know? I mean,
more like slow motion.
I remember...
Riding in that ambulance.
Well, he died right there.
Right there.
Christ, what was
his fucking name?
Swat goes before dicks.
Here.
They love this.
Police!
Clear!
Good morning, sweetheart.
Get up now, motherfucker.
Now!
Get up, you sack of shit.
Oh, fuck me.
Dicks!
You want to come
take a look at this!
Dicks!
Jesus.
Victor?
That's just Victor.
Call an ambulance.
A hearse.
Get your people out of here.
Go!
No one touches anything!
Some kind of freaking
wax sculpture or something.
"Sloth."
Oh, man.
Goddamn.
This picture was dated
three days ago.
This must be
the first one. Look.
It's dated exactly
one year ago today.
I got a hair sample,
a stool sample, piss.
I got fingernails.
He's laughing at us.
You got what you deserved.
He's alive! He's alive!
That cocksucker's alive!
Calm down! Emergency
on that ambulance!
He's playing games.
Ah, no shit.
We have to divorce
ourselves from emotion.
We have to remain
focused on the details.
I feed off my emotions.
Are you listening?
Yes, I can hear you.
Excuse me.
Closed crime scene.
Get the fuck out.
I got a right.
Get out of here, piece of shit!
Get out of here!
I got your picture, man.
Detective Mills.
M-i-I-I-s! Fuck off!
I'm surprised you can spell.
Fuck you!
How do they get here
so fucking quick?
They pay police for
the information and pay well.
Hey, man, I'm sorry.
I...
Well, he pissed me off.
It's impressive to see a man
feeding off his emotions.
A year of immobility
seems about right
judging by the deterioration
of the muscles in the spine.
Blood tests show many drugs
in his system,
even an antibiotic
which must have
been administered
to keep bedsores from infecting.
Has he tried to speak
or communicate in any way?
Even if his brain were not mush,
which it is,
he chewed off
his own tongue long ago.
Doctor.
Is there absolutely no chance
that he might survive?
Detective, he'd die
of shock right now
if you shined
a flashlight in his eyes.
He's experienced about
as much pain and suffering
as anyone I've encountered,
give or take,
and he still has hell
to look forward to.
Good night.
We bring you
the Charlie Parker Quintet,
featuring Charles Thompson on
piano, Herb Pomeroy's trumpet,
Jimmy Woode, bass,
Kenny Clarke, drums,
and the alto saxophone
of Charlie Parker.
Yeah.
Hello, William?
Lt's Tracy.
Tracy?
Ls everything all right?
Yeah. Yes, everything's fine.
Where's David?
He's in the other room.
He's in the shower.
I'm sorry to call you like this.
Oh, it's all right.
What can I do for you, Tracy?
I, uh...
Um, I need someone to talk to.
Do you think you
could meet me...
somewhere maybe
tomorrow morning?
I don't understand.
I feel stupid calling,
but, uh...
you're the only person
that I know here.
There's no one else.
If you can,
just give me a call, OK?
I have to go now.
Good night.
It can be a hard place.
I don't know
why I asked you to come.
Why don't you talk
to him about it?
Tell him how you feel.
I can't... you know,
I can't be a burden,
especially now.
I'll get used to things.
You know, I think
I just wanted to talk
to someone who's lived here
for a long time.
I mean upstate, you know,
it's a completely
different... environment.
Did David tell you
that I teach fifth grade?
Well, I did.
Uh, he mentioned it.
I'm going around,
you know, looking at schools,
but the conditions here...
are horrible.
What about primary schools?
I don't know.
Why don't you tell me
what's really
bothering you, Tracy?
David and I are
going to have a baby.
Oh, Tracy...
I don't think I'm...
I'm the one
to talk to about this.
I hate this city.
I had a relationship once.
It was very much
like a marriage.
We got pregnant.
This was a long time ago.
I remember getting up
one morning
and going to work,
just another day like any other
except it was the first day
after I knew
about... the pregnancy.
And I felt this fear
for the first time ever.
I remember thinking,
how can I bring a child
into a world like this
with all this around them?
I told her
I didn't want to have it...
And over the next few weeks,
I wore her down.
I want to have children.
I can tell you now...
I'm... I know...
I mean...
I'm positive
I made the right decision,
but there's not
a day that passes
that I don't wish
that I'd made
a different choice.
If you don't keep...
the baby -
I mean, if that's
your decision,
don't ever tell him
you were pregnant.
But if you choose
to have this baby,
you spoil that kid
every chance you get.
That's about all the advice
I can give you, Tracy.
I got to go.
William.
Thank you.
Victor's landlord said
there was cash in
the office mailbox
the first of every month.
"I never heard
a single complaint
"from the tenant
in apartment 306,
"and nobody ever
complained about him.
"He was the best tenant
I've ever had."
Yeah, a landlord's dream -
a paralyzed tenant
with no tongue.
Who pays the rent on time.
I'm sick of all this waiting.
This is the job.
Why aren't we out there?
Why do we sit here rotting,
waiting till
the lunatic does it again?
That's dismissive.
Don't make that mistake.
Come on. He's insane. Look.
Right now, he's probably
dancing around
in his grandma's panties,
yeah, rubbing himself
in peanut butter.
Ooh, how's that?
I don't think so.
Yeah, his luck will run out.
He's not depending on luck.
We walked into that apartment
exactly one year
after he tied Victor to the bed.
He wanted us to.
Don't know that for sure.
Oh, yes, we do.
This note he left,
his first words to us.
"...leads up to light."
Fuck him. So what?
He's right so far.
Imagine the will it takes
to keep a man bound
for a full year,
to sever his hand and use it
to plant fingerprints,
to insert tubes
into his genitals.
This guy's methodical,
exacting, and worst
of all, patient.
He's a nut-bag.
Just because the fucker's
got a library card,
doesn't make him yoda.
How much money you got?
I got, like, 50. 50 bucks.
I propose a field trip.
Come on.
We'll make a list.
At the top we'll put
Purgatory, Canterbury Tales,
anything relating
to the seven deadly sins.
Ask yourself,
what would he study
to do the things he's done?
What are his interests now?
Jack the Ripper, for instance.
Where are we going?
The library.
Coupons! Coupons!
Free coupons. Discount...
Discount coupons!
They must have had
about 50 health violations
during their last inspection.
Could you at least
sit across from me?
I don't want people
thinking we're dating.
Give me your money.
I'm giving you this,
but I ought to know
what we're doing.
Fuck.
Hey, Somerset. How are you?
OK.
I didn't expect
a mnage trois.
It's not a problem. Sit down.
Only for you do I do this.
It's a big risk.
We're just fair and square.
It's a deal.
All right.
About an hour.
Yeah, help yourself.
Well, that was
money well spent.
Yeah.
All right.
By telling you this,
I'm trusting you
more than most people.
Good, because I'm
about ready to punch you.
It's probably nothing,
but it's no skin
off our teeth.
The guy in the pizza parlour
is a friend from the Bureau.
Who? Stinky man?
For years, the FBI
has been hooked into
the library system,
keeping records.
Mm-hmm. Assessing fines.
No, monitoring reading habits.
Look.
Certain books are flagged -
books on, say, nuclear weapons
or Mein Kampf.
Anyone who checks out
a flagged book
has his library records fed
into the FBl's computers.
Wait. How is this legal?
Legal, illegal -
these terms don't apply.
You can't use
the information directly.
It's just a useful guide.
It might sound silly,
but you can't get
a library card
without an I.D.
And a phone bill.
So they run a list.
Precisely.
If you want to know
who's reading
Purgatory and Paradise Lost
and Helter Skelter,
the FBl's computers
will tell us.
Could give us a name.
It could get a college kid
writing a term paper
on 20th-century crime.
At least you're
out of the office.
Get a haircut.
How do you know all this?
I don't. Neither do you.
Exactly.
The Divine Comedy,
History of Catholicism.
There's a book called
Murderers and Madmen.
Modern Homicide Investigation,
In Cold Blood,
Of Human Bondage.
Bondage?
Not what you're thinking.
The Marquis de Sharday.
It's the Marquis de Sade.
Whatever.
The writings of
Saint Thomas Aqua-something.
Saint Thomas Aquinas.
He wrote about
the seven deadly sins.
Is that it?
Yeah.
Let's try it.
Jonathan Doe?
Whatever.
We're sure about that name?
Yeah.
You saw the list. John Doe.
Let's take a look at him.
Talk to him.
This is crazy.
Ah, we'll just talk to him.
Excuse me, sir,
are you, by any chance,
a serial killer?
OK.
You do the talking.
Put that silver tongue to work.
Have you been talking
to my wife?
This is retarded.
Charlie's fucking Angels.
Name off a computer.
Mills.
You're hit.
No.
He's going down!
Fifth floor!
Mills.
Mommy!
Police. Is there a back exit?
Lock your door.
What's going on?
Get out of
the fucking hall, please.
Get down!
Get the fuck down!
Shit.
Goddamn it!
Fuck.
Taxi!
Get out of
the fucking way! Move!
Mills!
No!
Mills?
Mills.
Are you OK?
I'm all right.
Where are you going?
I'm going in.
Wait, wait, wait.
Wait!
What are you talking about?
He fuckin' shot at us.
We can't go in.
We need a warrant.
We got probable cause.
Think. How did we get here?
I can't tell anyone.
I can't tell about the Bureau.
We have no reason to be here.
Listen to me.
Get the fuck off me!
I'm sorry,
but just pay attention.
If we leave a hole like this,
we can't prosecute.
The guy will walk.
Is that what you want?
By the time
we get the warrant...
Nah, fuck that! No!
We need a reason
to knock on this door!
Think about it!
OK.
OK, you're right.
I'm all fucked up.
You're right. You're right.
Well.
No point
in arguing any more...
unless you can fix that.
You stupid son of a...
How much money we got left?
So, yeah, like,
I noticed this guy
going out a lot
when the murders was happening,
and so I, um...
You called Detective Somerset,
right?
Right, so I called
the detective
because he looked creepy
and one of the murders
happened right over there.
OK, OK, OK...
I told you the rest.
You have to sign it.
OK.
All right.
You did good.
I did what you said.
Here. You get something to eat.
Everybody stay outside.
Victor.
Fuck.
Somerset!
Yeah.
What?
We had him.
What are you talking about?
Lt was the fucking photographer
on the fucking stairs.
We had him, and we let him go.
You're sure this is him?
Yeah. Good, good.
Uh, yeah. Good.
We've got nothing to go on.
No address books.
Just this receipt.
Then keep looking.
This was under the bed -
his only source of funds.
We got his money.
Fucking-A, good work.
One more thing
you won't believe.
We haven't found
a fingerprint, not one.
You're right. I don't
believe you. Keep looking.
We could use some more men.
I'm doing the best I can.
What's all this?
There are 2,000 notebooks
on these shelves.
Each contains about 250 pages.
Forget it. Anything
about the killings?
"What sick puppets we are.
"What a gross stage we dance on.
"What fun we have
dancing, fucking.
"Not a care in the world,
"not knowing
that we are nothing.
"We are not what was intended."
No, wait. There's a lot more.
"On the subway today,
"a man started
a conversation with me.
"He made small talk.
"A lonely man talking
about the weather.
"I tried to be pleasant,
"but my head began to hurt
from his banality,
"I almost didn't notice
it had happened,
"but I suddenly threw up
all over him.
"He was not pleased,
"and I couldn't stop laughing."
No dates.
Placed on the shelves
in no discernible order.
Just his mind
poured out on paper.
Looks like a life's work.
Even with 50 men,
it would take 2 months.
I know, I know, I know, I know.
Where's that phone?
Phone? Phone? Phone?
People, quiet!
Hello.
I admire you.
I don't know how you found me,
but imagine my surprise.
I respect you law enforcement
agents more every day.
Well, I appreciate
that... John.
I tell you...
No, you listen.
I'll be readjusting my schedule
in light
of today's little... setback.
I just had
to express my admiration.
I'm sorry I had
to hurt one of you,
but I didn't have
a choice, did I?
You will accept my apology?
I would say more,
but I'd ruin the surprise.
I'll be readjusting my schedule
in light
of today's little... setback.
Got it.
All right,
everybody back to work.
You were right. He's preaching.
Yeah. These murders
are his sermons to us.
Look, we know him,
we know him, we know him.
Who's the blonde?
Looks like a pro.
Maybe... she caught
John Doe's eye.
He collected it last night.
Last night?
This man?
Yeah. John Doe. He had a limp.
What was the job
you did for him?
I've got a picture.
One sweet piece.
I thought he was
one of them
performance artists,
the sort of guy
that pisses in a cap
onstage and then drinks it.
Performance art.
Yeah.
I think I undercharged him,
actually.
You made this for him?
I've made weirder shit
than that. So what?
They found the blonde.
The picture.
The picture!
Fucking pigs!
Get the fuck
out of the booth, pal!
I've been in this cage
the whole time, OK?
Come on. This way!
Can you do something
about this music?
We're working on it.
We're looking for the guy.
You from homicide?
You better see this.
Stay still, all right?
God, get this thing off of me!
Get him out of here now.
Get him out of here now!
Come on. I want
to hear it again.
Tell me again.
You heard nothing strange?
You saw nothing strange?
No.
He asked if I was married.
He had a gun.
Where was the girl?
The what? What?
The girl. The prostitute.
Where was she?
Someone comes
to your establishment,
they want to go downstairs
to get a little
ooh-la-la, whatever,
they got to come to you, yeah?
Yeah.
You didn't see anyone
with a package,
a knapsack,
something under their arm?
Hey, everybody
that comes in there
has got a package
under their arms.
Some guys are carrying
suitcases full of stuff.
She was just...
She was just
sitting on the bed.
Who tied her down, you or him?
Do you like what
you do for a living?
No.
No, I don't.
But that's life, isn't it?
He... he... He had a gun,
and... and he made it happen.
He made me do it.
He... he put that thing on me.
Then he made me wear it.
Then he... he... told
me to fuck her.
And I did. I fucked her!
Oh, God. Oh, God.
He had a gun in my mouth.
The fucking gun
was in my throat!
Fuck!
Oh, God! God!
God, help me. Please.
Please help me!
This isn't going
to have a happy ending.
Hey, man. We catch him,
I'll be happy enough.
If we catch John Doe
and he turns out
to be Satan himself,
that might live up
to our expectations,
but he's not the devil.
He's just a man.
You know, you bitch
and you complain
and tell me these things and...
If you think
you're preparing me
for hard times,
thank you, but...
But you got to be a hero.
You want to be a champion.
People don't want a champion.
They want to eat cheeseburgers
and watch television.
How did you get like this?
I want to know.
Well...
It wasn't one thing,
I can tell you that.
Go on.
I just don't think
I can continue
to live in a place
that embraces apathy
as if it was a virtue.
You're no different, no better.
I didn't say I was. I'm not.
Hell, I sympathise.
I sympathise completely.
Apathy is a solution.
I mean, it's easier
to lose yourself in drugs
than it is to cope with life.
It's easier to steal
what you want.
It's easier to beat
a child than raise it.
Hell, love costs,
takes effort, work.
We are talking about people
who are mentally ill,
people who are fucking crazies.
No.
Yes.
We're talking about
everyday life here.
You can't afford
to be this nave.
Fuck off.
Gee.
You should listen to yourself.
You say, "The problem with
people is that they don't care,
so I don't care about people."
That makes no sense.
You care?
Damn right.
And you're going
to make a difference.
Whatever. The point is,
is that I don't
think you're quitting
because you believe
these things.
You want to believe them
because you're quitting.
You want me to agree with you
and say, "Yeah, you're right.
"Lt's all fucked up.
It's a fucking mess.
"We should all go live
"in a fucking log cabin."
But I won't.
I won't say that.
I don't agree with you.
I do not.
I can't.
I'm going to go home.
Thank you, though.
I love you, honey,
so much.
So much.
I know.
911. What's your emergency?
Could you repeat that?
I've gone and done it again.
What have you got?
Sleeping pills...
Glued to one hand.
Telephone glued to the other.
You see what he did?
He sliced her up...
Then he bandaged her.
Call for help, and you'll live
but you'll be disfigured,
or you can put yourself
out of your own misery.
Come on.
Cut off her nose.
To spite her face.
He did it very recently.
Listen, I've decided to stay on
till this is done.
One of two things will happen.
Either we'll get John Doe,
or he'll finish his seven
and this case will
go on for years.
You don't have
to do me any favours.
Keep me as your partner
a few days.
You'll be doing me a favour.
You knew I'd say yes.
Hey, we're here.
Your wife called.
Get an answering machine.
Detective.
After this, I'm gone.
No big surprise.
Detective!
You're looking for me.
Don't fucking move!
On the floor!
Keep away from him!
I know you.
Now! Get down!
Get down! On your stomach!
You piece of shit!
Now! All the way!
All the way, fucker!
Down! Faster! Faster!
Faster, fucker! Now!
Nose on the ground!
Jesus Christ.
What the fuck is this?
I'd like to speak
to my lawyer, please.
Goddamn it!
He cuts the skin
off his fingers.
That's why we couldn't find
one usable print.
He's been doing it
for quite some time.
What about the trace
on his bank accounts?
So far everything's a dead end.
No credit history,
no employment records.
His bank account's
only five years old.
It was started with cash.
The only thing we know
about that guy right now
is he's independently wealthy,
well-educated,
and totally insane.
He's John Doe by choice.
When do we question him?
You don't.
He's going to court now.
There's no way he would
turn himself in.
It doesn't make sense.
It's not supposed to make sense.
He's not finished.
No, he's just
pissing in our faces.
You know what I'm talking about.
For the first time ever,
you and I are
in total agreement.
So what the fuck, man?
He's two murders away
from completing his masterpiece.
We'll wait for his plea.
My client says there are
two more bodies. Hidden away.
He will take Detectives Mills
and Somerset to these bodies,
but only Detective
Mills and Somerset,
only at 6:00 today.
Why us?
He says he admires you.
It's part of the game.
My client claims that if
the detectives do not accept,
these bodies
will never be found.
Frankly, counsel,
I'm inclined to let them rot.
Hey, we've got him
downstairs,
locked up, done deal.
He's going to get free
room and board, cable TV.
Hell, my wife doesn't
even have cable.
Mills!
Hey, something stinks.
And this one here...
Yeah, you, in your $3,000 suit
and that smug smile,
dealing for that shit...
Mills!
I am required by law
to serve my clients.
Ah, Jesus Christ.
To serve their best interests.
We don't make deals here.
My client says if
you do not accept,
he will plead insanity.
Let him try it.
I'd like to see him try.
With the nature of these crimes,
I could get him off
with such a plea.
I'm not letting
this conviction slide.
He says that if you do accept,
he will sign a full confession,
plead guilty right now.
It's your case. Make a decision.
Full confession. I'm in.
It has to be the both of you.
If he were to claim insanity,
this conversation
is admissible -
the fact that he's
blackmailing us.
My client would remind you,
two more are dead.
The press would have a field day
if the police didn't seem
concerned about finding them.
If there are two more dead.
The lab report came.
They did a quickie
on Doe's clothing.
They found blood from Doe
slicing his fingers,
blood from the woman
whose face he cut off,
and blood from a third party,
as yet unidentified.
You'd be escorting
an unarmed man.
Let's finish it.
If John Doe's head opens
and a UFO flies out,
I want you to have expected it.
I will.
Hey, man, if I was
to accidentally
shave off a nipple,
would it be covered
by workman's comp?
I suppose so.
If you were man enough
to actually file a claim,
I'd buy you one
out of my own pocket.
I keep coming home late,
my wife's going
to think something's up.
You know...
Yeah.
What?
Let's go!
Spin it around!
There he is.
Late model
black sedan at 10:00.
Who are you, John?
Who are you really?
What do you mean?
At this stage,
what harm can it do
to tell us about yourself?
Who I am means
absolutely nothing.
You need to stay
on your left up here.
So where are we heading?
You'll see.
We're not just going to pick up
two more dead bodies,
are we, John?
That wouldn't be
shocking enough.
We've got newspapers
to think about, yeah?
Wanting people to listen,
you can't just tap them
on the shoulder any more.
You have to hit them
with a sledgehammer.
Then you'll notice you've got
their strict attention.
But the question is,
what makes you so special
that people should listen?
I'm not special.
I've never been
exceptional.
This is, though...
what I'm doing.
The work.
The work, John?
Yes.
See, I don't see anything
special about it, John.
That's not true.
It is true,
and the funny thing is,
all this work,
two months from now,
no one's going to give
a shit or remember.
You can't see
the whole complete act yet,
but when this is done,
when it's finished,
it's going to be...
People will barely
be able to comprehend,
but they won't be able
to deny.
Could the freak
be any more vague?
As far as master plans go.
I can't wait for you to see.
It's going to be something.
I'm going to be
right next to you,
so when this thing
happens, let me know.
I wouldn't want to miss it.
Oh, don't worry. You won't.
You won't miss a thing.
Going south.
Keep two miles separation.
Roger.
What's so exciting?
Lt's not too far now.
I've been trying to figure
something in my head.
Maybe you can help me out.
When a person is insane,
as you clearly are,
do you know that you're insane?
Maybe you're reading
Guns & Ammo,
masturbating in your own faeces,
do you stop and go,
"Wow, it is amazing
how fucking crazy I really am"?
Do you guys do that?
Lt's more comfortable for you
to label me insane.
It's very comfortable.
It's not something
I would expect you to accept,
but I did not choose.
I was chosen.
Whatever.
I don't doubt that
you believe that, John,
but seems to me
you're overlooking
a glaring contradiction.
Meaning what?
Glad you asked.
If you were chosen...
that is, by a higher power...
and if your hand was forced,
seems strange to me
you would get such
enjoyment out of it.
You enjoyed torturing
those people.
Just doesn't seem
in keeping with
martyrdom, does it?
John?
I doubt I enjoyed it any more
than Detective Mills
would enjoy time alone with me
in a room without windows.
How happy would it make you
to hurt me with impunity?
That hurts my feelings.
I would never...
You wouldn't only because
there's consequences.
It's in those eyes
of yours, though.
Nothing wrong with a man
taking pleasure in his work.
I won't deny
my own personal desire
to turn each sin
against the sinner.
Wait a minute.
I thought all you did
was kill innocent people.
Innocent? Ls that
supposed to be funny?
An obese man, a disgusting man
who could barely stand up,
who you'd point out to friends
so they could join you
in mocking him?
Lf you saw him
while you were eating,
you wouldn't be able
to finish your meal.
After him, I picked the lawyer,
and you both must have
secretly been thanking me.
This man dedicated his life
to making money by lying
to keeping murderers
and rapists on the streets!
Murderers.
Murderers, John, like yourself.
A woman so ugly inside
that she couldn't bear living
if she couldn't be beautiful
on the outside.
A drug dealer -
a drug-dealing pederast,
actually.
And let's not forget
the disease-spreading whore.
Only in a world this shitty
could you even try to say
these were innocent people
and keep a straight face.
But that's the point.
We see a deadly sin
on every street corner,
in every home,
and we tolerate it.
We tolerate it
because it's common,
it's... it's trivial.
We tolerate it
morning, noon, and night.
Well, not any more.
I'm setting the example,
and what I've done
is going to be puzzled over
and studied
and followed
forever.
Yeah.
Delusions of grandeur.
You should be thanking me.
Why is that, John?
Because you're going to be
remembered after this.
The only reason
that I'm here right now
is that I wanted to be.
No. We would have
got you eventually.
Oh, really?
So, what were you doing?
Biding your time,
toying with me?
Allowing five
innocent people to die
until you felt like
springing your trap?
What was
the indisputable evidence
you were going to use on me
before I walked up to you
and put my hands in the air?
John, calm down.
I seem to remember us
knocking on your door.
Oh, that's right.
And I seem to remember
breaking your face.
You're only alive
because I didn't kill you.
OK. Sit back.
I spared you.
Remember that every time
you look in the mirror
for the rest of your life,
or for the rest of what life
I've allowed you to have.
Sit back, you fucking freak!
Shut your fucking mouth!
You're no messiah.
You're a movie of the week.
You're a fucking t-shirt,
at best.
Don't ask me
to pity those people.
I don't mourn them any more
than the thousands that died
at Sodom and Gomorrah.
Is that to say
what you were doing
was God's good work?
The Lord works
in mysterious ways.
Do you see
those high-tension towers?
That's where we're headed.
I see where
he's talking about.
Follow the access road.
Your signal's breaking up.
Un-fucking-avoidable, sir.
We're in powerline city.
There sure as shit
is no ambush out here.
Can't land anywhere
near those wires.
They're coming up behind us
in about two minutes.
Go up, way up.
30 seconds, back east.
On my mark. 30 seconds.
I'm getting him out.
We've got you in sight.
Get out...
Slowly.
Stop.
Stay.
What do you got?
Dead dog.
I didn't do that.
We're holding on stand-by. Copy.
What time is it?
Why?
I'd like to know.
7:01.
It's close.
Well, let's go take a look.
It's this way.
Bird Two, close your distance.
They're moving
away from the car.
We got them, we got them.
Closing in.
Negative, negative.
Mills.
Down. Down, down.
Watch him.
There he goes.
It's good we have
time to talk.
Stay on the guy in red!
There's a van
coming down the road
from the north.
Be ready for anything now.
Wait for my signal. Wait for me.
Get out of the van!
Out!
Jesus Christ, man.
Don't shoot me!
Step away!
Turn around.
Put your hands on your head!
What the hell is going on?
What are you doing here?
I'm just delivering
a package, man.
I got this package
for this guy David,
Detective David Mills.
Get it...
Slowly.
He's opening
the back of the van.
We've got him in sight.
This guy paid me 500 bucks
to bring it out here, man.
He said he wanted it here
at exactly 7:00.
Put it down.
We got a box.
We got a box!
Call the bomb squad.
We got a box.
Face the van.
Hands up.
Turn around.
OK. Go.
Off you go. Go!
I'm sending the driver
round on foot.
He's headed north
along the road.
Have him picked up.
I don't know. I don't know.
I'm going to open it.
When I said I admired you,
I meant what I said.
There's blood.
You've made quite a life
for yourself, Detective.
Shut the fuck up,
you piece of shit.
California, stay away from here.
Stay away from here.
Don't come in here.
Whatever you hear, stay away.
John Doe has the upper hand.
Mills!
Here he comes.
Throw your gun down!
I wish I could have
lived like you did.
What the fuck you talking about?
Do you hear me, Detective?
I'm trying to tell you
how much I admire you
and your pretty wife.
What?
Tracy.
What'd you fuckin' say?
Lt's disturbing how easily
a member of the press
can purchase information
from the men in your precinct.
What the fuck?
Throw your gun down!
I visited your home this morning
after you'd left.
I tried to play husband.
I tried to taste
the life of a simple man.
Throw it away!
Lt didn't work out...
So I took a souvenir -
her pretty head.
Mills!
What's he talking about?
Give me your gun.
What's going on there?
Put the gun... put the gun down.
What was in the box?
Because I envy
your normal life.
Put the gun down.
It seems that envy is my sin.
What's in the box?
What's in the fucking box?
I just told you.
You lie!
You're a fucking liar!
That's what he wants.
He wants you to shoot him.
No! No!
You tell me that it's not true.
Become vengeance, David.
She's all right.
Become... wrath.
Tell me!
Lf you murder a suspect,
David...
No!
She begged for her life,
Detective.
She begged for her life
and for her baby's life.
Shut up!
He didn't know.
Give me the gun, David.
David...
If you kill him...
he will win.
Oh, God!
Oh, fuck. He shot him!
Set it down somewhere.
Come on. Set us down.
Holy Christ,
somebody call somebody.
Call somebody.
Well, we'll take care of him.
Whatever he needs.
Where are you going to be?
Around.
I'll be around.
Ernest Hemingway once wrote,
"The world is a fine place
"and worth fighting for."
I agree with the second part.
www.moviesubtitles.org