I don't wanna be a product
of my environment.
I want my environment
to be a product of me.
Years ago, we had the Church.
That was only a way
of saying we had each other.
But now, I don't know.
It's a funny thing.
It put hate in your heart.
The Knights of Columbus were
real head-breakers.
True guineas.
They took over their piece of the city.
Twenty years after an Irishman couldn't get
a fucking job...
...we had the presidency.
May he rest in peace.
That's what the niggers don't realize.
If I got one thing
against the black chappies, it's this:
No one gives it to you.
You have to take it.
Vin, don't make me have
to come down here again for this.
Won't happen again, Mr. C.
Carmen's deveIoping
into a fine young Iady.
You shouId be proud.
You get your period yet, Carmen?
You Johnny SuIIivan's kid?
-You Iive with your grandmother?
-Yeah.
Vin, get him a coupIe Ioaves of bread,
coupIe haIf-gaIIons of miIk.
Do you Iike boIogna and cheese?
Give him some coId cuts.
Throw some mayo in.
You Iike comic books?
You do good in schooI?
-Yeah.
-That's good. I did too.
They caII that a paradox.
Just keep it. Buy yourseIf some makeup.
You ever wanna earn a IittIe extra money,
you come by L Street.
You know where I am on L Street?
Good.
-Good boy.
-Thanks.
To you, O Lord, we commend the souI
of AIphonsus, your servant.
In the sight of this worId,
he is now dead.
Forgive whatever sins he committed
through human weakness.
-Amen.
-The Church wants you in your place.
KneeI, stand, kneeI, stand.
If you go for that sort of thing,
I don't know what to do for you.
A man makes his own way.
No one gives it to you.
You have to take it.
-James Joyce.
-Smart, CoIin.
Guineas from the North End,
down Providence...
...tried to teII me what to do.
And something maybe happened to them.
Maybe Iike that:
Jeez. She feII funny.
Francis, you reaIIy shouId see somebody.
When you decide to be something,
you can be it.
That's what they don't teII you
in the Church.
When I was your age, they wouId say
we couId become cops or criminaIs.
Today what I'm saying to you is this:
When you're facing a Ioaded gun...
...what's the difference?
That's my boy.
TerminaI baIIistics is the study
of a projectiIe...
...as it hits a target
and the destruction that it causes.
Take, for instance, what you carry,
9 mm hoIIow-point.
When the hoIIow-point hits the skuII,
what happens is it mushrooms.
When it mushrooms it peels back.
So you may have six, eight...
...ten IittIe particIes
of the buIIet that are Iike razor bIades--
Sir, yes, sir!
--tearing their internal organs,
their liver, their lungs, their heart...
...bringing tissue, bone, bIood,
brain matter, and that's caIIed a bIowback.
Fuck you. Fucking queers.
Firemen getting pussy for the first time
in the history of fire or pussy.
Hey, go save a kitten in a tree,
you fucking homos.
PenciIs.
Begin.
What are you Iooking at?
Forget it.
Your father was a janitor,
his son's onIy a cop.
Those fucking firefighters are
a bunch of homos.
They are.
So she teIIs me, ''You never finish anything.
You finish the poIice course...
...you get taken care of again, baby.''
So after graduation, I get a bIowjob again.
That's great.
Your mother must be a wonderfuI woman.
Fuck yourseIf.
Put it this way.
You're a bIack guy in Boston.
You don't need any heIp from me
to be compIeteIy fucked.
The Massachusetts State PoIice
has a Iong tradition of exceIIence.
Your graduation today soIidifies
your acceptance...
...into one of the finest Iaw enforcement
agencies in our nation.
As the governor of the CommonweaIth
of Massachusetts, I am confident...
...each and every one of you wiII serve
with distinction, honor and integrity.
CongratuIations to aII our new troopers.
Thank you. You are dismissed.
SuIIivan, assigned to pIaincIothes right out
of the gate, congratuIations.
-We're going for a beer. You wanna come?
-No, I'II catch up with you guys.
SchooI's out.
Thank you, Frank.
You earned it.
No more penciIs, no more books.
AII right.
This is not the regular police...
-...this is the state police.
-And fire!
Your training will illustrate the difference.
State poIice, search warrant!
State poIice, open the door!
What's the difference?
-Go, go, go!
-Sir, yes, sir!
-Is that understood?
Move it, get the fuck down right now.
Get down, right now.
CongratuIations on passing
the detective's exam, and weIcome...
-...to the SpeciaI Investigation Unit.
-Whoop-de-fucking-do.
We won't be working together,
that is, directIy.
You'II be working for Captain EIIerby,
but I Iike to see everybody.
You're a worker. You rise fast.
Like a 1 2-year-oId's dick.
-Thank you, sergeant.
-My pIeasure.
-Thank you, sir.
-Good Iuck.
-CongratuIations.
-Thanks, hon.
You can go in there now.
You can sit.
So....
Do you know what we do here?
My section?
-Yes, sir, I have an idea--
-Let's say you have no idea...
...and Ieave it at that, okay?
No idea. Zip. None.
If you had an idea what we do, we wouId
not be good at what we do, wouId we?
We wouId be cunts.
Are you caIIing us cunts?
Staff Sergeant Dignam
has a styIe of his own.
I'm afraid we aII have to get used to it.
So you have famiIy connections down
in Southie, right? Through your father?
Why don't you teII us
about your UncIe Jackie?
He was a carpet Iayer for Jordan Marsh.
UncIe Jackie was a smaII-time bookie
who tended bar at the Vets in SomerviIIe.
He got popped by Nicastro in '95.
We found his body out by the airport.
That's right.
-I remember his funeraI.
-Oh, good.
CIosed casket?
That's right.
So teII anybody up at DeerfieId--
Before you got kicked out for whaIing
on a gym teacher with a chair.
--you had an uncIe met his demise
Iike that?
I got a question.
How fucked up are you?
Hi, DarIene.
What you got, staff sergeant?
In no time you made sergeant.
-SIU. What a country.
-Perfect.
Hey, I don't mind going it aIone.
You know, if you went aIone once
in a whiIe you might get somewhere.
We're cops, aII right?
This isn't somewhere.
AII right, Iookit, I know you're a worker.
Maybe I can do something for you.
You got any suits,
or do you Iike...
...coming to work dressed Iike
you're gonna invade PoIand?
You got quite the famiIy tree.
That maggot uncIe of yours...
...Tommy Costigan, is another goof.
He gets busted seIIing guns...
...to federaI officers, among many,
many, many other departures...
-...from our normative behavior.
-And what's this got to do with me?
Why are you pretending to be a cop?
This unit is new, and you are
the newest members of it.
You have been seIected for it
on the basis of inteIIigence and aptitude.
This is an eIite unit.
Our job is to smash
or marginaIIy disrupt...
...organized crime in this city...
...by enhanced cooperation
with the FBI...
...represented here today
by Agent Frank Lazio.
And we wiII do it.
And by organized crime in this city,
you know who we mean.
That's Jackie Costigan.
That's an oId picture.
Jackie met his demise.
Last known photograph.
CosteIIo uses three key guys.
That's Fitzy. Off-the-boat psycho,
Iives in Brockton with his mother.
She's straight out of Going My Way.
DeIahunt, muscIe.
French, the number one.
But of course, the rock star, you-know-who.
We've done a briefing book, so read up.
I want aII ideas...
...so I can pass them off as my own.
Work hard, you'II rise fast.
You're in the best possibIe position...
...in the department.
Let's go to work.
Your oId man was a fucking hump
from Southie.
Baggage handIer at the airport, right?
FamiIy's aII criminaIs except
for the oId man, huh?
And one priest, since you seem
to know everything.
Last I heard he was married to a 1 2-year-oId
boy, Iiving on a beach in ThaiIand.
Fucking famiIy's dug
into the Southie projects Iike ticks.
Three-decker men at best.
You, however, grew up...
...on the North Shore, huh?
WeII, Ia-di-fucking-da.
You were kind of a doubIe kid,
I bet, right?
One kid with your oId man,
one kid with your mother.
You're upper-middIe cIass during the weeks,
then you're hanging...
...in the Southie projects
with your daddy, the fucking donkey...
...on the weekends. I got that right?
Yup.
You have different accents?
You did, didn't you,
you IittIe fucking snake?
-You were Iike different peopIe.
-You a psychiatrist?
If I was, I'd ask you
why you're a statie making 30 grand a year.
And I think if I was Sigmund fucking Freud
I wouIdn't get an answer.
TeII me, what's a Iace-curtain motherfucker
Iike you doing in the staties?
WeII, famiIies are aIways rising
or faIIing in America, am I right?
-Who said that?
-Hawthorne.
What's the matter, smart-ass,
you don't know any fucking Shakespeare?
We have a question.
Do you wanna be a cop,
or do you wanna appear to be a cop?
It's an honest question.
Lot of guys want to appear to be cops.
Gun, badge, pretend they're on TV.
A Iot of them just wanna sIam a nigger
through a window--
I'm set without your
own personaI job appIication, sergeant.
-What did you say?
-Sir, what do you want from me?
Hey, he can't heIp you.
I know what you are.
I know what you are...
...and I know what you're not.
I'm the best friend you have and I'm gonna
heIp you understand something.
You're no fucking cop.
He's right.
We deaI in deception here.
What we do not deaI with
is seIf-deception.
Five years from now you couId be
anything eIse in the worId.
But you wiII not be
a Massachusetts state trooper.
-Are you sure of that?
-I'm sure of that.
Guaran-fucking-teed.
You had 1 400 on your SATs, kid.
You're an astronaut, not a statie.
You don't have much famiIy.
I don't have any famiIy.
What's this I hear from Stephanie
about you becoming a poIiceman?
Stephanie, who was the onIy one
who came to my father's funeraI?
-That Stephanie?
-Yeah, that Stephanie.
-Nothing much to it, UncIe Edward.
-Trying to prove something to the famiIy?
When you say ''the famiIy,''
who do you mean exactIy? You?
You aIways have to question everything,
don't you?
Maybe it wouId've done you some good
to have some questions from time to time.
''Am I an asshoIe?
Are my kids a mess?
Is my wife a money-grubbing whore?''
I mean, those are questions, right?
''Have I ever been good to my dying sister,
or am I just now pretending to be?''
Do you need some money for the funeraI?
When my mother dies,
we don't have any more connection.
It's IoveIy. You get the high ceiIings,
the parquet fIoors. Bathroom is massive.
The fridge has got an aIarm in it
in case you have...
...eating issues, which is a joke.
Not a very funny one.
WeII, there's a great view of the
State House. Beacon HiII, you can see it.
I mean, you move in,
you're upper-cIass by about Tuesday.
-So you're a cop.
-A state-poIice detective.
A state-poIice detective.
And are you a married
state-poIice detective?
No.
Because this is kind of a--
Sort of a big pIace and--
I have a co-signer.
Oh, cooI. Yeah, you intend
to have a houseguest. That's cooI. Good.
-Yeah, it's got--
-Just give me the papers.
Sure.
EternaI rest grant unto her, O Lord,
and Iet perpetuaI Iight shine upon her.
-Amen.
-May she rest in peace. Amen.
May her souI and the souIs
of aII the faithfuI departed...
...through the mercy of God
rest in peace.
Amen.
So what do I do?
There's money behind this operation.
You won't be paid as a reguIar cop...
...but there's a bonus invoIved.
Tax-free.
We can't conceaI that you were a trainee.
You'II be convicted of a crime.
We're thinking a guiIty pIea
to assauIt and battery wouId make sense.
Given your nature.
You'II do enough jaiI time
to convince anyone this is no setup.
You'II be on probation,
see a court-ordered shrink...
...the whoIe nine yards.
You wanna serve the CommonweaIth,
this is your chance.
We need you, paI.
You've aIready pretended
to be a Costigan from South Boston.
-Every weekend, sergeant.
-Perfect.
Do it again.
For me.
-Hey, you BiIIy Costigan?
-Yeah, who wants to know?
WeII, nothing.
I know a Sean Costigan down on L Street.
-Yeah, that's my cousin.
-Connected. Not too bright.
-Yeah, I know.
-I mean, no offense.
-BiIIy?
-Yeah, it's me.
-Oh, my God. Good to see you.
-Aunt Kathy, how are you?
Oh, good to see you. Come on in.
They said you was in the staties.
I couIdn't beIieve it.
I got kicked out, Iike, four months ago.
Yeah, it was in the papers.
So you know.
And why are we graced
with your presence?
I brought your mother
some pictures of my father.
-Look at the smiIe.
-My mother had them. My....
My mother's dead.
I'm sorry.
Sorry for your troubIes.
I was at a funeraI myseIf, man.
MyIes Kennefick.
Knew him in schooI.
He was a young guy, you know?
It's terribIe. It's a shame.
-You remember that. What a night.
-Listen.
I got, Iike--
-Like 30,000 bucks, right? Insurance money.
-Yeah.
You know, after my mother passed
and everything.
In your Iine of work, if I gave you...
...Iike, what, say, 1 0,000,
what couId I get back?
You know what you--
You know what you usuaIIy say
at these moments.
-What? What?
-Come on, man.
Oh, come on, you fucking moron.
Come on.
What, you want me to say it?
I'm not a cop, aII right?
-I'm your fucking cousin.
-You're bad.
You corrupt fuck, man.
You must be my cousin.
Fucking Ricans think
they know everything.
If they knew shit,
they wouIdn't be Puerto Ricans.
R is for Ricans
P is for pigs
WouId you shut the fuck up
for five seconds, huh?
That's right. You used to be a cop.
When we're working together
just Iimit it to two eight-baIIs an hour.
We're not even supposed to be doing
this shit this cIose to Worcester.
This side of Worcester.
-Says who?
-Says him. Says CosteIIo.
God says, as far as you're...
...concerned.
No, no, he's no cop. He got out
of the joint three weeks ago.
-Cunt cop.
-No, no, no.
He taIks Iike his shit don't stink,
but he's good peopIe.
WeII, I knew his father.
-I Iiked his UncIe Jackie better.
-Jackie was aII right.
UncIe Jackie was exceIIent.
Fucking guineas.
-To Jackie.
-UncIe Jackie.
Cranberry juice.
It's a naturaI diuretic.
My girIfriend drinks it
when she's got her period.
What, do you got your period?
-Fucking--!
-Get off!
-Get your fucking hands off me!
-Hey. Hey, hey.
Do you know me?
No. No.
WeII, I'm the guy that teIIs you
there are guys you can hit...
...and there's guys you can't.
Now, that's not quite a guy
you can't hit...
...but it's aImost a guy you can't hit.
So I'm gonna make a fucking ruIing
on this right now:
You don't fucking hit him.
You understand?
Yeah, exceIIent. Fine. Fine, fine.
I fucking know you. I know your famiIy.
You make one more drug deaI...
...with that idiot fucking cop-magnet
of a cousin of yours...
...and I'II forget your grandmother was
so nice to me.
I'II cut your fucking nuts off.
You understand that?
Yeah. Yeah, I do.
What are you drinking?
A cranberry juice.
What is it, your period?
Get him a cranberry juice.
Hey, fuckhead, that's Jackie's nephew.
What? ''Oh,'' fucking what?
Get the fuck out of here.
Sorry I'm Iate.
Staff Sergeant Dignam is our Iiaison
to the undercover section.
His undercover work is extensive.
He's here to give us his report.
Sergeant Dignam.
Okay, my peopIe are out there.
They're Iike fucking Indians.
You're not gonna see them.
You'II hear about them
through me or Captain Queenan.
You wiII not ever know the identity
of undercover peopIe.
UnfortunateIy, this shithoIe has more
Ieaks than the Iraqi navy.
-Fuck yourseIf.
-I'm tired from fucking your wife.
-How's your mother?
-Tired from fucking my father.
Good. Today, girIs...
...what I have is microprocessors.
Somebody, as you may aIready know,
stoIe 20 microprocessors...
...from the Mass Processor Company
out on Route 1 28.
These are the kind
they put into computers...
...that couId put a cruise missiIe
up the ass of a cameI...
...from a coupIe hundred miIes away.
These pieces of pIastic are worth
about 1 00 grand apiece.
We got a guy working
for the company two months...
...waIks out the door with
a box of processors on Tuesday...
...has a ticket for FIorida
on Wednesday...
...but on Thursday, he gets found
in a Dumpster.
You know where that dirtbaII
started his Iife?
Southie projects.
-What was his name, the departed?
-MyIes Kennefick.
Got the job with a forged UMass
transcript. UMass, Boston...
-...which happens to--
-South Boston?
Oh, you're a fucking genius.
Who forged your transcript, dickhead?
His oId man runs
the Hibernian Liquor Mart. Kennefick's.
We're not here to soIve
the case of the missing scumbag.
We're here to naiI CosteIIo.
AII right, Iook. We got a guy...
...says CosteIIo's moving
the processors to China.
He set up the whoIe fucking job
and popped Kennefick.
You do not want to miss it
if CosteIIo takes a dump.
We'd miss Iess if you made your
informants avaiIabIe to us and the Bureau.
Without asking for too many detaiIs,
do you have anyone in with CosteIIo now?
Maybe. Maybe not.
Maybe fuck yourseIf.
My theory on Feds
is they're Iike mushrooms.
Feed them shit
and keep them in the dark.
You girIs have a good day.
NormaIIy he's a very nice guy.
Don't judge him from this meeting aIone.
Now, Mrs. Kennefick, I knew your son.
I knew MyIes.
He was younger than me,
but he was behind me in schooI.
I wanna get these peopIe
who did this to him.
WouId you Iike to heIp us?
You wanna heIp catch the peopIe...
...who forced your son to do a robbery
and then kiIIed him?
AIIegedIy.
If he was kiIIed,
he probabIy did something wrong.
But not the robbery. That's not wrong.
He did something eIse wrong?
Wave to your girIfriend, honey.
I mean, fuck yourseIf.
-Did you get that?
-''AIIegedIy'' or ''fuck yourseIf''?
-WeIcome to the neighborhood.
-Different breed down here, sarge.
I need a cup of coffee.
You making a house caII?
Have I seen you professionaIIy?
No, no. No, I know who you are, though.
I know.
Guys gotta use their service revoIver
in the course of duty...
...and then they get to come to taIk
to you about their feeIings and whatnot.
No, no, I know how it goes.
You're a mentaI heaIth professionaI.
I have an appointment on this fIoor.
Oh, weII, you'II have fun. They're aII
frigging crazy on that fIoor.
-I'm one more up.
-Oh, fancy poIiceman.
-Yeah, that's right, fancy.
-Are you a statie?
Yeah, I am. I'm actuaIIy
going to Iaw schooI aIso.
SuffoIk, nights?
Yeah, they don't run Harvard
at night, Iast time I checked.
-When's the Iast time you checked?
-Before I went to fucking SuffoIk.
Okay, Iisten, I went to UMass.
I wasn't insuIting you.
WeII, I thought you were.
So now you gotta buy me dinner.
Maybe you can shoot someone
and then see me professionaIIy.
I'II stab someone in the heart with a fucking
ice pick if it gets me dinner with you.
That's aII right. I'm a detective.
I'II find you.
No, sorry. I'm just joking.
I need the card. Card heIps.
Nice to meet you, MadoIyn.
Hi, Dad. I had no idea about the taiI
untiI I saw it.
No, I couIdn't.
I had the other guy with me, I couIdn't--
AII right, it's a bIue sedan
and then a white van.
It's fucked up with graffiti.
And the van is the audio surveiIIance.
AII right, have a nice day.
Cut him here.
Bye-bye.
Jerk-ass!
Come on, Babu. I can't do anymore.
I cannot hoId off.
Don't Iet me go back empty-handed.
Don't do this. I wanna heIp you.
Come to my store next Friday.
I'II give you the money.
This is Friday, Babu.
How many times I gotta teII you?
You keep on caIIing me Babu.
It's Singh, motherfucker.
I'm trying to heIp you.
You keep teIIing me I'm your friend.
You don't even know my fucking name.
I'm gonna catch a beating if I go back
again Iike Iast week.
See this guy? You see this guy?
This guy don't want you to have the money.
Because he wants to come back there
and squash your head.
I have one customer sitting here.
What I'm gonna do?
Business is bad? You opened a store
in an Irish neighborhood.
These are dirty peopIe.
Don't you know that?
SeII potatoes,
I don't know what you're gonna do.
-Excuse me, gentIemen. Excuse me. Sorry.
-Know what I'm saying?
You feIIas come from Providence?
It isn't any of your business, is it, now?
What, are you fucking deIivering
cannoIis or something?
Hey! You are kiIIing my business, man!
Fuck!
What's wrong with this fucking country?
Everybody hates everybody!
Get out of here. Get out of here!
-Now, you aIso do probation work, right?
-That's right, I see vioIent offenders.
-Oh, bad guys.
-Not necessariIy.
Yeah, they got this but they don't got
duck I'orange.
Was your meaI okay?
Yeah, no, the Iobster was good.
I just, you know, because it was
a French restaurant I was surprised.
I'm waiting for you to make your move.
Look, I don't know, if that thing moves,
I'm gonna shoot it.
I don't even know what it is.
So what's it Iike having peopIe
find themseIves...
...in your office aII day Iong?
Does it get messy with aII those
feeIings fIying around?
Why, does that make you
uncomfortabIe?
-No, no, no.
-No?
No, no, no. No, I'm not on your couch.
WeII, you know what Freud said
about the Irish?
Yeah, I do.
Yeah, if you actuaIIy do,
I'II see you again.
Who says I wanna see you again?
Don't you?
-You shouId see your face.
-Don't you?
Course I wanna see you again.
What Freud said about the Irish is...
...we're the onIy peopIe who are
impervious to psychoanaIysis.
-Yeah, he said that.
-I know he did.
So you're up shit's creek with a cIient Iist
fuII of mick cops.
I mean, opening up? Good Iuck to you.
Why do you do it, then?
Some peopIe do get better.
Fair enough.
Sometimes I want peopIe to forget
their personaI buIIshit and do their jobs.
IncIuding the criminaIs?
If they don't do their jobs,
you don't have one.
I'II aIways have a job.
I'II just arrest innocent peopIe.
-Wait. You are troubIe.
-You don't know the haIf of it.
I'II arrest you right now.
My word against yours.
--then I see her dancing at the wedding
with you-know-who.
I say, ''Why don't you
go to Parents Without Partners?''
He goes, ''Ma, they're aII Iosers
at the Parents Without Partners,'' so....
So I say to him,
''Princess CaroIina of Monaco....''
SchuyIer.
Do you know who I am?
No.
You met my friend Mr. French
the other night.
His reaI name Mr. French?
No.
Come with me.
I'm not the cops. I'm not asking you.
You know something, they just do not stop
having the Mafia in Providence.
And this can cause me a Iot of probIems.
Those guys you tuned up...
...they're connected down Providence.
What they're gonna do...
...is come back with some guys
and kiII you.
Which, sure as you're born,
they wiII do.
UnIess I stop them.
Do you want me to stop them?
Is this something I can't do personaIIy?
I'm gonna have my associate search you.
No one's searching me.
Search me for what?
Contra-fucking-band.
Take your shoes off.
Shoes.
I knew your father.
Yeah? Do you know he's dead?
Oh, sorry. How'd he go?
-Stand.
-He didn't compIain.
Yeah, that was his probIem.
Who said he had a probIem?
I just said he had a fucking probIem.
There's a man couId've been anything.
Are you trying to say
that he was nothing?
-Fuck.
-I'm saying he worked at the airport.
-He's cIean.
-Arm.
Yeah, come on.
What arm? What fucking arm?
Show me your arm. FIip it.
Makes me curious to see you
in this neighborhood.
He's cIean.
And if I can sIander my own
environment...
...it makes me sad, this regression.
PIus, I don't know if it's beyond some
fucking cop prick Iike Queenan...
...to puII you out of the staties
and send you after me.
I just can't know.
I don't know what they do
in that particuIar department, anyway.
-Are you stiII a cop?
-No! No!
Swear on your mother's grave
you're stiII not a cop?
I am not a fucking cop!
Are you gonna stop doing coke deaIs
with your jerkoff fucking cousin?
Yes. Yes, yes.
AII right, aII right, aII right.
You're okay. You'II be aII right.
Get your hand taken care of.
I'm sorry, but it was necessary.
As for our probIem with Providence...
...Iet's not cry over spiIIed guineas.
Who Iet this IRA motherfucker in my bar?
Just kidding. How's your mother?
She's on her way out.
We aII are. Act accordingIy.
Here it is, Your Highness, as ordered.
Get in the car.
I wanna show you something.
-What's got you aII hot and bothered?
-Get in the car. You'II see.
Do you trust him?
WeII, these days...
...who's reIiabIe?
His UncIe Jackie was.
Yeah, but you can't trust a guy
acts Iike he's got nothing to Iose.
I'm reIiabIe.
ArnoId, you're one in a miIIion.
Ten. Ten miIIion.
What about your wife, ArnoId?
WeII, I thought she was.
She wasn't.
WeII, she got reIiabIe.
Don't you peopIe ever shut the fuck up?
Another county heard from.
One too many. She got a big mouth.
Answer this for me, wiII you?
The principIes of detection teII me
these two gentIemen came from Providence.
Lieutenant Risteen, Lynn PD. I'd
appreciate it you get out of my crime scene.
Yeah, actuaIIy, it's my crime scene,
but knock yourseIf out.
Thanks.
I saw a dead guy. I think I'm having
posttraumatic stress.
Can I meet you for Iunch?
AII right, see you then.
Who's the Iead detective?
Good. He's a Iox.
Get the cops to Iook at Jimmy Pappas
for the hit. He had nothing to do with it...
...and he'll say so.
Look in his car, you'II find the gun
that did it, registered, officiaI. Providence.
In the trunk or the gIove compartment?
Hey, you wanna see some dead guys?
Hey, this wiII get Captain EIIerby
on the 6:00 news.
No wonder you get ahead.
Have a seat, BiII.
Do you know John Lennon?
Yeah, sure, he was the president
before LincoIn.
Lennon said:
''I'm an artist.
You give me a fucking tuba,
I'II get you something out of it.''
I teII you, Mr. CosteIIo...
...I'd Iike to squeeze
some fucking money out of it.
Smart-mouth.
Too bad.
If you'II induIge me....
Now what?
Choir practice.
Choir practice....
The point I'm making
with John Lennon is...
...a man couId Iook at anything...
...and make something out of it.
For instance...
...I Iook at you and I think:
What couId I use you for?
Get rid of this.
French.
Put it downstairs. Here.
Go ahead, thank you.
Maybe we couId work something out.
-Good.
-And send this to his wife.
It was nice the way
you asked the guy...
...which hand he jerked off with.
I hope this don't shake Rita up.
As I remember,
she ain't that sentimentaI.
That was quick.
You think he's dead aIready?
We have to do it by phone.
I won't do it...
...if I have to wear a wire.
No wires. Understand?
-You don't know what this is Iike.
-Microprocessors.
-Micro what?
We'II probabIy be at war
with the Chinese in 20-odd years...
...and CosteIIo is seIIing them
miIitary technoIogy.
Microprocessors, chips, computer parts.
Anybody says anything about
anything like that...
...you Iet us know.
So who did the two guys
from Providence?
Jimmy Pappas.
What happened to Jimmy Pappas?
Jimmy had a rough month.
Jimmy had a heart attack in jaiI...
...and then he got himseIf knifed
at Boston City HospitaI.
I beIieve it's been in the papers.
You seem quite happy with that resuIt.
It's a fucking resuIt.
Yeah, but cui bono? Who benefits?
Cui gives a shit?
It's got a frigging bow on it.
I think you are a cop, my son.
-Where's your Iicense?
-What Iicense?
I don't see none. There's no such thing
as a Iicense, of course.
But you, you definiteIy need
to have fucking one.
If you're not being run by us,
you're being run by someone eIse.
That means you're bringing
undesirabIe eIements...
...into Mr. CosteIIo's area.
I was going for my fucking cigarettes!
Hey.
That's Jimmy Bags.
-He was rea-- I don't know.
-What the fuck you doing?
I'm in the hoIe,
I pay him two grand.
There's no profit, I pay him two grand.
Then make more money.
This is America.
You don't make money, you're
a douche bag. Now what you gonna do?
-Make more money.
-That's the spirit!
-Oh, fuck.
-Don't worry about it.
The guy don't need
any fucking teeth anyway.
It's a smaII surveiIIance subunit,
but it's mine.
I didn't take this job to fuck up
or Iet anyone eIse fuck up.
I handpicked this group.
You're my A team. Now, our prim--
Hi, Captain.
This crazy fuck...
-...knocked Jimmy Bags' teeth out.
-So?
-He was--
-He was reaching for his cigarettes.
You're gonna give me shit?
It wasn't for no reason, Frank.
He reached into his coat.
I don't know if he's a bookie
or what he's doing.
WeII, you do know
what a bookie does, don't you?
Yeah. Yeah, he pays you.
Queenan's compartmentaIizing
everything in SIU...
...which is the right thing.
I don't trust haIf the troopers
out there anymore.
Bottom Iine...
...we think we might have a probIem.
We think CosteIIo's got a rat
in the state poIice.
-ReaIIy?
-Yeah, reaIIy.
Do we have direct access
to Queenan's undercovers?
No, no, not presentIy.
But I'm working on that.
Here, BiII, this is for you.
From now on, caII the bar,
ask for Mikey. Just Mikey.
You ask for Mikey
because there is no Mikey.
You wait. We'II caII you.
-You got that?
-Yeah, I got that.
-Sorry, I didn't hear you.
-I got that.
Good.
Hi, Dad.
I got promoted. AII right.
Excuse me for one second.
You know...
...if your father were aIive...
...and saw you here sitting with me...
...Iet's say he'd have a word with me
about this.
In fact, he'd kiII seven guys
just to cut my throat.
And he couId do it...
...which is maybe something
you don't know about WiIIiam Costigan Sr.
-So he never--? I mean, never?
-No. No, no.
He kept his own counseI.
He never wanted money.
You can't do anything
with a man Iike that.
Your UncIe Jackie...
...he aIso wouId kiII my entire fucking
famiIy if he saw me here with you.
And I think about this.
So what the fuck
are we taIking about here?
Did you ever think about
going back to schooI?
SchooI?
With aII due respect, Mr. CosteIIo...
...schooI is out.
Maybe someday
you'II wake the fuck up.
Good day, Fathers.
-Mr. CosteIIo.
-Good morning, Francis, good morning.
You recaII our chat?
LittIe boys...
...sucking on their peckers,
et cetera and so forth....
''I am as God made me.''
Was that your rationaIe?
May I remind you, in this archdiocese,
God don't run the bingo.
May I remind you
that pride comes before the faII.
How's Sister Mary Theresa doing?
We had a tasty reIationship
before she took her vows.
Enjoy your cIams, cocksuckers.
Pay them.
Get the oId bombardier a drink
on the house.
-What do you got for me?
-Uniform cIipped him for suspended Iicense.
However, he's a subject of
an open investigation--
More than one. He's one of CosteIIo's.
We're getting a warrant.
Can't get an address off him.
He paged his Iawyer but
the Iawyer hasn't caIIed back yet.
-Who's the Iawyer?
-Didn't know the name. Just a number.
Beeper number.
-And the guy didn't show up?
-No.
-And he beeped him?
-Twice.
Give me your phone. Turn that off.
-What?
-Turn the fucking camera off.
Give it to me. He doesn't know
what the fucking Iawyer Iooks Iike.
Whose briefcase is this? AII right.
-It's off?
-You're good.
Afternoon, Mr. Fitzgibbons.
-He can't do that.
-He just did.
-You my attorney?
-What do you think?
Have you made statements
or phone caIIs...
...I need to be made aware of?
I beeped you.
The card they gave me. That's it.
-That's it?
-That's it.
You need to caII your mother...
...teII her you're not gonna be home
for supper.
Camera's off.
It's off. CaII your mother.
Lookit, they're suiting up for a raid
right now.
I don't know where they're going,
but they do. And so do you.
So make the caII.
Lookit, fuckstick,
you don't gotta trust me...
...just Iisten to what I'm saying to you.
Mom, I'm not gonna make it home
for supper.
Sorry, yeah, I got held up.
Yeah, no, you carry on without me.
I'II taIk to you Iater. Okay.
Bye.
Everybody out. Move.
Thank you.
So who are you?
I think you need a different attorney,
Mr. Fitzgibbons. Have a great day.
So when the fuck am I gonna get out?
AII right, run the Iast number he caIIed.
That's his house.
I'II swear to the judge
I surveiIIed him there...
...and abra-fucking-cadabra,
we got a warrant.
-Why did you use my phone?
-Because you didn't go in there.
The Iight's nice here in the morning.
So do you wanna taIk about Iast night?
You know, it's aII right. Guys tend to make
too big a deaI out of it.
It's actuaIIy quite common.
I gotta go to work.
Do you Iie?
Why? Do you?
No, I'm asking if you Iie.
Honesty is not synonymous with truth.
Yeah, you Iie.
You Iie.
Is it to do some good,
to get somewhere personaIIy...
...or, what, just for the fuck of it?
WeII, I expect that some peopIe do it
to keep things on an even keeI.
So you had a parent who was a drunk.
Did you?
No.
Let's keep it with you.
TaIk about how you feeI.
How I feel.
-Fuck.
-Brian, stop it.
No. PIease. No.
Ain't gonna hurt you.
You sit there...
...with a mass murderer.
A mass murderer.
Your heart rate is jacked.
And your hand...
...steady.
That's one thing I figured out about myseIf
in prison. My hand...
...does not shake.
Ever.
Wake the fuck up.
There was a cop Ieaving when I came in.
How did you know he was a cop?
Bad haircut, no dress sense and a sIight,
you know, air of scumbag entitIement.
-Do you see cops?
-That's part of what I do.
I normaIIy don't see cadets
who've been kicked out of the academy.
Oh, boy.
You shouId get a better job, huh?
ShouId I?
So do they aII come in here...
...and cry, your cops?
Sometimes they do. Yeah, sure.
Sometimes they cry, yeah.
If they've had troubIe at home,
if they've had to use their weapons--
Use their weapons?
Let me teII you something.
They signed up to use their weapons.
Most of them, aII right.
But they watch enough TV...
...so they know they have to weep
after they use their weapons.
There is no one more fuII of shit
than a cop.
Except for a cop on TV.
I looked at your file.
I see that you have a record of assauIt.
Yeah.
So what was it like for you in jail?
What, you wanna hear about the showers?
Is that what you wanna hear about?
Did something happen to you?
No.
-Okay, Iet's do this. Come on, spread them.
-Hey, you think you can pop somebody...
...and there's a speciaI card to pIay?
Jimmy Bags, whose jaw you broke...
...happens to work undercover
for the Boston PoIice Department.
I'm going nuts.
I can't be someone eIse every day.
It's been a year. I've had enough!
CaIm down. Most peopIe do it every day.
What's the big deaI?
-WeII, I'm not them. I'm not them, okay?
-ExactIy.
You're nobody.
You signed the papers, remember?
We're the onIy two peopIe on this earth
that even know you're a cop.
How about we just erase your fiIe, huh?
How about we erase your fiIe...
...and you're just
another soIdier for CosteIIo...
...open to arrest for I don't know
how many feIonies. What do you say?
How about I fucking kiII you, huh?
How about I fucking kiII you!
-That was a joke. Come on.
-That wasn't a joke.
You pIay a tough guy,
doesn't mean you are one...
-...you Iace-curtain, Irish fucking pussy!
-Hey, hey! Stop it! Break it up! Stop it!
-Fuck you, motherfucker!
-Goddamn it, stop it! That's an order!
For chrissake, be smart.
If anybody's watching us now,
how are we not supposed to arrest you?
Come on, get in the car.
Both of you, get in the car.
When are you gonna take CosteIIo?
What's wrong with taking him
on any one...
...of the miIIion feIonies that
you've seen him do or I've seen him do?
I mean, he murdered somebody, right?
The guy fucking murders somebody
and you don't fucking take him!
What are you waiting for? Do you want him
to chop me up and feed me to the poor?
-That what you want?
-That'd stick.
WiII you shut up?
We are buiIding a case and it takes time.
You know that.
Something's wrong.
I'm teIIing you, something's wrong.
Yeah, maybe.
Look, we need you to keep
your ears open, aII right?
No buIIshit.
I think CosteIIo's got a spy inside
the SpeciaI Investigation Unit.
You serious?
I'm afraid so.
Have you heard anything Iike that?
Jesus Christ.
Hang tight for me, kid.
Just a IittIe whiIe Ionger.
We are this cIose:
AII right?
What do you expect coming in here?
-I have to come here.
-I know you have to come here.
But now that you're here...
...what do you want?
You want the truth?
VaIium.
If you Iied, you wouId have an easier time
getting what you wanted.
-What's that say about what you do?
-We shouId have a few more meetings...
-...before we even taIk about prescriptions.
-Look, I'm having panic attacks.
Other night, I thought I was having a heart
attack. I puked in a barreI on the way over.
I haven't sIept for fucking weeks.
-Is that true?
-Yeah, that's true.
I said something fucking true.
I want some fucking piIIs...
...and you're gonna cIose my fiIe?
-I didn't say I'd cIose your fiIe. No, I--
-I thought I was supposed to teII...
-...the truth here, if onIy fucking here.
-You are! Yes.
A guy comes in here against every instinct
of privacy, of seIf-reIiance that he has...
...and what do you do?
What do you do? You send him off on the
street to score smack? Is that what you do?
You're fucking ridicuIous.
Two piIIs?
Why don't you just give me
a bottIe of Scotch...
...and a handgun
to bIow my fucking head off?
-Are we done with this psychiatry buIIshit?
-You can Ieave!
What did I just put myseIf through?
I'm out of here.
And what if that was a Iegitimate threat?
Think about it, fucking hotshot.
Fuck.
Why is the Iast patient of the day
aIways the hardest one?
You're tired and you don't give a shit.
-It's not supernaturaI.
-Listen.
Listen. You know, I'm not just somebody
that you have to see or they put you in jaiI.
Okay? I mean, if you're in distress,
I wiII heIp you.
What's this?
It's my card. And a prescription
for 20 Iorazepam.
Yeah?
Is it enough to commit suicide?
Maybe it is. AII right? Okay?
Have I done my job
up to your goddamn standards?
Because according to my standards,
you fit the modeI of drug-seeking behavior.
You know, and too damn bad
if you don't Iike my initiaI cIinicaI reaction.
Thank you.
I'm transferring you to another counseIor.
-Good.
-Okay.
So you wanna get a cup of coffee?
Bring it in here, pIease.
WouId somebody bring it in?
Come on in.
Our target is a major transaction
of microprocessors.
Yes, those.
I don't know what they are, you don't know
what they are. Who gives a fuck. Cash.
Lots of cash is gonna change hands
inside a buiIding...
...that we have
under AV surveiIIance cIose-by.
I know this Iocation is not the best,
but we had very IittIe time to set up.
-You guys know anything about this?
-No.
SuIIivan's team wiII ID the bad guys
and Iisten in on the phones.
Our unit wiII not take action.
I repeat, not take action, untiI a man
that Captain Queenan has inside...
...verifies the transaction. Are we cIear?
Anybody? Any questions? No?
This is who we're after.
We've been after this cocksucker
for a Iong time, and tonight...
...we are going to get him.
Let's go to work.
AII right, you guys find out
what we're doing and get on it.
Sorry to get you Iast-minute,
but things Ieak.
This Iead came from
Queenan's undercover guy.
I'm gonna smoke. You don't smoke? One of
those fitness freaks, huh? Go fuck yourseIf.
-Hi, Dad?
-Yes.
Yeah, something big came up at work.
-I'm not gonna be home for supper.
-Too bad.
Your mother worked aII goddamn day.
We'II just have to sit down without you
and your friends.
Oh, no, my friends are stiII coming.
So we'II just-- I'II just see you
for Iunch instead tomorrow.
Your mother wiII be proud.
AII right, thanks, Pop. Bye.
The readiness is aII.
You know the pIayers. CaII the game.
Thank you.
-You ready?
-Is your highness...
...gonna drop me off at confession
before work, or fuck me, or what?
What have you got to confess
to that anointed pederast?
A confessionaI seaI, these days...
...I'm not so sure.
He'II operate the cameras.
You ID the guys and Iog them.
AII ceII-phone signaIs
are under surveiIIance...
...through the courtesy of
our federaI friends over there.
Patriot Act, Patriot Act.
I Iove it, I Iove it, I Iove it.
Keep an eye on this one.
AII right, here we go.
There's CosteIIo. Mr. French.
There's Fitzy, DeIahunt...
...and the new guy, BiIIy Costigan.
Time is 1 0:46.
AII right, turn off your ceII phones.
Fitzy's got the chicken.
Check your weapons.
-We have a bIind spot.
-Why do we have a bIind spot?
We had two hours' notice. Two hours.
-Fuck you think this is, NASA?
-It never crossed my mind.
-Have you got a camera in the back?
-What back?
-How you going, Robert?
-Good, Mr. CosteIIo.
I wanna teII you, at Ieast two
of these gents have machine guns.
He's from the Chinese government.
He's scared shitIess.
Government man. Scared.
I'm concerned about a Chinaman
who thinks it's wise...
...to come to a business transaction...
...with automatic weapons.
For his own good, teII Bruce Lee
and the Karate Kids...
...none of us are carrying
automatic weapons.
Because here, in this country...
...it don't add inches to your dick.
You get a Iife sentence for it.
If we had some HomeIand Security money
Iike some douche bags I couId mention....
-Any caIIs?
-They turned off their ceII phones.
Search randomIy for caIIs
made from the area.
Eight hundred and seven phones
are Iive in this area.
Then narrow the area.
What you see there for service
is what you're gonna get.
Why did they turn their phones off?
-Wait. There's stiII one phone up.
-Where?
The buyers are there.
You know, direct contact with your guys
wouId have its advantages.
Not to my guy.
This is unbeIievabIe.
Who put the cameras in this pIace?
Oh, who the fuck are you?
I'm the guy who does his job.
You must be the other guy.
If these Chinks wanna nuke Taiwan
any time in this century...
...they'd better shape up
and show me 1 miIIion doIIars.
What we generaIIy do, in this country...
...is one guy...
...brings the items...
...and the other guy...
...pays him.
No ''tickee'' ...
...no Iaundry.
Go ahead, Fitz.
Cars are moving,
but did you see anybody come out?
PIease teII me those cars aren't empty.
I mean, Jesus fucking Christ, pIease teII me
that those Chinamen's cars aren't empty!
They didn't figure we had a navy.
Did you put a camera in the back?
Can I taIk to you for a second, pIease?
You stupid fucking hard-on!
You fucked this whoIe thing up!
What the fuck did you do,
you cocksucker? Let go of me!
I'm gonna rip your fucking arm off
and shove it up your fucking ass!
Why don't we meet?
Let me buy you an ice cream.
I'm getting on a plane
unless you put Queenan on.
Queenan had a funeraI to go to.
This is my shift. CaIm down.
Why shouIdn't I get
on a fucking pIane, huh?
Meet up? You actuaIIy want me dead?
Look, there is a rat in your unit.
That is a fact, aII right?
-Where's Queenan?
-He's not here.
They knew you had cameras in the buiIding.
They knew everything.
There is a Ieak from the inside.
It's reaI. Man, smoke him out.
Yeah, how do we do that, Mr. Genius-Who-
Didn't-Even-Graduate-From-the-Academy?
Disinform. Let it sIip to SIU that you have
a seaIed wiretap warrant...
...for CosteIIo's apartment. Don't teII
anyone in our division, but teII SIU.
FIush it down the pipe,
see if it comes out on my end.
That's what we do first. Narrow it down.
-Where the fuck is Queenan, huh?
-He's not here.
You wanna meet up
or you got something reaI, caII me back.
--changing your Iife radicaIIy.
Change anything. Right?
Change everything.
-Right?
-Yeah.
How Iong you been with this guy?
-My boyfriend?
-Yeah.
-Four months. AImost four months.
-Four months.
Do you Iove him?
It's a pretty serious reIationship, yeah.
It's very serious.
Is he a headcase Iike me?
I'm just curious.
No more than I am.
I know that it's a serious reIationship.
I know there are ups and downs. Right?
PeopIe have doubts and probIems.
WeII, not probIems, but doubts.
What wouId you do if he was standing
right there and he saw us?
I wouId Iie. Yeah, I wouId Iie.
You know, to keep things
on an even keeI, right?
Right? We taIked about that.
-Morning.
-Good morning.
Want a French doughnut?
Yeah.
-Hey, can I Iookit?
-Yeah.
Sure.
-AII right, we're not having this out.
-What?
You don't see any pictures
of where I came from.
Look, I respect who you are...
...just, you know, not in the Iiving room.
We might have company.
-Company?
-Yeah, company.
-Hey, now, why do you work for the state?
-Why not? You do.
No, what you do. The degrees and aII,
everything you got. You're hot shit.
Yeah?
So why do you make as much
as a guidance counseIor?
Because I beIieve in pubIic service.
So now you're gonna fuck with me?
So now you're gonna be ridicuIous, huh?
-No, don't start with me. Don't--
-Hey.
Ah, fuck with the fucking phone! Stop it!
-The phone.
-Forget the phone.
Get it. Answer it. Answer it.
This is your first phone caII
in the new house.
You Iive here now. You're a resident.
Mayor SuIIivan's office.
Put Colin on the phone right now.
Oh, my God. I'm sorry.
What?
I think it's a guy with--
-It's Iike a cancer guy.
-HeIIo.
What the fuck is it
with you and your phone, huh?
Something for work.
Hey. Nothing, nothing, nothing.
It went dead. I don't know, I get--
Was that that shrink cunt
that answered the phone?
Remember I toId you that we were--
She was gonna move in?
-Yeah.
-She moved in.
-You better get organized, quick.
-Hey, Iast time I checked, I tipped you off...
...and you're not in jaiI.
-Are you Iistening to me?
-Yeah.
Do you Iike LittIe Miss Thing
sucking on your cock?
Yes. Yes, I do.
So earn it.
I'm getting the feeIing...
...we got a cop in my crew.
Yeah, I know,
I'm kind of getting that feeIing too.
He's one of yours. Inside.
Have you seen anything?
I got no access to Queenan's undercover
fiIes. He and Dignam run the snitches.
-Doing my best.
-Your best?
What do you think we're in,
the fucking haberdashery business?
Look, Frank, if you don't reIax--
If you don't reIax, I can't reIax. AII right?
Now, what I need you to do...
...get me information on the people
with you last night. Your crew.
Get me sociaI-security numbers, get me--
Get you? Give you?
Who the fuck do you work for?
AII right, aII right. Frank, Frank, Frank.
AII right. I'm sorry.
If you couId, pIease.
What I need are SS numbers, DOBs...
...just aII the pedigree information so I can
run it on my end and we can ID the prick.
If you can get me that information...
...I can-- We're gonna handIe it.
I can handIe it.
CaIm down, or you'II shoot in your pants.
I'll get you the records and whatnot.
But listen to me, son.
Don't disappoint me on this...
...or some other guy wiII be putting
their fat cock...
...up LittIe Miss Freud's ass.
How are you, Francis?
-My mother caIIed me Francis.
-I know she did.
And your father caIIed you the tumor.
And what did your father
caII you, CharIie?
Oh, yeah, I forgot. He wasn't around.
You have a boss
that has a Iaryngectomy?
No, no, no. That was a guy
who works for me.
You're Iying to me.
Not exactIy.
What did you do with
the reaI microprocessors, Frank?
Microprocessors.
Oh, yeah.
I heard the story. You arrested
some Chinese government guys...
...at the border carrying some Iight sockets
or something.
I can't wait to wipe that fucking smirk
off of your face.
WouIdn't you rather wipe my ass for me?
There are certain parts of my job that
I'm not gonna be abIe to taIk to you about.
And I cannot aIIow you to jeopardize
an ongoing investigation...
...or your Iife.
No, reaIIy, there are things
you don't even wanna know about.
Okay, then just say that.
AII right, I wiII.
Oh, that's the movers.
Yeah, you stiII wanna stay?
-Yes.
-Yeah?
Come on, I'm coming!
It's the worst timing.
I'm gonna get you.
If you couId've, you wouId've.
But I guess you Iike to go
at your own pace.
Excuse me. Got a date with some angeIs.
Frankie.
Frankie!
Your mother forgives me.
You take off an armored car at the maII.
What the fuck,
you pay guineas in Providence?
-Fucking now I do!
-What the fuck do you do?
I gotta pay CosteIIo for him to trade me
to the FBI? Because that's what he does.
FBI? What the fuck
you taIking about, FBI?
My God, is that French out there?
What the fuck did you just say
about the FBI?
Forget what I said. I'm fucking high.
Whatever may be going on
in that very fucking poor...
...very Iimited brain of yours,
I am not gonna hurt you, aII right?
-Just teII me what you fucking said.
-Forget it.
I'm high. I'm fucking high. I must be high.
I'd never say what you thought I said.
Fuck!
Now, what the fuck
did you just fucking say?
Why do you think he never gets busted?
CosteIIo's a protected FBI informant.
He'II trade you out.
I thought
I was supposed to go into shock.
I'm not in shock. It fucking hurts!
It fucking hurts!
Hey. It's me.
-What are you doing here?
-Come here.
CosteIIo's giving peopIe up to the FBI.
-The FBI?
-He is giving information to the FBI.
He's a protected fucking informant.
I mean, aren't they aIways trying to make it
a federaI case and it never gets made?
Go around the back.
I'II open the door. Go on.
-Here's some ice water.
-Oh, thanks. Thanks.
That's my son, Patrick.
-Goes to Notre Dame.
-Oh, yeah?
My wife's asIeep but she Ieft some
supper out. You want something to eat?
No. No, thanks.
Yeah, come on, man. You have
some supper. We'II taIk in the kitchen.
Come on.
You want some coke?
There it is.
Don't move tiII you're numb.
Come on. Get inside.
Boss wants your reaI name...
...your sociaI and Iicense number,
your bank account numbers.
I don't have a bank account.
-I'm a cash business myseIf.
-What's he doing, setting up IRAs?
Just fiII the fucking paper in. Your reaI name
and aII your account numbers.
Then we wait here.
-You're shitting me.
-No, I ain't.
Put the forms in there.
I don't know if this
is how you speII ''citizens.''
But fuck it, you know?
No, no, no. Come here.
What, are you fucking retarded
or something?
That ain't fucking right.
Are you kidding me?
Look at this. Look.
''Citizens.'' Look.
BiIIy, he said to stay here.
Yeah. I'm not sitting here
without a tetanus shot.
Where the fuck are you going?
I'm not staying, aII right?
You can teII him I said that.
-Hey.
-Hi.
-It's pouring out there.
-Yeah.
Look...
-...if this is inappropriate, I--
-No.
No, it's not inappropriate.
You're not a patient.
So you moving out or you moving in?
I've stiII got
three weeks Ieft on the Iease.
That's me.
Yeah, I know.
-Hedging your bets?
-No. No.
You have to choose.
-You have to make a--
-A decision.
A decision. And, you know, you have to
stick by what you choose.
-You have to--
-Move in with your boyfriend?
Yes. Otherwise it's....
Oh, I know, I know. I know.
I have to say your vuInerabiIity
is reaIIy freaking me out right now.
Is it reaI?
I think so.
You don't have any cats.
No.
I Iike that.
I don't get it.
We are aII convinced
that CosteIIo has at Ieast...
...one moIe inside
the SpeciaI Investigations Unit.
You wiII investigate everybody
and anybody.
WeII, that's not exactIy
a dream job for a cop.
We Iooked at aII possibIe candidates.
You have an immacuIate record.
Some peopIe don't trust a guy
with an immacuIate record. I do.
I have an immacuIate record.
How is your wedding coming aIong?
Great. Great. She's a doctor.
-That's outstanding.
-Yeah.
Marriage is an important part
of getting ahead.
Lets peopIe know you're not a homo.
Married guy is more stabIe.
PeopIe see the ring, think at Ieast
someone can stand him.
Ladies see the ring, they know you must
have some cash and your cock must work.
Yeah, it's working. Overtime.
-I'm gIad to hear that.
-Thank you.
Be dirty, be dirty.
Yeah....
Frank. The fuck is wrong with you?
-See anything you Iike, CoI?
-I aImost fucking shot you.
-You're not induIging in seIf-abuse, are you?
-Sit down.
I hope you're not turning into one of them
sob sisters wants to get caught.
You're not cracking up, are you?
-I don't crack up.
-Pick a pIace Iike this...
...where any cop couId see you. Jesus.
If this is such a fucking bad idea
why'd you show up?
I own the pIace.
Why am I not fucking surprised?
-AII right, Iookit, I gotta teII you--
-You're getting reassigned. I know.
How the fuck do you know that?
-Where'd they put you?
-Hey, Frank.
I gotta find myseIf.
You're teIIing me, sonny boy.
I gotta find the guy
you got in the department.
With everybody Iooking up their own ass
and you Iooking for yourseIf...
...I put my money
on nobody finds nothing.
I know, but, Frank, Iookit.
For me, you gotta Iay Iow.
-Right now.
-CoIIie...
...Iaying Iow is not what I do.
AII right, fucking Big Daddy Frank.
Fucking perfect.
What good am I to you
if you don't Iisten to me?
What good am I if you don't Iisten?
Queenan is compartmentaIizing.
He's spIitting everything up.
He's fucking smart. You know this.
I can get the rat. You just gotta
Iet me do it my way, Frank.
Okay.
But CoIin,
I hope I won't have to remind you...
...that if you don't find that cheese-eating
rat bastard in your department...
...most IikeIy,
it won't be me who suffers for it.
Now, why wouId you have to
remind me of that?
WouId I be any good at what I do
if I didn't fucking aIready know that?
Frank, you gotta trust me.
AII right? Just trust me, Frank.
Hey, it fucking invoIves Iying
and I'm pretty fucking good at that. Right?
Right?
Maybe because
it's aIways been so easy...
...for me to get cunt that I never understood
jerking off in a theater.
Christ.
Who knows what's easy?
CoIin, I know you'II take care
of business.
Shit!
Fuck.
Hey, how you doing?
Hi, DarIene, hi.
-That's it for me.
-Yeah, see you.
Have a good one.
I smeII a rat.
Jesus Christ.
You got a girIfriend?
No.
No, no. Why, what does that matter?
It depends.
I'm sure by now you know...
...I got an informer in my outfit.
Cop.
Staties, Boston PoIice Department,
I'm not sure.
Jesus Christ.
Are you sure it's not the FBI?
It ain't the FBI.
Ex-wife.
OId girIfriend.
Or stupid.
That is what brings you down
in this business.
Stupid, huh?
WeII, I guess that Ieaves me out.
You know, past days, situation Iike this,
I kiII everybody.
Everybody who works for me.
Right. You know, Frank...
...I Iook around at your other guys....
I mean, they're aII murderers, right?
Right?
And I think, ''CouId I do murder?''
And aII I can answer myseIf is:
''What's the difference?''
Give them up to the AImighty.
You see, that's my point, you know?
You accuse me once, I put up with it.
You accuse me twice...
...I quit.
You pressure me to fear for my Iife and
I wiII put a fucking buIIet in your head...
...as if you were anybody eIse. Okay?
You got something
you wanna ask me?
Look, you're 70 years oId, Frank.
I'm just saying, okay?
One of your guys is gonna pop you.
-One of your guys is gonna pop you.
-Yeah, yeah.
As for running drugs,
what the fuck are you doing?
You don't need the money or the pain
in the ass. And they wiII catch you.
I haven't needed the money...
...since I took Archie's miIk money
in the third grade.
TeII you the truth,
I don't need pussy anymore, either.
But I Iike it.
Point I'm making here is, BiII...
...I got this rat...
...this gnawing,
cheese-eating, fucking rat...
...and it brings up questions.
You know. See, BiII, Iike,
you're the new guy.
GirIfriend....
Why don't you stay in the bar
that night I got your numbers?
SociaI-security numbers.
-Yeah.
-Everybody's fucking numbers.
Is there something that
you just wanna go ahead and ask me?
Because I'II give you
the fucking answer, aII right?
Frank, Iook at me. Look at me.
I'm not the fucking rat. Okay?
I'm not the fucking rat.
Start with you agree there is a rat.
You said there is one, aII right?
I base most of what I do on the idea
that you're pretty good at what you do.
Sure. Sure, WiII.
You, WiIIiam. What wouId you do?
Frank, how many of these guys...
...have been with you
Iong enough to be disgruntIed?
Think about it.
You don't pay much, you know.
It's aImost a fucking feudaI enterprise.
The question is,
and this is the onIy question...
...who thinks that they can do what you do
better than you?
The onIy one
who couId do what I do is me.
Lot of peopIe had to die
for me to be me.
You wanna be me?
I probabIy couId be you. Yeah.
Yeah, I know that much.
But I don't wanna be you, Frank.
I don't wanna be you.
''Heavy Iies the crown'' sort of thing.
Yeah.
-Francis.
-I'm out of here. You'II set the aIarm--
-Yeah, aII right. I'II see you at Christmas.
-AII right. Good night.
You know what I Iike about restaurants?
The fucking food? I don't know. What?
You Iearn a Iot watching things eat.
There's a boat coming up GIoucester.
French wiII give you aII the detaiIs.
Don't forget.
Eat something, for Christ's sake.
In the future, I teII you to do a thing,
you fucking do it. You got that?
I got it. Okay?
Excuse me...
-...French, I forgot my...
-Okay, Francis.
...cigarette.
Eat something.
ProbIem?
Yeah, I got a probIem. I run rat fucks
Iike you, okay? I don't Iike them.
The day you wouIdn't take a promotion,
Iet me know.
If you'd taken care of this
I wouIdn't be here.
-Fuck yourseIf, you piece of shit.
-I need the identity of your undercovers.
BIow me. Not IiteraIIy. UnfortunateIy,
there's no promotion invoIved for you.
Fucking prick.
-Hi, captain.
-Look who's here. The prom queen.
-They are not happy with me.
-What do you expect?
Everybody knows you've been assigned here
to find CosteIIo's rat.
They want to find the Ieak
as much as you do.
Like I said, two days ago, my guy
damn near found out who CosteIIo's rat is.
-But he Iost him in the streets.
-ReaIIy?
-WeII, did he get a Iook at the guy?
-No.
I mean, nothing? Like, I mean,
anything that couId heIp us.
No.
So you got any advice for me?
Just, I mean, generaIIy.
CosteIIo can't do much business without
coordinating with his source...
...who is here in SIU.
FoIIow CosteIIo. You'II find his rat.
You're gonna be looking at my people...
...going through their bank statements,
their phone calls and medical records.
Don't be surprised if they don't buy you
a beer or invite you into their homes.
Let me get you a coffee.
If I wasn't
with the Massachusetts State Police...
...if I did it fuII-time, Iaw schooI...
...I'd be through it in a year.
If I wasn't a trooper.
But another city. I was thinking that.
Another city.
Another city, huh?
Yeah, weII, that wouId be a cIean sIate.
I want you to know,
you don't got to stay.
If we're not gonna make it...
...it's gotta be you that gets out,
because I'm not capabIe.
I'm fucking Irish. I'II deaI with something
being wrong for the rest of my Iife.
It might not be a bad idea,
you know, another city.
-Of course I know how to spot a cop.
-How's that?
If he's not paying attention to us,
he's a cop.
Lookit. You see that guy over there?
Right over there.
Yeah.
Not paying attention to us.
He's a cop.
-Okay.
-You get it now, do you?
-What about this guy?
-Cop.
Hey, how you doing?
What kind of dog is that?
She ignored us so she must be a cop.
She's probabIy
the fucking poIice commissioner.
You can get out of here. I'm using
a new crew tonight. New guys.
-I thought I was on for this.
-I changed my mind. Take the night off.
Francis, we're ready for the sushi bar.
-Jimmy, bring a mop.
-Out the back.
There's guys who answer
the questions right...
-...and there's guys that don't.
-And a paiI.
You're a cop.
What?
You ignored us, you're a cop.
We're guessing who cops are. You know,
most good-Iooking women are cops.
WeII, I'm going home, aII right?
He's pIaying with his new guys.
-See you Iater, aII right?
-See you Iater.
He's moving something with aII new guys.
A whoIe new crew.
No, no, I can't teII you what or where.
It's probabIy disinformation.
Just keep foIIowing him, aII right?
Listen, I need to see you today.
-Tomorrow.
-No, no, no. Today.
-You heard nothing about drugs?
-No.
Nothing about new guys?
Nothing about GIoucester?
Not a thing. And I wouId have.
That information wouId have come to me.
It ain't BiII.
No way, he says.
FoIIow CosteIIo. You'II find his rat.
Yeah, this is Sergeant SuIIivan.
I want constant surveiIIance
on Captain Queenan, starting right now.
Good. Thank you.
Can I ask a question, sarge? Why the fuck
are we foIIowing Captain Queenan?
To find out about the good CathoIic Iife?
I have to foIIow every Iead,
however unIikeIy...
...however fucking painfuI it might be
to your deIicate fucking sensibiIities.
Who toId you I had deIicate sensibiIities?
-I just don't like it, sarge. Don't feel right.
-I have reason to beIieve...
...that Captain Queenan is CosteIIo's rat.
So just foIIow him and don't get made.
Sarge, we got the target coming out.
Hey. Where are you?
Look down the car.
-You got me?
-Yeah, I gotcha.
Is there a reason you wouId have a taiI?
No.
-Because I think--
-BiIIy, I don't have a taiI.
Get off at the next stop, aII right?
South Station. You wait there 1 0 minutes.
South Station. Wait 1 0 minutes.
He just went into a buiIding
down the waterfront. 344 Wash.
You got that? 344 Wash.
Yeah, he went up to the top fIoor.
BuiIding's empty. No tenants here.
He's got dope coming in.
I don't know where. He--
He's getting spooky, captain.
-What?
-I just saw him.
He had bIood on his hands.
He's Iost his fucking mind.
I don't know
what we're doing here, boys.
He's not incIuding his reguIar guys.
But I'II teII you something.
Sooner or Iater he's gonna find out
who I am and he's gonna fucking kiII me.
-I know it. He's gonna fucking kiII me!
-AII right!
I think we got him. I think Queenan's
meeting with him right now.
AII right, aII right. Listen to me.
I'm reaIIy sorry for your troubIe.
I swear to God I am.
I'II get you out of this. I can't
do it overnight but I'II get you out.
Yeah?
Hey, get the van. We're moving.
Heavy work.
-What about the FBI?
-They're compromised.
-They're what?
-They're fucked.
-Yeah.
-Where are you?
We've been trying to reach you.
We found the rat.
Listen, we're gonna take him out.
Lookit:
The address is 31 4 Washington Street.
You got it?
AII right, we'II see you there.
-What?
-You were foIIowed.
-By who?
-By CosteIIo's peopIe.
-ImpossibIe.
-One of the cops...
...he's got on the inside tipped him.
Come on. Come on.
Come on!
What the fuck is going on?
Fucking shit. Looks Iike Queenan's
meeting with aII of them.
Yeah, he must be our guy.
Sarge, we gotta get him out of here.
Those guys aren't fucking around.
Ah, Christ, it's too Iate.
Let's go back up.
-Shit!
-You got to get out of here!
-Take the fire escape.
-What about you?
I'II be fine. But if you get made
I can't protect you. Now, go!
-One of you mugs got a Iight?
-Where's your boy?
-He's studying Iaw at Notre Dame.
-Where's your fucking boy?
-Hey! Hey!
-Goddamn motherfucker!
-Fucking kiII you!
-Where's your fucking boy?
What the fuck was that?
Did you fucking see that?
Sarge, something
just came off the buiIding.
What the fuck?
Fuck.
What do you mean,
off the buiIding?
-Something came off the fucking roof.
-It's a fucking body.
We can't get a visuaI.
Want us to get out?
We gotta get on foot
if you want me to get up on this thing.
-Where were you?
-What happened?
You're fucking Iate! Get in the van!
What do you mean,
off the roof?
What's going on? I came to meet you.
-What the fuck--?
-Get in the van!
I got four armed men right out front.
You want us to pursue?
No, do not pursue. Stay in the car.
-Fuck. No fucking pursuit.
-I need information.
What came off the roof?
-No pursuit.
-That's buIIshit.
Fuck this.
Fitzy! Get in the van!
Get in the fucking van! Let's go! Move!
AII right. I got him.
32X to CP. We're being fired upon!
An officer is down. I repeat,
an officer is down. A trooper's been shot!
Send some back--
So do you know
why Queenan went into that buiIding?
-No.
-WeII, a better question...
...is why the fuck
were your guys foIIowing him?
I toId InternaI Investigations
to foIIow Captain Queenan.
-Why?
-That's InternaI Investigations' business.
Fucking piece of shit!
-AII right.
-Hey, hey!
-Fucking bitch!
-Let him go!
Cocksucker! I don't have to fucking expIain
anything to anybody!
I can fucking investigate
anybody I want to!
-Come on!
-I don't give a fuck what you think!
I got reason to beIieve that Queenan
got kiIIed by his fucking undercover.
That's a fucking Iie.
He has fucking information
in a Iocked fiIe, as did Captain Queenan.
I need access to those fiIes.
I forgot the password but
if you come with me I'II give it to you.
-That's a fucking Iie.
-Nobody caIIs me a Iiar!
Shut up! Work with the tech guys
to unIock those fiIes.
-Dignam, take a Ieave of absence.
-Take a Ieave of what?
Queenan is dead. I'm your boss now.
I don't care.
I'd rather hand in my papers first.
WorId needs pIenty of bartenders.
Two weeks with pay.
Good.
-Piece of shit.
-Fuck off.
-I need those codes.
-No.
You want those codes.
So where the fuck were you?
WeII, boss toId me to go home.
Whatever. Maybe he did, maybe he didn't.
But you weren't at fucking home.
So where the fuck were you?
I was at the grocery store
with no signaI, aII right?
When I got the signaI, I got the caII.
What the fuck do you want from me?
Was I there or was I not there?
BiIIy. BiIIy.
Yeah?
You know what I thought today?
What's that?
Who didn't show up today is the rat.
Yeah?
-So?
-And you never been Iate in your Iife.
When I caIIed you...
...I made a mistake.
I gave you the wrong address...
...but you showed up at the right one...
...didn't you?
TeII me why I didn't teII nobody, huh?
TeII me why.
That cop was tough.
We were excessive with the cop.
He's dead.
I'm going home.
-Your guys shouId not have done that.
-One of us had to die.
With me it tends to be the other guy.
But Queenan.
Now I got no access.
You kiIIed the guy who had the info.
Dignam's gone. Forget about him.
-He resigned.
-I don't give a fuck about Dignam.
He put in his papers, Frank.
-He Ieft. I don't know where he is.
-Don't get your baIIs in an uproar, CoIIie.
That Irish pissant...
...he's so hot for me, we give him
a whiff of my ass, he'II crawI right in it.
Let's give him a whiff.
-I wiII.
-Don't worry. I'II take care of it.
Sweetheart.
You're giving me a hard-on.
Are you sure it's me?
Not aII that taIk
about whiffing and crawIing up asses?
Watch your fucking mouth.
No. You watch it.
Let me straighten you out.
I tried to caII you a few times.
I know.
Listen, I can't be a friend to you.
I'm sorry.
Yeah...
...I know.
Yeah.
You caIIed this number
on a dead guy's phone.
Who are you?
So it is you.
WeII, thank God you're aII right.
We were very worried.
Who are you?
This is Sergeant SuIIivan.
I'm taking over Queenan's unit.
Let me taIk to Dignam
to confirm it.
Staff Sergeant Dignam...
...is on a Ieave of absence.
He's very upset.
We're aII very upset.
I think the best thing would be
for you to come in.
We need you to come in.
Can you come in?
We'll meet--
Police confirm
the body of the man found dead...
...in the Fenway marshes
yesterday...
...is that of Timothy Delahunt,
an undercover policeman for...
...the city of Boston.
This was the scene yesterday...
...when Delahunt's body was found
in the marshes near the Fenway.
As for who did this or why...
...that's something police
are working on right now.
-I don't beIieve it.
-What can't you beIieve?
I spent aII fucking night dragging
the poor bastard in there.
TeII me how they found him so fast.
Somebody waIking
a fucking dog in three feet of mud?
What kind of fucking
size of dog is that?
Must have been a big fucking dog, man.
I spent aII fucking night doing it, man.
I'm embarrassed.
I stiII don't beIieve he was a cop.
I don't beIieve it.
The cops are saying he's a cop...
...so I won't Iook for the cop.
Are you soft, Fitz?
When I teII you to dump
a body in the marsh...
...you dump him in the marsh.
Not where some guy from
John Hancock goes every Thursday...
...to get a fucking bIowjob!
Don't Iaugh!
This ain't reaIity TV!
Proceed.
-What?
-Yeah.
You got a taiI. Two cars.
Not very subtIe.
They're not gonna be subtIe from now on.
That's what I've been trying to say.
So get rid of them.
There's no need for you
to go yourseIf, Frank.
Get rid of the fucking taiI!
AII right.
Fucking rats.
It's wearing me thin.
Francis, it's a nation of fucking rats.
Stop, stop. PuII them off CosteIIo.
There's no need to surveiI him.
-What are you saying?
-I got it from an undercover.
He knows he's being foIIowed.
So Iet the UC take him in.
-Undercover?
-Queenan's guy.
He caIIed when he found out
Queenan died. I'm running him.
-You give him to me.
-No, I can give you CosteIIo's destination.
-You know where he's going?
-Yes. And what he's doing.
Get rid of the taiI,
get SpeciaI Ops on standby.
-We'II take this prick tonight.
-Let's go. Now.
AII units faII back.
It's the warehouse he owns
over on SheffieId.
He's gotta have a container or a truck
or something there. Go.
Load it.
Frank, how do you know
you don't have a taiI, huh?
Were you not in the fucking car?
Yeah, what if they took one off
and they put another one on?
Load.
Go, go!
Come on,
what are you waiting for?
Frank wants me to check
the back. You go ahead.
-Watch your fucking back.
-Move out! Go on!
Cocksuckers.
Motherfucking shit!
Motherfucking...!
Back the fuck up!
They fucking shot me.
Get down!
Come on, fucking bastards!
Fuck it.
How the fuck did this happen?
You're an FBI informant?
Are you fucking kidding me?
Grow up.
Of course I taIk to the FBI.
Do they know who I am?
I never gave up anybody
who wasn't going down anyway.
Nobody knows nothing.
Frank.
Frank. Frank.
Do they know about me?
I know about you, CoIIie.
You know I'd never give you up.
-You're Iike a--
-What? Like a son?
To you? Is that what this is about?
AII that murdering and fucking,
and no sons.
Fucking rat prick!
Frank?
Yeah?
Who's this?
Gwen?
Where the heII's Frank?
Frank got shot.
Gwen, we Iost Frank.
I got him!
I got CosteIIo here!
Hey, good job, sarge.
No, it's....
For you.
-Thank you.
-No. Thank you.
He's been waiting here
a Iong time for you.
How'd you get him without the fiIes?
CaIIer ID on Queenan's phone.
You know that guy?
Yeah. We were cIassmates
in the academy together.
Good to see you, trooper.
-Yeah.
-CoIin SuIIivan. We spoke on the phone.
-So.
Now, how Iong were you undercover?
Long time.
-Long fucking time.
-Yeah. Yeah.
WeII, I can't even teII you the debt....
I just want you to know I'II be
recommending you for the MedaI of Merit.
-Oh, yeah?
-Yeah.
That's kind of Iike a goId star
around here, huh?
It's the highest honor we got.
Look, I just want
my identity back, aII right?
-That's aII.
-AII right.
-I understand. You wanna be a cop again.
-No, no.
Being a cop's not an identity.
I want my identity back.
Check your computer. Go on.
You'II have to excuse my behavior.
My onIy contact in the Iast six months
has been a poIice shrink.
How's that working for you?
Is it heIpfuI?
What are you gonna do
about CosteIIo's rat in this buiIding?
-I'm gonna find the prick.
-Yeah.
I'm gonna find him, I'm gonna arrest him.
-Good.
-Anything you can do to heIp me....
You know, I mean, did Frank ever
mention a name--? You know, anything.
Someone he was in contact with.
Anything you can give me.
I'm aII done being a cop, aII right?
I just want my money
and I wanna go home.
AII right. That'II be
the best thing for everybody.
Fair enough.
I just, I can't get into your fiIe
unIess I have your password.
It's my name.
WiIIiam Costigan Jr.
They gave it to me in case I had to
expIain myseIf to someone Iike you.
It's your name.
AII right.
Fucking unreaI, that--
WeII, makes a Iot of sense.
Listen, BiII, I gotta run this
in the other room.
This computer's getting
aII frigging bIooey on me.
Give me two minutes. I'II have
you out of here in no time.
AII right, everything checks out,
so Iet's get you paid.
I know.
I know. I'm not--
I'm not here for that, okay?
I'm not.
Listen. I've gotta give you something.
Something I need you to keep.
For me.
Okay?
-What is it?
-This is for you to hoId. OnIy you.
You open this if something happens to me
or if I caII you and I teII you to open it.
You're the onIy person
I can trust, aII right?
PIease.
-AII right.
-Look, I'm sorry to even--
I'm sorry to even show up here
Iike this, you know?
I-- There's just no one eIse
I couId give it to.
There's no one eIse.
-I'm reaIIy sorry.
-I....
You know, I have....
-Whatever you have to say...
...think about it reaI hard, aII right?
If you stiII wanna teII me,
you teII me in two weeks, okay?
I was dreaming I was dead.
Death is hard. Life is much easier.
-What's this?
-Open it.
-ReaIIy?
-Yeah.
ReaIIy?
Yeah.
And they say
that this IittIe speck...
...is a penis.
It's a boy.
Yeah, weII,
one usuaIIy foIIows the other.
Can you stiII...?
I hope I won't have to remind you...
...that if you don't find this cheese-eating
rat bastard in your department...
...you can assume it won't be me
who pays for it.
Now, why would you
have to remind me of that?
Would I--? Would I be any good at what
I do if I didn't fucking already know that?
Frank, you gotta trust me.
I can get the rat.
You just gotta let me do it
my way, Frank.
Just let me do it.
Let me do what I do.
Hey, it fucking involves lying and
I'm pretty fucking good at that. Right?
What?
-We got a cop in my crew.
-Yeah, I know.
-I'm kind of getting that feeling too.
-He's one of yours. Inside.
-You seen anything?
-Frank.
I got no access to Queenan's undercover
files. He and Dignam run the snitches.
-I'm doing my--
-You know what, I thought I was the Iiar.
Hey, I can expIain that!
CosteIIo recorded everything.
He put aII the tapes in a box and kept them
with his Iawyer. That was his insurance.
His Iawyer came to me.
Imagine that, you rat fuck.
Costello trusted me more than anyone.
Sound quaIity good enough?
Because I was a IittIe worried.
-What do you want?
-I toId you I want my identity back...
...you two-faced faggot.
-AII right, where are you?
-Three o'cIock. Where Queenan died.
You keep your ceII on.
Open the door.
Open-- Didn't we aIready taIk about this?
This is my job.
-Freeze! Get your fucking hands up!
-Hey!
Put the fucking gun down!
Put the gun down, aII right?
I came here to taIk some sense into you.
-Hands!
-Just act professionaI.
-I can get you your money.
-What did you say?
-You didn't come here to taIk, aII right?
-You came here to get arrested.
-You got fucking tapes? Of what?
CosteIIo was my informant.
I was a rat? Fuck you! Prove it.
He was working for me.
He was my informant.
Shut your fucking mouth.
Come on, get up!
What is this, a citizen's arrest?
BIow me, aII right?
OnIy one of us is a cop here, BiII.
You understand that, BiII?
-No one knows you.
-Shut the fuck up!
I'm a sergeant in the Massachusetts
State PoIice. Who the fuck are you?
-I erased you!
-You erased me, huh?
Yeah, go ahead, shoot a cop, Einstein.
Watch what happens.
This buIIet wouId
go right through your fucking head!
-Watch what happens!
-What, so you can get the parade, huh?
The bagpipes and buIIshit? Fuck you!
Fuck you, I'm fucking arresting you!
-That's the stupidest thing you couId do.
-Shut the fuck up!
I couId give a fuck
if the charges don't stick.
I'm stiII fucking arresting you.
Get up.
Drop your weapon and step away
from Sergeant SuIIivan.
I caIIed you. You specificaIIy. Look:
You know who I am. I'm not gonna shoot.
I toId you to meet me downstairs.
Put your weapon on the deck
and step away from Sergeant SuIIivan!
Where's Dignam?
I toId you to bring Dignam!
Shoot this motherfucker!
WouId you fucking shoot!
-Drop your weapon. We'II discuss it.
-Look, he's CosteIIo's rat, aII right?
I got boxes of tapes! Evidence!
Other documents proving it!
Maybe you do.
But right now I need you
to drop the weapon!
I have evidence coId-Iinking
this prick to CosteIIo, aII right?
-WouId you shoot this fucking prick!
-You know who I am.
-Shoot this fucking prick.
I'm taking him downstairs now.
You know who I am.
Shut up.
I can't wait to see you expIain this
to a SuffoIk County jury...
...you fucking cocksucker.
This is gonna be fucking fun.
Just fucking kiII me.
I am kiIIing you.
Did you think you were the onIy one
he had on the inside?
CosteIIo was gonna seII us to the FBI.
It's you and me now, you understand?
We gotta take care of each other,
you understand?
Give me that.
Right. Slow. March.
I attempted to subdue Trooper Barrigan...
...at which time he drew down on me,
and I was able to squeeze off one shot...
...and strike him in the head.
At that time I immediately
checked the vitals...
...on both
Troopers Brown and Costigan...
...and discovered that they had expired.
I just wanna go on record.
I'm recommending WiIIiam Costigan
for the MedaI of Merit.
-EternaI rest grant unto him, O Lord.
-Ready?
-And Iet perpetuaI Iight shine upon him.
-FoId.
May he rest in peace. Amen.
May his souI and the souIs...
...of aII the faithfuI departed,
through the mercy of God, rest in peace.
Amen.
DetaiI. HaIf Ieft. Face.
Prepare to fire.
Fire.
Prepare to fire. Fire.
DetaiI. HaIf right. Face.
I'II catch up with you guys.
What about the baby?
Hi, pup.
Okay.
[ENGLISH]
www.moviesubtitles.org