Subtitle created by - Aorion -
"The Martian (2015)" ^ (Run time : 02:16:00)
THE
MARTIAN
MARS
ACIDALIA PLANITIA
NASA -  ARES III - LANDING SITE
Alright team,
stay in sight of each other.
Let's make NASA proud today.
How's it looking over there, Watney?
Well, you'll be happy
to hear that in
grid section 14 to 28,
the particles were phenomenally coarse,
and on 29, they're....
they're much finer,
which should be ideal
for chemical analysis.
Oh, wow.
Did everybody hear that?
Mark just discovered dirt.
Should we alert the media?
It's alright.
What're you doing today, Martinez?
Making sure that the MAV
is still upright.
Well, I like you know that
visual inspection of the equipment
is imperative to mission success.
I also like to report
that the MAV is still upright.
Watney, you're keep leaving
your channel open,
which leads to Martinez responding,
which leads to all our listening,
which leads to me being annoyed.
Roger that.   Martinez, the captain
would like you to please...
shut your smart mouth.
We prefer to use a different adjective
to describe Martinez's mouth.
- Oh, did Beck just insult me?
- Dr. Beck, and, yes.
I'll be happy to turn the radios off
from here, commander.
Just say the word.
Hey, Johanssen.
Constant communication is the whole...
Shut him off.
Apologise for my countrymen, Vogel.
Accepted. How many samples
do we need, commander.
7,
a hundred grams each.
[ EMERGENCY ]
MISSION STATUS UPDATE
We have a mission update.
Storm warning.
Commander, you should come inside.
You're going to want to see this.
- What is it?
- Storm warning.
I saw that in this morning's briefing.
We'll be inside before it hits.
Yeah.
They-They upgraded their estimate.
The storm is going
to be a lot worse.
Martinez, how's it look?
Not good.
1200 km in diameter
bearing 24.41 degrees
That's trekking right towards us.
Base on current estimation,
estimated force of 8600 Newtons.
- What's the abort force.
- 7500.
Anything more than that
and the MAV will tip.
- Do we scrub.
- Begin abort procedure.
We are estimating where the marginal error
would be... could we wait it out?
Let's wait it out.
Commander.
Prep emergency departure.
- Commander.
- We're scrubbed, that's an order.
Martinez, how long before take off?
10 minutes.
Visibility is almost zero.
Anyone gets lost,
home in on my suit's telemetry.
- You ready?
- Ready!
- Commander, are you okay?
- I'm okay.
Commander, we're at 10 degrees,
and the MAV's going to tip at 12.3
Hey! We might be able to
keep the MAV from tipping.
How?
Use the cables from
the solar farm as guylines!
Anchor it with a Rover!
Watch out!
Aahhhhh!
Watney!
WARNING
SUIT BREACH DETECTED.
- What happened?
- He was hit.
Watney, report.
Before we lose telemetry,
his decompression alarm went off.
- Johanssen, where did you last see him?
- He's offline.
- I can't, I don't know where he is.
- What are the vitals on his suit.
- He's offline. He's offline.
- Negative. Complete lost of signal on Watney.
- Mitch?
- Yeah.
How long can he
survive decompression?
Less than a minute.
Line up.
Walk west.
He maybe prone,
we don't want to step over him.
Commander, we're at
10.5 degrees, tilting to 11.
We got a gust of wind.
Copy that.
Everyone, home in on Martinez's suit.
It'll get you to the airlock.
Get in, prep for launch.
What about you, commander?
I'm going to search a little longer.
Keep moving.
Go!
Watney.
Watney, report.
The MAV is at 11.6 degrees.
Once good gust and we're tipping.
If it tips, you launch.
You really think I'm
going to leave you behind?
That's an order, Martinez.
Mark!
Mark.
Can you hear me?
Martinez, what about the proximity radar?
Could that detect,
Watney's suit.
Uh. It's made to see
the Hermes in orbit,
not a little piece of metal
put in a single suit.
- Give it a try.
- Roger.
What is she thinking? She knows the
infrared can't get through a sand storm.
She is grasping for anything.
We got negative contact
on the proximity radar.
- Nothing?
- Nah.
I can barely see the Hab.
Commander, I know you
don't want to hear this but...
Mark is dead.
Commander.
Hey. What the hell is
wrong with you, man?
My friend just died, I don't want
my commander to die too.
[ STABILITY WARNING ]
-11.2  degrees
WE'LL COME BACK !
Commander, you need to
get back to the ship, now.
13 degrees.
If we past balance,
we'll never rock back.
I got one more trick left, and
then I'm following orders, commander.
You're firing the OMS?
That's right.
Commander!
On my way.
[ -12.9 degree -12.9 ]
Johanssen, let's go.
Mark.
We're 11.5 and holding.
Ready to go on your command.
Ready to launch.
Commander.
I need you to verbally
tell me whether or not to.
Launch.
At around 4:30 AM,
central standard time,
our satellites detected a storm
approaching the Ares 3
mission site on Mars.
At 6:45, the storm has
escalated to severe
and we have no choice
but to abort the mission.
Thanks to the quick action
of Captain Lewis,
astronaut Beck, Johanssen,
Martinez and Vogel
were all able to reach
the Mars ascend vehicle.
And performed an emergency launch
at 7:28 central time.
Unfortunately during the evacuation,
astronaut Mark Watney was
struck by debris and killed.
Commander Lewis and the rest of her team
were able to intercept safety
with the Hermes and
now are heading home.
But Mark Watney,
is dead.
- Mr. Sanders.
- Mr. Sanders!
OXYGEN LEVEL : CRITICAL
OXYGEN LEVEL : CRITI...
PRESSURE : STABLE
AWWWW!
Okay.
- Okay.
[MISSON DAY : SOL 19]
Hello, this is Mark Watney, astronaut.
I'm entering this log for the record,
because, in case I don't make it.
It is 06:53
on Sol 19, and
I'm alive.
Obviously.
But...
I'm guessing that's going to come as a
surprise to my crew mates and to NASA.
And to the entire world, really.
So...
Surprise.
I did not die on Sol 18 and
best I can figure.
This length of our primary
communication antenna broke off
and threw it through my bio-monitor.
and ripped a hole in me as well.
But the antenna
and the blood really
managed to seal the breach
in my suit which kept me alive,
even though the crew must
have thought I was dead.
I have no way to contact NASA.
And even if I could,
it's going to be...
4 years until a manned mission
can reach me.
And I'm in a Hab
designed to last 31 days.
If the oxygenator breaks,
I'm going to suffocate.
If the water reclaimer breaks,
I'll die of thirst.
If the Hab breaches,
I'm just kind of... implode.
And if by some miracle
none of that happens,
eventually I'm going to
run out of food.
So.
Yeah.
[hab]
I'm not going to die here.
SOL 21
32.
33.
34.
35, 36.
Sweet & Sour chicken.
[ VAC FLUSH ]
- Alright.  Let's do the math.
[SOL 21]
Our service mission here
was suppose to last
for 31 Sols. For redundancy
they sent 68 Sols worth of food,
that's for 6 people.
So for just me,
that's going to last 300 Sols.
Which I figure I could stretch
to 400 if I ration. So...
I got to figure out a way,
to grow
3 years worth of food here.
On a planet where nothing grows.
Luckily.
I'm a botanist.
And Mars,
will come to fear
my botany powers.
ORGANIC
WASTE
BIOHAZARD
HUMAN - WASTE
[ M. WATNEY ]
SOL 22
PRESSURE : STABLE
Staple came out.
SOL 24
Fuck you, Mars.
SOL 31
Johanssen, Jesus.
SOL 36
The problem is water.
I have created
126 square meters of soil.
And every cubic meter of soil
requires 48 liters of water
to be farm with.
So, I'm got to make
a lot more water.
Good thing is that I know the recipe.
- You take hydrogen, you add oxygen,
you burn them.
[ SOL 37 ]
Now, I have hundreds of liters
of unused hydrazine at the MDV.
I run the hydrazine
around an iridium catalyst
It will separate into N2 and H2.
And if I just direct the hydrogen
into a small area and burn it,
likely remake history of humanity.
Nothing bad has ever happened
from lighting hydrogen on fire.
NASA hates fire
because of the whole, fire makes
everybody die in space thing.
So, everything they sent us up here
with is flame retardant, with...
the notable exception of...
Martinez's personal items.
I'm sorry, Martinez, if you didn't
want me to go through your stuff,
you shouldn't left me for dead
on a desolate planet.
By the way, I'm figuring you're
going to be fine with this,
given my present situation.
Counting on you.
- So, yeah. I blew myself up.
[SOL 41]
- Best guess.
[Sol 41]
I forgot to...
account for the excess oxygen that...
I've been exhaling when
I did my calculations,
because I'm stupid.
Yeah, I'm going to
get back to work here,
just as soon as
my ear stop ringing.
Interesting side note, this is actually
how the jet propulsion lab was founded
5 guys at Caltec,
trying to make
rocket fuel and they nearly
burned down their dorm.
And rather than expel them,
banished them to a nearby farm
tell them to keep working.
And then we have a space program.
Okay.
[ SOL 44 ]
[ SOL 45 ]
[ SOL 46 ]
SOL 48
SOL 54
Hey, there.
The nation was blessed, to have
Mark serving in our space program.
While his lost will be deeply felt,
the men and women of NASA
will soldier forth,
onward and upward, in the
mission of their agency.
By doing so they honor the legacy
Mark's leaving behind.
To ensure his sacrifice
will not be in vain.
VINCENT KAPOOR
DIRECTOR OF MARS MISSIONS, NASA
I thought you gave a lovely speech,
by the way.
- I need you to authorize my satellite time.
- It's not going to happen.
We're funded for
5 ARES missions.
I think I can get congress
to authorize a 6th.
Look, ARES 3 evac'd after 18 Sols.
There's-There's half a mission
worth of supplies up there.
I can sell it at a fraction of
the cost of a normal mission.
And all I have to know is,
what's left of our asserts.
You're not the only one who
needs satellite time.
We got the ARES 4
supply missions coming up.
We should be focusing
on the Schiaparelli crater.
Okay, we got 12 satellites up there,
surely we can spare a few hours.
It's not about satellite time, Vince.
We're a public
domain organization.
- We need to be transparent on this.
- Okay.
The second we point
the satellites to the Hab,
I broadcast pictures of Mark Watney's
dead body to the world.
You're afraid of a PR problem?
Of course I'm afraid of a PR problem.
Another mission?
Congress won't reimburse
us for a paper clip
if I put a dead astronaut out on the
front page of the Washington Post.
He's not going anywhere, Teddy.
I mean, he's not...
he's not going to decompose.
You know, he's going to be
up there forever.
Meteorology estimates that
he'll be covered in sand
from normal weather activity
within a year.
We can't wait a year,
we got work to do.
ARES 5 won't even launch for 5 years,
we've plenty of time.
Okay.
Okay, consider this.
Right now,
the world is on our side.
Sympathy for the Watney family.
ARES 6 can bring his body home
Now. We don't say that's
the purpose of the mission,
but we make it clear
that would be a part of it.
If we frame it that way.
More support from congress,
but not if we wait a year.
We wait a year
nobody gives a shit.
MISSION CONTROL, NASA
JOHNSON SPACE CENTER, HOUSTON, TEXAS
01:30 AM
MINDY PARK
SATELLITE COMMUNICATIONS, NASA
INCOMING: VINCENT KAPOOR
MESSAGE
RECEIVED
Vincent Kapoor.
CHECK THESE COORDINATES:
LAT : 46°  42' 0"
LON : 22°  0'  0"
ACIDALIA PLANITIA
SOL 54
SOL 18
What?
Hi, security.
This is Mindy Park in SatCom.
I need the emergency contact
for Vincent Kapoor.
Yes, him.
Yes, it's an emergency.
02:30 AM
- How sure?
- A 100%
You got to be shitting me?
Prove it to me.
For a start.
Solar panels have been cleaned.
They could've been cleaned by wind.
Back it up.
Look at Rover 2.
According to the logs,
Command Lewis took it out, Sol 17,
plugged it into the Hab to recharge.
It's been moved.
She could have forgotten
to log the move.
No.
Not likely.
Why don't we just ask Lewis.
Let's get on CAPCOM and
ask her directly right now.
No, no.
If Watney is really alive,
we don't want the
ARES 3 crew to know.
How-How can you not tell them?
They have another 10 months
on their trip home.
Space travel is dangerous, they
need to be alert and undistracted.
But, they already think he's dead.
And they'd be devastated to
find out they left him there alive.
I'm sorry but you have not
thought this through.
I mean, what-
what are we going to say?
Dear America, remember that astronaut
we killed and had a really nice funeral for?
Turns out he's alive,
and we left him on Mars.
Our bad,
sincerely NASA.
I mean, do you realise the
shit storm that's about to hit us?
How're we going to
handle the public.
Legally, we have 24 hours
to release these pictures.
We release a statement with them.
We don't want people
working it out on their own.
Yes, sir.
Look, if my math is right,
he's going to starve to death
long before we can help him.
You can't imagine what
he is going through up there.
I mean, he's 50 million miles
away from home.
He thinks he's totally alone.
He thinks we gave up on him.
And what does that do
to a man, psychologically?
What the hell is he thinking right now?
[ SOL 54 ]
I'm definitely
going to die out here.
If I have to listen to anymore
goth hop disco music.
My god, Commander Lewis, couldn't you
have packed anything from this century?
No, I'm not.
I'm not going to turn the beat around.
I refuse to.
What attempts have been made
to make contact with Mark Watney?
We're working on it.
Does he have enough
supplies to survive?
We'll be looking into that.
What does this say about the agency?
Are you going to resign?
No.
Dr. Sanders...
SOL 70
It's time to start
thinking long term.
The next NASA mission is ARES 4
and it's suppose to land
at Schiaparelli crater,
3200 km away.
hundred kilometers.
In 4 years, when the
next ARES crew arrives,
I'll have to be there.
Which means I have to
get to the crater.
Okay, so here's the rub.
I've got 1 working Rover, designed
to go a max distance 35 km.
Before the battery has to be
recharge at the Hab.
That's problem A.
Problem B, is this journey is going to
take me roughly 50 days to complete.
So, I got to live for 50 days
inside a Rover with marginal
life support, the size of a small van.
- So.
[ SOL 71 ]
In the face of overwhelming odds,
I'm left with only 1 option.
I'm going to have to science
the shit out of this.
[ SOL 74 ]
Okay.
So, a success.
I've double battery life,
by scavenging Rove 1.
But, if I use the heater,
I will burn through half
of my battery every day.
If I do not use my heater,
I will be...
slowly killed
by the laws of Thermodynamics.
I would love to solve
this problem right now, but...
unfortunately,
my balls are frozen.
I can't.
I'm calling it. I'm calling it.
Good news, I may have a solution
to my heating problem.
Bad news, it involves me digging up the
radioisotope thermoelectric generator.
Now, if I remember my training correctly,
One of the lessons was titled:
Don't dig up the big box
of plutonium, Mark.
I get it, RTGs are good for spacecraft,
But if they rupture around humans,
no more gamelies.
Which is why buried it
when we arrived.
And planted that flag,
so we can never be stupid enough
to accidentally go near it again.
But, as long as
I don't break it,
Elmo did said 'Everything will be fine.',
out loud.
Look, the point is,
I'm not cold anymore.
And sure, I could choose to
think about the fact that I'm...
warm because I have a decaying radioactive
isotope riding right behind me,
But right now I got
bigger problems on my hands.
I've showered every single data file
on Commander Lewis personal drive.
This is officially the least
disco song she owns.
[ SOL 76 ]
Where is Watney going?
Well, we think he is
preparing for a journey.
He's been conducting
equal amount of test .
Taking the Rover 2 out for
longer and longer trips each time.
To what end? Why would he
leave relative safety of the Hab?
Well, we think he plans to travel
to the Ares 4 launch site
in order to make contact with us,
but it would be a dangerous gamble.
But, if we could talk to him,
we would tell him to stay put
And to trust that we're doing everything
in our power to bring him home alive.
Thank you very much.
Don't say
'Bring him home alive', Vincent.
You know what,
these interviews aren't easy.
God forbid, I try to say something
proactive and positive.
Annie!
No more Vincent on TV.
Copy that.
76 kilometers.
Am I reading that right?
Are you asking me?
I am.
Yes, sir.
Mark drove 2 hours straight
away from the Hab,
Did a short EVA and then
drove for another 2.
We think the EVA
was to change batteries.
He didn't load up the oxygenator
or the water reclaimer?
Every 41 hours,
there is a 17 minute gap.
It's just the way the orbits works,
so...
it's possible that
we missed something.
I want that gap down
to 4 minutes?
I'm giving you total authority over
satellite trajectories and orbital adjustments.
Make it happen.
Okay.
Let's assume Ms. Park
didn't miss anything,
So, Mark is not going
to Ares 4, yet,
But he's smart enough to
figure out that is his only chance.
Bruce, what's the earliest
we can get a pre-supply there?
Well, with the positions
of the Earth and Mars,
- It'll take 9 months.
BRUCE NG Director, Jet Propulsion Laboratory
And it'll takes 6 months
to build them in the first place.
3 months.
3?
You're going to say it's impossible,
and them I'm going to make a speech
about the abiding capabilities
of the JPL team,
And then you're going to do the math
in your head, And say something
like,  "The overtime alone
would be a nightmare."
The overtime alone
would be a nightmare.
Get started.
I'll find you the money.
- We need to tell the crew.
MITCH Henderson,  HERMES FLIGHT DIRECTOR, NASA
- Mitch, we've discussed this.
- No, you discussed this.
I'm the one who decides
what's best for the crew.
They deserve to know.
Once there's a real rescue plan,
we'll tell them.
Otherwise, it's moot.
Bruce has 3 months to get
the payload done.
That's all that matters right now.
We will do our best.
Mark dies if you don't.
SOL 79
It's been 48 Sols since
I planted the potatoes, so...
Now it's time to
reap and re-sow.
They grew even better
than I expected.
I now have 400 healthy potato plants.
I dug them up being careful
to leave their plants alive.
The smaller ones are reseed,
the larger ones are my food supply.
Are natural, organic,
Martian grown potatoes.
You don't hear that everyday, do you?
And by the way,
none of this matter at all
If I can't figure out a way
to make contact with NASA.
CHRYSE PLANITIA
[ SOL 79 ]
I know what I'm going to do.
Oh, he's moving again.
Where the hell is he going?
He hasn't change course for 13 days.
He's no where near the Ares 4.
Problem is he's not
taking a direct route.
I mean, he might be trying
to avoid some obstacle.
What obstacle?
It's Acidalia Planitia.
There is nothing out there except the...
What?
I need a map.
Yeah.
Hey. Come on, man.
What's are you doing?
It's alright. It's alright.
Can I borrow this?
Okay.
So, where's the Hab location?
31.2° north,
28.5° West.
Okay.
And, where is Watney?
Here.
Okay, okay.
Okay.
I know where he's going.
I need to get on an airplane.
[ SOL 94 ]
JPL
Jet Propulsion Laboratory
Hi.
Please follow me.
The Jet Propulsion Laboratory
PASADENA, California
- How are you, Vincent?
- Bruce.
Good flight?
Yeah.
It's in storage,
just around the corner.
Vincent, nice to see you.
Nice to see you.
What are the chances of Mark
to get it working again?
It's hard to say.
We lost contact in 1997.
We think it was battery failure.
But I like to point out, it last
3 times longer than we expected.
Nobody is criticizing JPL's work
I just need to speak with
everybody who was here in 97.
Don't worry, they're here.
Guys.
I would like to introduce, Vincent Kapoor,
Director of the Mars missions, NASA.
This is our current team,
- and original project members.
- How ya doing? Alright?
- Is this the replica.
- This is her.
Okay.
Let's see it.
Pathfinder.
SOL 109
Come on.
Holy shit.
Okay.
Broadcasting Status.
Listening for telemetry signal.
Okay.
Signal acquired.
- Alright.
- Okay.
Camera.
Incoming.
Are you receiving me?
Yes.
No.
Okay.
Point the camera, yes.
32 minutes round trip
communication time.
All he can do is ask,
yes, no, questions.
All we can do is to
point the camera.
This wasn't exactly
what we might have gone,
- Are you kidding me?
- Tim. Tim.
- Just point the camera.
- Roger that.
Pointing the camera.
Yes!
So, here's the rub.
[ SOL 109 ]
Somehow, we have to have complex
astrophysical engineering conversations .
Using nothing but a still
frame camera, from 1996.
Luckily
The camera does spin.
So, I can make an alphabet.
It can't be our alphabet.
26 characters plus a question card
and a 360 gives us 13 degrees of arc.
That's way too narrow. I'll never know
where the camera is pointing at.
Hexadecimal.
Hexadecimal to the rescue.
I figured one of you guys who
kept an ASCII table lying around,
I was right.
Ladies and Gentlemen,
I give you Super nerd, Beth Johanssen.
Who also have copies of Zork II
and Leather Goddesses of Phobos
on her personal laptop.
Seriously, Johanssen.
Who thought this Miss Sonian of loneliness,
Not that I'm complaining.
Yes!
Who am I to talk about loneliness?
I know where
he's going with this.
Alright
F, O.
7, W.
HOW ALIVE?
Vincent.
Wake up.
I'M OKAY
IMPALED BY ANTENNA
BIOMONITOR DESTROYED
CREW HAD REASON TO
THINK ME DEAD
NOT THEIR FAULT
Now that we can have more
complicated conversations,
The smart people at NASA have sent me
instructions on how to hack a Rover
so that it can talk to Pathfinder.
If I hack, a tiny bit of code,
just 20 instructions
in the Rover's operating system,
NASA can link the Rover to Pathfinder's
broadcasting frequency
and we're in business.
Mark,
this is Vincent Kapoor.
We've been watching you since SOL54.
The whole world is rooting for you.
Amazing job, getting Pathfinder.
We're working on rescue plans.
Meantime, we're putting together a supply mission
to keep you fed
until Ares 4 arrives.
Glad to hear it.
Okay.
Really looking forward to not dying.
- Oh.
- Whoa.
Yeah.
How's the crew?
What did they say when
they found out I was alive?
RU receiving? Mark.
Guys, can we get some space, please.
- Me?
- Yeah, you.
Just give me a second.
You should tell him.
We haven't told the crew
you are alive yet.
We need them to concentrate
on the mission.
(What?)
(What the fuck!)
He says.
They don't know I'm alive?
What the F word.
F word in gerund form.
F word again, what's wrong with you?
Mark, please watch your language.
Everything you type is being
broadcast live all over the world.
Yeah?
Oh, my God.
Yes, sir. He's under a
tremendous amount of stress.
I understand.
We're working on it.
I'm sure he didn't mean
what he said.
Thank you, Mr. President.
Problem is, Mark's right.
The longer we wait,
The worse it's going to get.
We need to tell the crew.
You're bringing this up while
Vincent is in Pasadena
so he can't argue the other side.
I shouldn't have to
answer to Vincent.
Or anyone else.
It's time, Teddy.
THE HERMES
4 MONTHS SINCE MARS DEPARTURE
Captain Lewis?
Go ahead.
Data dump is almost complete.
Copy that.
On my way.
You're in a hurry.
Yeah.
My son turned 3 yesterday.
Should be pictures of the party.
Got a batch of personals.
Dispatching them to your laptop now.
I don't mean to read, Vogel,
weird German fetish e-mails.
They're telemetry updates.
Hey, whatever does it for you, man.
TO : ALL CREW
VIDEO FILE : RECEIVED
Oh, there's a video message.
It's-It's address to the whole crew.
Play it.
Come on, guys.
I want to get in on that
that telemetry action.
Hi, hello.
It's Mitch, Mitch Henderson.
I have some news.
There's no subtle way to put this.
Mark Watney is still alive.
Oh my God.
I know that's a surprise,
I know you'll have lots of questions,
But here are the basics.
He's alive and
he's healthy.
We... We found out 2 months ago
and... decided not to tell you.
- What?
- 2 months?
Oh my god.
I was strongly against that decision.
We are telling you now, because...
we finally have communication with him.
and a viable rescue plan.
We'll get you a write up of what happened.
A full write up of everything.
But it's not your fault.
Mark stresses that
everytime it comes up.
So...
Yeah.
Take some time to absorb this.
And... send all the questions
you want, we'll answer.
Alright, Henderson out.
Holy shit.
He's alive.
I left him behind.
- No.
We all left together.
You were following orders.
I left him behind.
SOL 128
So, now that NASA can talk to me,
they won't shut up.
They want constant updates
on every Hab system,
and they've a room full of people
trying to micromanage my crops.
Which is awesome.
Look, I mean, I don't mean
to sound arrogant or anything,
But I am the greatest botanist
on this planet, so...
Oh, one big bonus to this
communication with NASA again
is the e-mail,
I'm getting them again.
A big data dump.
It's like when I was on the Hermes.
I even got one
from the President.
The coolest one now.
The coolest one I got
was from the University of Chicago,
where I Alma mater.
They said that,
once you grow crops somewhere,
You officially "colonized" it.
So, technically,
I colonized Mars.
In your face, Neil Armstrong.
Oh, another news.
There's been a request
for me to post for a photograph
on my next transmission.
I am trying to figure out whether
I should go with high school senior,
or ingenue.
But, I'm not really sure how it's
going to look with my spacesuit on.
Yeahhh.
What's he doing?
I ask for a photo,
and what, he's the the Fonz?
Just be grateful we got
you something, Annie.
I can't use this, Vincent,
and you know that.
I need a picture of his face.
Well, I can tell him
to take off his helmet,
But then he,
you know, die.
So.
We'll release the photo and
we'll detail the rescue operation.
I want to announce we're launching
some supplies to him next year
during the Hohmann Transfer Window.
Bruce, your team still on schedule?
It will be tight, but
we'll make it.
9 months travel time, that puts
the probe to Mars on Sol 868.
Did we get the
Botany team's analysis?
Yeah. They estimate
Mark's crops will last till Sol 912.
They grudgingly admit that
he's-he's doing a great work.
Grudgingly?
Well, yeah. Mark has the tendency to tell
them to have sex with themselves
whenever they question one of his decisions.
Get him online, Vincent.
We can't afford any miscommunication.
I hate this margin.
912 Sols worth of food,
we get there in 868.
That's assuming nothing goes wrong.
[SOL 134]
[ MALFUNCTION ]
Aw!
Aww!
SUIT BREACH DETECTED
OXYGEN LEVEL CRITICAL
14.0 %
OXYGEN
13.5 %
OXYGEN LEVEL : 10%
OXYGEN LEVEL : 5%
SUIT PRESSURE STABLE
PRESSURE STABLE.
GONE!
Gone, gone, gone, gone!
Crops are dead.
Complete loss of pressure
boiled off most of the water.
Any bacteria that survived died
in the subzero temperatures
when exposed to Mar's atmosphere.
How long has he have?
Oh. He can still eat the potatoes he has,
he just can't grow anymore, so...
Give him... 200 Sols.
Rations give him to what?
Sol 409?
So, with potatoes, 609.
So, by Sol 868,
he'll be long dead.
We're going to have to launch
as soon as possible,
which changes our travel time.
Yeah, we're working on it.
Preliminary estimates
call for a 414 day trip.
It's Sol 135 now.
We need 13 days to mount
the boosters, perform inspections
which gives Bruce and his team
47 days to make this probe.
I'll let you call Bruce.
Give him the news.
Okay.
I'm...  I'm going to need
a change of clothes.
SOL 136
Dear Mark,
Apparently,
NASA's letting us talk to you now.
And I,
drew the short straw.
Sorry we left you behind on Mars,
but we just don't like you.
Also, it's a lot roomier
on the Hermes without you.
We have to take turns
doing your tasks,
but, I mean,
it's only botany.
It's (not real science.)
Oh, Jesus.
How's Mars?
Dear Martinez, Mars is fine.
I accidentally blew up the Hab,
but unfortunately all of Commander Lewis'
disco music still survived.
Every day I go outside
and look at the vast horizons.
Just because I can.
Tell the others I said hello.
Will do, buddy.
PRESSURE STABLE.
5, 10,
15, 20, 30, 35,
40.
52.
JET PROPULSION LABORATORY
PASADENA, CALIFORNIA
Rich.
Wake up.
RICH PURNELL
ASTRODYNAMICS
Sorry, but they're asking
for the probe courses.
What time is it?
It's... 03:42
I know we're coming
at this backwards,
but we can't commit to a firm
launch date with so many unknowns.
It's alright.
All 25 models for launch will take
414 days to reach the Mars.
They varies slightly in
thrust duration and
fuel requirement isn't nearly as identical.
Not a good time to launch, is it?
Yeah. Earth and Mars
are really badly positioned.
Heck, it'd almost be easier if you...
Almost easier to what?
I need more coffee.
- Are you alright?
- It's fine.
Almost easier to what?
You do understand
I'm your boss, right?
Uh-huh.
Let's ask the very very
expensive question.
Is the probe going
to be ready on time?
- We are behind.
- Give me a number.
15 days.
15 days and I can get it done.
Alright, let's create 15 days.
13 days to mount the probe.
Can we reduce?
It actually takes 3 days
to mount the probe.
And we can get it
down to 2, right?
I can get it down to 2.
10 days are for
tests and inspections.
How often do those inspections
reveal a problem?
Are you suggesting we
don't do the inspections?
Right now, I'm asking how often
they reveal a problem?
1 in 20.
But that's grounds
for countdown halt.
We can't take that chance.
Anyone else know a safer way
to buy more time?
Dr. Keller, stretch Watney's
rations 4 more days.
He's not going to like it,
but that will get us to 15.
- And we'll cancel the inspections.
-Teddy.
- Sir, If that ever got out.
- It's on me.
You got your 2 weeks.
Get it done!
So, now, I have to hold out until
the probe gets here with more food.
You want to see what
minimum calorie count looks like?
Standard issue ration.
But instead of 3 of these
every 1 day,
I'm now eating 1 of these
every 3 days.
And now they've asked me...
to do that.
[SOL 154]
The point is,
stretch the rations 4 more days.
These are real dick punch.
I'm...
I'm going to dip this potato
in some crashed vitacarn.
And there's nobody
who can stop me.
It has been 7 days
since I ran out of ketchup.
JET PROPULSION LABORATORY
IRIS PROBE
4 WEEKS LATER
Up.
Up, up.
Come up here.
.
CAPE CANAVERAL
IRIS PROBE LAUNCH
This is the Flight Director = (Flight).
Begin launch status check.
Roger that, Flight.
Beginning launch status check.
Do you believe in god, Vincent?
Yeah.
Well. My father was a Hindu,
My mother's a Baptist, so, yeah.
I believe in several.
We'll take all the help
we can get.
Launch status check complete.
This is Flight.
We are go for launch.
Proceed with the count.
10.
9,  8,
7, 6,
Main engines start.
4, 3,
- 2,
- Ignition.
1.
Liftoff.
Good thrust.
Performance is normal.
The payload is giving good data.
She's rock solid at this point, Flight.
TVC looks good.
- My god.
- Yes!
- Yoo hoo!
- Yeah.
We have an extra TDCS duration.
We're getting a little shimmy, Flight.
Say again?
We're getting a very large precession.
Are we good?
Flight, it's hitting the red line.
Spinning on the long axis
with a 17° precession.
Launch, what's happening?
Force on Iris is at 7 g's.
We've lost the readings
on the probe, Flight.
- Oh.
- Oh!
- Oh, Jesus Christ.
- Jesus.
We lost it, Flight.
SatCon?
No satellite acquisition of signal.
LOS.
LOS here too.
US Destroyer, Stockton,
Reporting debris falling from the sky.
Everyone in the LCC
maintain your positions.
GC.
Lock the doors.
HOW'D THE LAUNCH GO?
WATNEY
SOL 186
Commander Lewis,
I may need you to do
something for me.
If I die, I need you to
check in with my parents.
They will want to hear all about
our time here on Mars.
I know that sucks,
and it will be hard
talking to a couple
about their dead son.
It's a lot to ask.
Which is why I'm asking you.
I'm not giving up.
I just need to
prepare for every outcome.
Please tell them.
Tell them
I love what I do,
And I'm really good at it.
And I'm dying
for something big
and beautiful,
and greater than me.
Tell them I said
I can live with that.
And tell them,
thank for being my mom and dad.
CNSA - CHINA NATIONAL SPACE ADMINISTRATION
BEIJING
We substituted protein cubes
with the standard rations.
The thrust of the launch combine with the
simultaneous lateral vibration
liquified the cubes and
created an imbalance load.
Vincent, why wasn't this address
from the inspection phase?
In order to make our launch window,
we were forced to accelerate our schedule.
Their astronaut is going
to die from hunger.
GUO MING
CHIEF SCIENTIST, CNSA
Of course.
There are other ways.
ZHU TOO
DEPUTY CHIEF SCIENTIST, CNSA
Our engineers have ran the numbers
of the Taiyang Shen's boosters.
It has the fuel capacity
to reach Mars orbit.
Why didn't NASA approach us?
Because they don't know.
Our data is classified information.
That's to say.
If we do nothing...
The world will never knew,
actually we could have helped.
So.
For the sake of argument,
let's say we decided to help them.
We give them the boosters, that means the
cancellation of Taiyang Shen's program.
Then let us, from Aerospace point of view,
try to solve this problem.
Find a way to cooperate.
Yes.
Yes, I understand.
Thank you.
Yes!
Alright!
Thanks to my uncle Tommy in China,
We got another chance at this.
Now we finished
the Iris probe in 62 days,
we're now going to
attempt to finish it in 28.
PLEIADES
NASA ADVANCED SUPERCOMPUTER
CALCULATIONS
CORRECT
We can jettison
any kind of landing systems.
We're sending only rations.
We can crash land on Mars.
You should hang up the phone.
- I'm sorry, who are you?
- My name is Rich Purnell.
I work in Astrodynamics, and you
should hang up the phone, right now.
Alright.
I'm going to call you back.
I know how to save Mark Watney.
Your probe plan won't work.
Too many things can go wrong.
I got a better way.
- Astrodynamics?
- Yeah.
What the hell is Project Elrond?
I had to make something up.
Yeah, but, Elrond?
Because it's a secret meeting.
How do you know that?
Why does Elrond mean secret meeting?
The Council of Elrond.
It's from the "Lord Of The Rings."
- It's the meeting where they
- The Lord Of The Rings.
decide to destroy the One ring.
If we are going to call
something Project Elrond,
I would like my codename
to be Glorfindel.
Okay.
I hate everyone of you.
Wait, Teddy doesn't even
know about this yet?
I'm sorry.
Who are you?
This is Rich Purnell,
Astrodynamics.
Tell them what you just told me.
I can get the Hermes
back to Mars by Sol 561.
How?
Would you stand right there
for me, please?
Thanks.
Right there, great.
And could you, stand right there?
Right there.
Okay. Let's pretend that this stapler
is the Hermes,
And you are...
I'm sorry.
What's your name again?
Teddy.
I'm the director of NASA.
Cool.
Teddy, you're Earth.
And right now, the Hermes
is heading towards you,
starting it's month long
deceleration intercept,
but instead,
what I'm proposing is,
It start accelerating immediately,
to preserve and gain even more.
We don't intercept with Earth at all,
but we come close enough...
to get a gravity assist
and adjust course.
While we're doing that,
- we resupply with the probe.
- The Taiyang Shen.
Pick up whatever
provisions we need.
And now we accelerating towards Mars.
You're Mars.
Now, we are going too fast
at this point to fall into orbit, but...
we can do a flyby.
What good is a flyby if you
can't get Watney off the surface?
Watney would
intercept using  the MAV.
Ow.
And then they'll just head home.
I done the math.
It checks out.
- Rich.
- Yes, sir.
- Get out.
- Alright.
- Is he right?
- Yep.
Bruce, what do you think?
Well, If Vincent say so.
- We need to use the Taiyang Shen?
- Uh-huh.
Wha-What am I missing?
Why is that important?
Because we can only do one.
Send Watney enough food
to last till Ares 4,
or send Hermes back
to get him right now.
Both plans require the Taiyang Shen.
So, we have to choose.
But, what about the Hermes' crew?
It would be asking them, to add
533 extra days to their mission.
And they wouldn't hesitate,
not for a second.
Can the Hermes function for 533 days
beyond the scheduled mission?
Should.
Built to last the full Ares mission.
So, technically, it's only
half way through it's lifespan.
- But, if something goes wrong.
- Then, we lose the crew.
So, what? We, either have a
high chance of killing 1 person, or
low chance of killing 6 people.
How do we make that decision?
We don't have to make it, Bruce.
He does.
Yeah.
But, bullshit.
Should be Commander Lewis' call.
We still have a chance to bring
5 astronauts home safe and sound.
I'm not risking their lives.
Let them make that decision.
Mitch, we're going with option 1.
You god damn coward.
- Johanssen?
- Yeah.
I know it's your private time.
Can I bother you for a second?
Yeah, go ahead.
- Where are you?
- The gym.
What's up?
I just got an e-mail from my wife,
and the subject line says, "our children."
My computer won't open
the attachment.
Okay.
Let's take a look.
Let's see.
This isn't a jpeg.
It's a-It's a plain ASCII text file.
I don't really know what
we're looking at. It's...
That make any sense to you?
Rich Purnell maneuver.
It's a course maneuver
for the Hermes.
My god.
The mission concludes with
Earth intercept 211 days later.
Would it work?
We ran the numbers.
They checked out.
It's a brilliant course.
So, why all the cloak and dagger?
Because it goes directly
against NASA's decision.
Yeah. If we do the maneuver, they have
to send the supply ship or we die.
We have the opportunity
to force their hand.
So, are we going to do?
If it's up to me,
we'll already be on our way.
But it is, no, isn't it?
Up to you?
Not this time.
This is something NASA
expressly rejected.
We're talking about mutiny here,
which is not a word that I take lightly
So, we do this together,
or not at all.
And, before you answer,
consider the consequences.
If we mess up the
supply rendezvous, we die.
Earth gravity assist, we die.
If we do everything perfectly,
We add 533 days to our mission.
533 more days,
before we see our families again.
533 days of unplanned space travel
where anything can go wrong.
If it's mission critical, we die.
Sign me up.
Alright, cowboy, slow down.
You and I, we're military.
Chances are, we go home,
they'll court martial us.
- Oh yeah, there's that.
- And for the rest of you guys,
I guarantee they will never
send you back up here again.
Good. So, if we go for it,
how would it work?
I'll plot the course and execute it.
Remote override.
They can take over the Hermes
from Mission Control.
Can you disable it?
Hermes has 4 redundant
flight computers,
each connected to
3 redundant comm systems.
We can't shut down the comms,
because we'll lose telemetry and guidance.
And we can't shut down the computers,
because we need to run the ship.
I'll have to disable remote override
on each system.
It's part of the OS,
I have to jump over the code.
Okay, but like in English,
like what would that mean?
I can do it.
Great.
But, it has to be unanimous.
If we do this, it will be
over 900 days of space.
It's more than enough space
for 1 life, so...
Yes.
I vote yes.
Let's go get him.
Johanssen?
Yes.
- Yeah.
- Yeah!
Got an unscheduled status update
from Hermes.
Roger, read it out.
Message reads:
'Houston, please be advised:
Rich Purnell is a
steely-eyed missile man.'
What?
Flight, Guidance.
Hermes is off course.
CAPCOM, advise Hermes they're drifting.
Guidance, get a correction ready.
Negative, Flight. It's not adrift.
They adjusted course.
What the hell?
Telemetry, any chance this is
instrumentation failure?
Negative, Flight.
Guidance, work out how long they can
stay on this course before it's irreversible?
Working on that now, Flight.
Who's Rich Purnell?
I don't know.
And somebody find out
who the hell  Rich Purnell is!
Annie will go before
the media this morning
and inform them of NASA's decision
to reroute the Hermes to Mars.
Sounds like a smart move.
Considering the circumstances.
Whoever gave them the maneuver,
only passed along information.
The crew made the
decision on their own.
You may have killed them, Mitch.
We're fighting the same war.
Every time something goes wrong,
the world forgets why we fly.
I'm trying to keep us airborne.
It's bigger than 1 person.
No.
It's not.
When this is over,
I'll expect your resignation.
I understand.
Bring our astronauts home.
SOL 219
Okay. Every Ares mission requires
3 years of pre-supplies.
So NASA decided a long time ago
it's a lot easier to
send some of this stuff beforehand
rather than bring it with us.
So, as a result,
the MAV for Ares 4
is already there, at the
Schiaparelli Crater, just waiting.
So, the plan is for me
to use that to go into orbit
just as the Hermes is passing,
And I guess they catch me
in space.
So, I've got 200 Sols
to figure out
how to take everything here
that keeping me alive:
The oxygenator, the water reclaimer,
the atmospheric regulator.
Bring that all with me.
And luckily I have the-
the greatest minds on planet Earth,
really, all of the brain power
of the entire planet,
helping me with this endeavor.
And so far they've come up with,
"Hey, why don't you drill holes
in the roof of your Rover
and hit it as hard as you
can with a rock."
We're going to get there.
[SOL 220]
Identification.
Goodbye
Mars
533 days longer?
And you said yes to this?
He would have done the same for me.
You know that.
Cheese.
Cheese. Cheese.
He didn't do cheese.
Did he do cheese?
Hey, baby.
- Hey.
- I got something for you.
I found it in a flea market.
Original pressing.
No.
[ABBA GREATEST HITS]
Not a scratch.
I love it.
With all due respect to your
CNSA protocols ,
but-but we haven't done things that way
since-since... Apollo 9.
- Did he get that?
- (Do you understand?)
Ignition.
[SOL 227]
7 MONTHS AFTER
SOL 461
I've thinking about laws on Mars.
There's an international treaty
saying no country can lay claim
to anything that is not on Earth.
And by another treaty,,
if you're not in any countries territory,
Maritime law applies.
So, Mars is "international waters."
Now, NASA is an American
nonmilitary organization,
it owns the hab.
But, the second I walk outside,
I'm in international waters.
So, here's the cool part.
I'm about to leave for
the Schiaparelli crater
where I'm going to
commandeer the Ares 4 Lander.
Nobody explicitly gave me
permission to this,
and they can't until
I'm on board the Ares 4.
So, that means I'm going to be
taking over a craft over in
international waters without permission.
Which, by definition,
makes me a pirate.
- Mark Watney, space pirate.
[SOL 461]
systems shutdown
shutdown complete
Space pirate.
Wherever I go,
I'm the first.
It's a strange feeling.
Step outside the Rover,
first guy to be there.
Climb that hill,
first guy to do that.
4.5 billion years,
nobody here.
And now, me.
I'm the first person to be alone
on an entire planet.
How's he doing?
So far so good.
He's... sticking to schedule.
Directs for 4 hours before noon,
Lays the solar panels, waits
13 hours for them to recharge,
and sleeps somewhere in there
and then, starts again.
How's he doing?
He asked us to call him,
Captain Longbeard.
Well, technically, Mars would be
under maritime laws.
I know, I know.
He explained it to us.
Where is he?
- Here.
- Okay.
Here.
Okay.
SOL 494
SOL 517
Okay, we're going to
start by stating,
for the record, that
you're not going to like this.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah. The problem is
the intercept velocity.
The Hermes. Well, they,
it can't enter Mars orbit.
Otherwise, they will never have
enough fuel to, make it home.
The MAV was only designed
to get to low Mars orbit.
So, in order for Mark to escape
Mars gravity entirely,
and to intercept the Hermes...
- He has to be going fast.
- Exactly.
Which means we need to
make the MAV lighter.
A lot lighter.
5000 kg lighter.
But, you can do that, right?
Well, there's some gimmes
right off the bat.
The design presumes 500 kg
of Martian soil and samples.
Obviously we won't do that.
And there's just 1 passenger
instead of 6.
With suits and gear,
that's another 500?
Ditch the support of life.
We don't need it.
And I'm going to make Mark to wear
his EVA suit for the whole trip.
Wait a second! If he's in his EVA suit,
How's he going to operate the controls?
Well, he won't.
Martinez will pilot the MAV
remotely from the Hermes.
We've never had a manned ship
controlled remotely before.
But I am excited about the
opportunities that I forged.
If we go remote, we can lose the control panels,
the secondary, tertiary comm systems.
Wait. Wait a second.
You want to what?
You want to remotely controlled
ascent with no backup comms?
He's not even got to the
bad stuff yet, Vincent.
Well, let's get to the bad stuff!
We need to remove the nose airlock,
the windows and Hull Panel 19.
You want to take
the front of the ship off?
Sure.
The nose airlock alone is 400 kg.
You want to send a man into space
without the front of his ship?
Well, no.
We're going to have him
cover it with Hab canvas.
The hull's mostly there
to keep the air.
Mars atmosphere is so thin,
you don't need a lot of streamlining.
By the time the ship's going fast enough
for air resistance to matter,
it'll be high enough
that there's practically no air.
You want to send him
into space under a tarp.
Yes.
Can I go on?
No.
Are you f---ing kidding me?
You think he means it like,
Are you kidding me?
- You know?
- Um-hum.
Or like,
"Are you kidding me?"
I think it might be
the second one.
- Really?
- Uh-huh.
Could be the first one.
Are you kidding me?
Yeah, it could be the first one.
SOL 538
SCHIAPARELLI CRATER
Ares 4 LANDING SITE
I know what they are doing.
I know exactly what they are doing.
'Cause they're keep repeating,
Go faster than any man
in the history of space travel.
Like that's a good thing.
Like it would distract me
from how insane their plan is.
Yeah. I get to go faster than any man
in the history of space travel.
Because you're launching me
in a convertible.
Actually, it's worse than that, because
I won't be able to control that thing.
And by the way, physicists,
when describing things like acceleration,
do not use the word 'fast'.
So...
They're doing that, in the hopes
that I won't raise any objections.
It's a lunacy.
You think, because I like the way,
'The fastest man in the history of
space travel.' sounds.
I do like the way it sounds.
Yeah, I like it a lot.
I'm not going to
tell them that.
Okay.
Let's do this.
Come on.
[EJECT]
(400 kg nose airlock?)
Beck and Vogel. I want
you guys in airlock 2.
With the outer door open
before the MAV even launches.
Okay.
Martinez flies the MAV,
Johanssen sysop the ascent.
Once we hit intercept,
it's Beck's job to go get Watney.
We're ready.
What's the intercept plan?
We finished attaching
the tethers into 1 long line
It's 214 meters long.
And I'll have the MMU, so
moving around should be easy.
How fast a relative velocity
can you handle?
I can grab the MAV at
5 meters per second.
Ten is like jumping onto a moving train.
So, any more than that,
I might miss.
Well, we may have some leeway.
The launch takes 12 minutes,
and it will be 52 minutes
before intercept.
Once Mark's engines shut off,
we'll know our
intercept point and velocity.
Vogel, you're Beck's backup.
Everything goes well, you pull them
on board with the tether.
If anything goes wrong,
you go out after him.
Yep.
Okay.
Let's go get our boy.
SOL 561
To whom it may concern,
take care of this Rover. She saved my life.
Watney.
There's a mood of tension and anxiety
here, outside Johnson Space Center.
As you can see,
many people have gathered here,
To see whether or not, the mission to
retrieve Mark Watney will be a success.
Remember, they had some kind
of contact with him.
but it hasn't been very much.
We have to remind our viewers
that we're watching this as it unfolds
and we'll try to keep you up to date
as to what exactly is going on.
Let's listen in to NASA,
making contact with Mark Watney.
Let's listen in.
If something goes wrong,
What can Mission Control do?
Not a damn thing.
It's all happening
12 light minutes away,
which means it takes 24 minutes for them
to get the answer to any question they ask.
Our launch is just 12 minutes,
so...
They're on their own.
CNSA HEADQUARTERS
BEIJING
Today, people have gathered in front of
the TVs in Beijing and all over the world,
watching attentively at the rescue mission which
have caught the attention of the whole world.
This rescue made possible,
is due to China NSA's selfless....
TRAFALGAR SQUARE
LONDON
Mark has been
completely alone on Mars.
According to psychology expert,
they said...
Fuel pressure green.
Engine alignment perfect.
Communications 5 by 5.
We are ready for
preflight checklist, Commander.
Mission Control, this is Hermes Actual.
We will proceed on schedule.
We are T minus 2 min 10 sec
to launch, by the mark.
About 2 minutes, Watney.
How are you doing down there?
I'm good.
I'm anxious to
get up to you.
Thanks for coming back for me.
Yeah.
We're on it.
Remember, you'll be
pulling some serious g's.
So, it's okay to pass out.
You're in Martinez's hands now.
Well.
Tell that asshole no barrel rolls.
Copy that, MAV.
CAPCOM.
Go.
Remote Command.
Recovery.
Go.
Secondary recovery.
Pilot.
Go.
Copy.
We're a go.
Mission Control.
We are go for launch.
T minus 10,
- 9.
- Main engine start.
8.
7.
Mooring clamps released.
About 5 seconds, Watney.
Hang on.
See you in a few, Commander.
4.
3.
2.
1.
Velocity, 741 meters per second.
Altitude, 1350 meters.
It's too low.
I know.
It's fighting me.
Watney, do you read?
Booster separation complete.
Velocity, 850.
Altitude, 1843.
He's way below target altitude.
How-How far below?
Checking.
Watney, do you read?
He's probably passed out
He pulled 12 g's on the ascent.
Give him a few minutes.
Copy that.
Main shutdown in 3,
2,
1.
Shutdown.
Back to automatic guidance.
Shutdown confirmed.
Fuel reserve depleted.
Watney,
do you read?
There seems to be some sort
of problem with the transmission.
I have interval pings.
Intercept velocity will be
11 meters per second.
I can make that work.
Distance at intercept will be...
We'll be 68 km apart.
68 km?
Did she just say 68 km?
Come on, guys, keep it together.
Work the problem.
Johanssen, time to intercept?
39 minutes 12 seconds.
Martinez, what if we point
our thrusters in the same direction?
Well, it depends on how much
fuel you want to save
for the altitude adjustments
for the trip home.
How much do you need?
I can get by with about 20%
of what we have left.
If we use 75.5% of remaining
altitude adjustment fuel,
That'll bring the intercept range to zero.
Do this.
Hang on.
It brings the range to zero,
but the intercept velocity will be
42 meters per second.
And it's way too fast.
Then, we have 39 minutes
to figure out how to slow down.
Martinez, burn the jets.
Copy that.
Mav to Hermes.
Watney?
Affirmative.
What's your status?
My chest hurts.
I have broken my ribs.
How are you?
We're working on getting to you.
There was a complication during the launch.
Copy that.
Well, how bad is it?
Well, we corrected the intercept range,
but we got a problem with intercept velocity.
How big a problem?
42 meters per second.
Well,
shit.
Commander, I have an idea.
Go ahead, Mark.
Well, If I can find something
sharp in here
and poke a hole in the
glove of my EVA suit.
I could use the escaping air
as a thruster
and fly towards you.
It would be easy to control,
because it would be on my arm.
I can't see you having any control
if you did that.
You'd be eyeballing the intercept using
a thrust vector you can barely controls
Yes. Yes.
Those are all very good points.
But, consider this:
I'd get to fly around
like Iron Man.
Commander,
let's go Iron Man.
This is unexpected, LOS.
Communication lost.
Standby.
Maybe it's not the worst idea.
No, it is the worst idea.
It's the worst idea ever.
Not what he said.
Using atmosphere as thrust.
What happens if we blow the VAL?
What? You want to open
the vehicular airlock?
It'd give us a good kick.
Yeah, but it will also blow
the nose off the ship.
And all the air will leave,
and we need air to not die.
We'll seal the bridge
and the reactor room.
Everywhere else will go vacuo.
Vogel.
Go ahead, Commander.
I need you to come inside
and make a... bomb.
Uh.
Again, Commander?
You're a chemist.
Can you make a bomb with
what you have on board?
Probably.
But I feel obliged to mention that
setting off an explosive device
in a spacecraft is a
terrible terrible idea.
Hang on. You guys making
a bomb without me?
Copy that.
Can you do it?
Yeah.
Houston. Be advised we're going to
deliberately breach the VAL
- to produce some reverse thrust.
- What?
Beck, leave your suit on,
meet Johanssen in airlock 1.
We'll open the outer door.
I need you to place the charge
on the inner door.
Climb back to airlock 2
along the hull.
Copy.
I'm on my way.
I'm in, Commander.
Copy that.
Vogel, where are you?
- I'm in the kitchen.
- Okay.
Commander,
I can't let you
go through with this.
I am prepared to cut the suit.
Absolutely not.
Well, see.
The thing is, I'm selfish.
I want all the memorials
back home to be about me.
Just me.
I should have
left this guy on Mars.
Hey.
-Sugar?
- Yeah.
Can you hold this?
Liquid oxygen.
Add some stain remover
that contains ammonia.
This thing here,
is 5 times stronger than
a stick of dynamite.
How do we activate it?
You can connect this to
one of your lighting panels.
Careful.
Open airlock 1.
I'm on the way to Beck.
I just hope this is a
good idea, guys.
- It is.
- Open A1.
Hi.
You have it?
Make sure you're not in here
when this thing goes off.
Hey.
Be Careful out there.
In space.
Don't tell anyone I did that.
Bomb set.
Leaving airlock 1.
Guys, I'm running the numbers,
even with optimum VAL blow,
We're going to be off
on our angle.
What's the intercept distance?
Johanssen?
260 meters to approximate.
It's too far.
Commander?
Martinez, close the door.
Open D3.
Leave it open.
Open B2.
Johanssen,
Time to VAL blow after initiate?
15 seconds.
We sure know how
to cut it close.
Commander.
The distance is too far,
I'm going out.
- I can do this.
- It's not a debate.
I'm not risking another crew member.
Beck's returned.
Johanssen, initiate the bomb.
10 seconds.
Strap in.
5.
4.
3.
-Deceleration!
-2,
1.
Activating the panel 41.
Bridge seal holding.
- What's the damage?
- Worry about that later.
What's the relative velocity?
12 meters per second.
Copy.
Hook me up.
Done.
I've visual of the MAV.
What's the intercept range?
I'm checking.
312 meters.
Did you say 312?
Okay. I'll wave at
you guys as I go by.
Oh.
I can't get to you, Mark.
You're too far.
- I'm not going to make it
- I know.
Beck, unhook me.
I'm going after him.
Commander, I got this.
Mark, report.
On my way, Commander.
Damn it.
Johanssen, what's my
relative velocity to Mark?
5.2 meters per second.
Copy.
Adjusting course.
3.1 meters per second.
Distance to target 24 meters.
11 meters to target.
6 meters.
Hold on, Mark.
Come on.
I got him!
I got him.
Way to go, Iron Man.
Beck, pull us in.
It's good to see you.
You...
have... terrible taste
in music.
Houston, this is Hermes Actual.
We got him.
YEAH!
Watney is secure.
YES! YES!
YES!
Contact in outer space,
with Mark Watney.
After a very long time, they have done
what many people thought was impossible.
Mark Watney has been successfully rescued.
Mark Watney has been rescued.
This has been an incredible mission.
Get a hold of him.
Hey-Hey, handsome.
Beck, close the hatch.
Hey, guys!
Houston, 6 crews safely aboard.
This is a huge moment
for this nation, for the world
and, in deed,
for international space travel.
- Hey.
Oh god!
There's a little sloth going on
over there, man.
I know. I haven't had a shower
for a year and a half.
Don't make me laugh.
I have a broken rib.
Hey, there.
Good day, sir.
- It's an honor, sir.
- Sir.
Good morning, sir.
DAY 1
Welcome to the
Astronaut Candidate Program.
Now pay attention,
because this could save your life.
Trust me. I know what
I'm talking about.
Alright. Let me get a few things
out of the way, right off the bat.
Yes, I did in fact survive on a deserted
planet by farming in my own shit.
Yes, it's actually worse than it sound.
So, let's not talk about that ever again.
The other question
I get most frequently is.
When I was up there
stranded by myself,
Did I think I was going to die?
Yes, absolutely.
And that's when you need to know going in,
because it's going to happen to you.
This is space.
It does not cooperate.
At some point, everything's
going to go south on you.
Everything's going to go south
and you're going to say "This is it."
That is how I end.
Now you can either accept that,
or you can get to work.
That's all it is.
You just begin.
You do the math.
You solve one problem
and you solve the next one,
and then the next.
And If you solve enough problems,
you get to come home.
Alright.
Questions?
Once Mission Control complete
their preflight checks,
we'll begin launch procedures.
The Ares 5 team will
rendezvous with the Hermes
approximately 48 minutes after launch.
From there, they'll have 414 days
of space travel ahead of them.
Have the goals changed from the
previous mission to the Ares 5 program?
And what do you hope
to achieve this time around?
Well, no. The goals has always been
the same for the Ares Program.
This time, of course we hope to bring
all the astronauts back at the same time.
- Flight, Guidance check complete.
- Copy, Guidance.
This is Flight.
We are go for launch on schedule.
Final Aerial Service Check are complete.
As everything remains a go.
for the launch of the Ares 5.
20 seconds.
Proceeding with the count.
T minus 10.
9.
Main engine start.
7, 6, 5, 4,
3, 2, 1.
And liftoff.
As the crew of the Ares 5 begin the
next chapter of America's space exploration.
Pressure look good.
Woo!
Wow, good shot.
There it is. 5 years after the
rescue of astronaut Mark Watney,
the Ares 5 is on it's way to Mars.
Subtitle created by - Aorion -
www.moviesubtitles.org